<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/rss.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 01:33:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Update on Gifted 3: An Unschooling Experiment</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first two installments of this very slow-moving series, Delphine was &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html"&gt;assessed as gifted&lt;/a&gt; and we &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedtwo.html"&gt;decided to check out our local gifted program&lt;/a&gt;. I posted that second post over three years ago; as you might imagine, many things have happened since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:48:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Latest Update on the Gifted Saga</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedtwo.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since my &lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html"&gt;last post on this topic&lt;/a&gt; I've met
with Andrea, a friend of a friend who is an expert on special education and
works at the TDSB. She very kindly allowed me to pick her brain, and I learned
plenty. Apart from lots of advice and insight on how gifted education is
handled in the TDSB, she had two concrete suggestions: to seriously consider
the TDSB gifted program, and to ask Delphine’s teacher specifically how he is
differentiating for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Differentiated education is something they ask teachers to do these days,
where basically every child gets their own special curriculum. It’s how they
justify combining ages and abilities within one classroom: the teacher is
supposed to assess the ability of each child in their class and provide each
and every one of them with assignments and materials that suit their level. You
might infer that I am skeptical as to the practicality of this system.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had every intention of getting Delphine assessed for giftedness, because you
basically can’t ask for anything without having that rubber stamp. But from
talking to other parents I got the impression that the gifted program, which is
at a school a few neighbourhoods away, would not be suitable for Delphine. So
we had written off the possibility of the gifted program and hoped that the
rubber stamp could be put to use some other way. But Andrea urged me to be
open-minded and check out the program ourselves. And she’s absolutely right;
neither Delphine nor I know what the program is really like nor whether it will
suit her in ways that she can’t even articulate. So we’re going to, at least,
go and visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met with Delphine’s teacher in November as part of the regular
parent-teacher interviews, and I did ask him how he’s differentiating the
program for her. He said something like, “I’m not going to offer her anything
different until I’ve seen that she can do the assigned work to a better
standard.” He doesn’t like the quality of her work — it’s messy and she
doesn’t go the extra mile to produce really great work. She meets the
requirement of the assignments without adding &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5YClmS3umk"&gt;flair&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this decision on the part of the teacher is deeply unsatisfying to
me. An education that is suited to your ability is a not a carrot to be dangled
in front of you as a reward for jumping through arbitrary hoops of the
teacher's devising: tidy handwriting, sitting still, completing assignments to
a level beyond that asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it does make a certain, superficial sense; I've mentioned this to a few
people and they've said it seems fair. But it isn't really, when you think
about it. There's no real connection between being tidy, or putting a great
deal of effort into an arbitrary tast, and needing (or deserving) to be
challenged intellectually.  Both of those are useful skills to have (the first
probably more than the second) but neither of them have to do with being smart,
and it doesn't make sense to connect one to the other. Just because she's not
particularly strong in these areas is no reason to deprive her of stimulation
in other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And besides, an education suited to the student’s level is a legal entitlement
in Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(We haven't even considered that she might not be completing the assignments to
the teacher's standard because she's not really very interested in them —
because they're too easy or because they're on a topic that doesn't interest
her, or because she wants to save her limited energy for an endeavor that's of
more interest to her.  Of course the question of whether she can apply focus
and determination and effort to a project which &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; important to her is
another matter, and one which doesn't seem to be resolved within the
traditional school system.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the reasons we are interested in an IEP; because it's a document
which requires that teachers offer her an education that suits her ability
level, without having to adhere to the teacher's idea of what's suitable for a
gifted child, or what should be required of a child before they get the
education that they need. Of course this leads to the question of whether we
want to establish an adversarial relationship with our teachers before we've
even established any other kind of relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story continues but this post has been sitting on my hard drive for a
while. More to come...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedtwo.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 23:05:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold Ring: A Poem By Delphine (Age 9)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/writes/poemgoldring.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Gold ring, halfling,&lt;br&gt;
Man gone, but for song,&lt;br&gt;
Wizard fell, into hell,&lt;br&gt;
Mirror of elf, see the south,&lt;br&gt;
Forest bent, met an Ent,&lt;br&gt;
Isengard strong, soon to be gone.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Into the black land, they will stand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Gold ring, halfling.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/writes/poemgoldring.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:01:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventures In Giftedness: Chapter 1 of ???</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in November I got a call from one of the special education teachers at the
school — Delphine's teacher this year and her grade two teacher had both
flagged her to be assessed for the gifted program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no gifted program at the girls' school — the program for gifted
kids is hosted at another school, so attending would require a daily bus ride. 
The special ed teacher said that Delphine was eligible for the gifted
assessment, but that if we wouldn't consider sending her to the gifted program
we shouldn't have her assessed, since the assessment is "resource-intensive".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really like our neighbourhood school, Delphine loves her friends, and she
gets carsick, so I declined the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had heard from a friend who works for the school board that if your child is
assessed as gifted you can get an IEP (individual education plan), which seemed
to be the best solution. An IEP provides specific guidance to the classroom
teacher, so Delphine could stay at her school while still getting the extra
enrichment she needs to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been talking with Delphine's teacher about this all year, and a few weeks
ago she finally arranged a team meeting to discuss Delphine's case. The team
meeting was supposed to involve us, Delphine's teacher, the principal and
vice-principal, the special ed teacher, and a psychologist from the school
board. That seemed like a bit of overkill to me, and apparently everyone else
agreed because only the vice principal, a special ed teacher and Delphine's
classroom teacher ended up attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't sure what would come of this meeting; I wanted to get the lay of the
land, see what our options were, and talk about an IEP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEP idea was shot down immediately. Apparently gifted students used to be
eligible for IEPs, but no longer. That leaves the bus-in gifted program, or, as
the special ed teacher said, we can "cross our fingers" and "hope" that next
year Delphine gets a teacher who understands the needs of gifted children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know how parents of other kids with special needs would feel if their
team meeting included the words "cross our fingers" and "hope", but I'm not
particularly happy about it. It's as irresponsible to neglect gifted kids as it
is to neglect kids with other special needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what our next move is. I'm reading up on gifted children because
I'm woefully uneducated in this matter, so hopefully next time I meet with the
"team" I'll be able to advocate more intelligently for my girl. We might
consider the bus-in program, since Delphine's very best friend is thinking
about going to another school for Extended French, which releases one of her
ties to the neighbourhood school. (At least we can visit the
gifted program so Delphine has an idea of the possibilities.) We're
contemplating other specialised programs, like the TDSB Vocal Academy; that
would be valuable and enriching in some ways but still wouldn't directly
address Delphine's needs as a gifted learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't one of those satisfying blog posts with a useful conclusion. I have
no idea where we're going from here, I just know I'm not satisfied with the
path we're on. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 01:34:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We Invented a Game!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/spellinggame.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine, her friend Darina and I invented a word game. It goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The first player says a letter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next player says that letter and then another letter to start spelling
a word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first player says the first two letters then continues spelling
the word – maybe the same word as the second player, maybe not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The players continue to take turns spelling, adding a letter each time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You win if:&lt;br&gt;
- you finish spelling a word and the other player can't think of a way to make 
it longer.&lt;br&gt;
- you stump the other player - they can't think of a word which starts with the
letters so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we just did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy: A&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: A-W&lt;br&gt;
Amy: A-W-E&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: ... (she didn't know "awesome" has an "e")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine: J&lt;br&gt;
Amy: J-U&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: J-U-N&lt;br&gt;
Amy: J-U-N-I&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: ... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going for "junior" but Cordelia reminded me about "juniper".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Cordelia gave us "G" as a start letter, and Delphine lead with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G-E&lt;br&gt;
Amy: G-E-N&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: G-E-N-U&lt;br&gt;
Amy: G-E-N-U-I&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: G-E-N-U-I-N&lt;br&gt;
Amy: G-E-N-U-I-N-E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I won that round because I got to the end of the word and Delphine couldn't
make it longer. But then we decided (when we did "zamboni") that if you're both
obviously working on the same word you should both get a point. (We're not much
for points, anyway.) It works best if you're playing with someone with about
the same vocaulary as you; I kept stumping Delphine with ridiculous words but
Delphine and Darina were well-matched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I don't know if it's a brilliant game but we almost never come up with
good games so we're pretty pleased with ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/spellinggame.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:46:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to make a After School Snack</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/writes/snackrecipe.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A recipe by Delphine. [Spelling and capitalization hers. -AB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredeents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banana&lt;br&gt;
Small fruit [Like strawberries or blueberries. -AB]&lt;br&gt;
Ckrackers&lt;br&gt;
Jam&lt;br&gt;
Peanut butter&lt;br&gt;
cheese&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spread peanut butter on crackers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut Banana and place on crakers with peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread Jam on three Differet crakers [That is, not the crackers with the peanut butter. -AB]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut cheese. Hee Hee Hee!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h5&gt;How to place&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Put crakers Around edge of a plate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;place small fruit in middle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fill cracks with cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/writes/snackrecipe.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 21:49:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Delphine Turns Eight</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/eighthbirthdayparty.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;...on Tuesday May 10. But her party was on Saturday, a perfect day for a party.
Delphine invited four friends: Ursa, Darina, Amelia and Rosebella. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was sunny and warm, and almost all the guessts arrived on time.
We started
the fun as we usually do, decorating brown paper lunch bags for loot bags.
This is a pretty good way to keep everybody busy while all the guests arrive,
although it's surprising how quickly a child can coat a paper bag with
glitter and stickers. The girls spent a good eight to ten minutes on their bags
before disappearing upstairs to "visit" the cat. I don't like parties to go
upstairs because it creates far too much mess, so I called them down and sent
them outside to play while we waited for the one straggler to arrive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the final guest appeared, we rounded up the whole gang and 
walked up to a nearby parkette to terrorize unsuspecting dog walkers
with a series of silly races. We did a traditional speed race, then
a hopping race, a egg and spoon race, a three-legged race and a sack
race. It was a pretty nice combination: the speediest kid was totally
hamstrung by the sack race, the least athletic kid turned out to have 
nerves of steel and totally shellacked everyone in the egg and spoon
race.  Delphine won the sack race because most of the big kids collapsed
in exhaustion and the little kids just kept falling over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After everyone was worn out and sweaty we headed back to the house
— curiously, the children managed to muster enough energy to run
most of the way there — for sub sandwiches and cheesies and
apple juice. Everyone was happy with lunch. Even the children who don't
like sandwiches (seriously?! Who &lt;em&gt;doesn't like sandwiches&lt;/em&gt;?) were
convinced to disassemble their sandwiches and enjoyed all the ingredients
thereof. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine once again designed an awesome and original cake: lemon cake
sandwiching a thick layer of rainbow sherbet, with blue buttercream icing. I
decorated it with kosher jelly candy shaped like slices of citrus fruit. (On
sale after Passover.) The cake was a hit with everyone; some kids ate just the
cake, some kids ate just the sherbet — no-one ate just the icing, I guess
that stops at about five or six — and some kids ate the whole thing and
had seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Delphine opened her presents, slowly, paying great attention to each
gift, much to the irritation of those children whose gifts she hadn't 
opened yet. She got a Geronimo Stilton book which she was very gracious
about even though she has been openly scornful of Geronimo Stilton
lately. (It's come up because Cordelia likes Geronimo Stilton —
they read them at daycare.) From the same child she also got 
&lt;em&gt;Happy Birthday Bad Kitty&lt;/em&gt; by Nick Bruel, which is a fairly witty
comic/novel hybrid. From her school bestie she got the puzzle game Rush
Hour. From her friend down the street she got a big sketchpad, a box
of bright, gorgeous oil pastels and a book called &lt;em&gt;The Sisters 8&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best present was from Ursa, or rather her mother Tanya. Tanya
snuck all through the house and hid a series of clues leading Delphine
to her gift, a set of stilts. Delphine &lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; a treasure hunt, and she
was thrilled with the treasure, too. The girls spent a good part of the rest
of the party trying them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradually all the kids except Ursa left (Ursa's a semi-permanent addition to
our household and doesn't count as company). I was just about to collapse into
well-earned slumber (did I mention the day before the party I published a book?
Well, I did. More about that soon.) when my friends Kat and Joel arrived. Kat
had been away in Asia for weeks so I peeled myself off the couch to give her a
hug and make some tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Kat brought Delphine a beautiful red silk cheongsam, and for Cordelia a
set of glow-in-the-dark rubber bangles. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party finally came to an end when Ursa and Kat and Joel went home.
Delphine went to bed happy and exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/eighthbirthdayparty.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 02:04:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Santa</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/santa2010.html</link><dc:creator>Delphine Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Santa,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're real, this is my Christmas list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I would like a name necklace—a coloured one. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like a cat buddy. (That's a stuffie.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like some chapter books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like some long-sleeve shirts,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a butterfly net,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and binoculars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like a little Pokémon stuffy,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and a toy Pokéball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A craft set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br&gt;
Delphine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Typed by Amy.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/santa2010.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 21:24:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First Entry</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/myfirstentry.html</link><dc:creator>Delphine Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My name is Delphine.  There’s another Delphine in the school I go to.  I go
to a K-6 school in Toronto.  My friend at my school’s name is Darina.  She
really likes bugs.  She’s going to dress up as a moth for Halloween.  I’m
dressing up as an elf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, me and my dad cooked dinner.  We had sandwiches, soup, and mini
pizzas.  It was fun to make dinner with Dad.  I liked making the
sandwiches.  I made five sandwiches.  They were tomato, mayonnaise and
cheese sandwiches.  Dad made the soup, and it was very good.  The mini
pizzas were kind of hard to make, because they took a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Ursa has gone to Winnipeg.  We feed her cats.  Her cats’ names
are Hebi-Chan and Columbus.  Here’s a joke: What do you call a locomotive
with a cold?  An achoo-choo train!  One more: Where would you weigh a
whale?  At the whale-weigh station!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Monday.  I’m going to go to school.  I like art.  I do not like
math.  The end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>first</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/myfirstentry.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 14:43:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Delphine Is Nearly Seven</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/nearlyseven.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine loves to read. We've recently been reading time travel books:
we read &lt;em&gt;The Root Cellar&lt;/em&gt; by Janet Lunn, and now we're reading 
&lt;em&gt;A Handful of Time&lt;/em&gt; by Kit Pearson. She also loves mysteries
(like her mother, her aunt, her great-aunt, her grandmother, her
other grandmother...) and is working on a Trixie Belden novel by
herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine also loves to watch TV. She loves &lt;em&gt;WordGirl&lt;/em&gt; but she
loves &lt;em&gt;Kim Possible&lt;/em&gt; more, which I'm kind of bummed about. Blake
introduced her to &lt;em&gt;Kim Possible&lt;/em&gt; because she liked &lt;em&gt;WordGirl&lt;/em&gt;
and y'know, female superhero. But &lt;em&gt;Kim Possible&lt;/em&gt; is a teenage
character, and well into that "kids are cool and parents are lame"
stage, and I wish Delphine wasn't being exposed to that already.
Unfortunately the horse is out of the barn now; failing another
hard disk crash (hmmmm) we're going to be watching &lt;em&gt;Kim Possible&lt;/em&gt;
until Delphine goes onto another thing or I ban TV altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine is no great fan of hard work. At school she goes to great pains
to make sure she's not at the beginning of the line, so she doesn't have
to hold the door. She loves the idea of having lots of responsibilities,
but she hates the reality of dropping whatever fun activity she's
doing in order to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a few jobs lately: she cleans the cat litter every other time
(I alternate with her); she helps clear the table; she's in charge of
her own morning routine and I'm trying to get her to help Cordelia,
too; she is in charge of her own bedroom, including putting away
laundry (which in effect means her room is a mess and her laundry
stays on her desk). The doing of all these jobs is prefaced by a 
great deal of moaning and whining. I feel somehow responsible for that
because I hated housework and it took me years to understand that
if I wanted my house to be nice I had to do the work of making it so.
I also have trouble understanding that things that are worth doing
take effort and time, and aren't always fun. I would like Delphine to
learn that before she's, like, twenty-five. Maybe then she won't be
a big old quitter like I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine is in gymnastics, trampoline and swimming this term. I
didn't mean for her to be an overscheduled child, but I happened to
check the city swimming classes and there were classes available at
the right time and the right level, which never happens, so I had
to pounce. She likes the classes in this order: swimming first, 
then trampoline, then gymnastics. This is interesting because swimming
is, like, $90, trampoline is $35 and gymnastics is $225.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swimming is going very well: she does front crawl and jumps in and
puts her head under water, all of which she couldn't do at the
beginning of the session. With gymnastics she's hit a bit of a 
roadblock because she doesn't like to be upside down. More than
that, she absolutely refuses to be upside down. This rules out
such cornerstones of gymnastics as somersaults, cartwheels, and
anything interesting on the bars. So either she has to bust through
that or I don't think she'll be having any more $200 gymnastics classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think school is going well. It's hard to tell, on account of she's
always in a bad mood on the way home, so she regales me with complaints
about how boring it is and how she hates everyone. Later in the day,
when she's rested and fed, I hear about the interesting things she
did and the fun she had. I suppose both angles could be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She seems much older lately; she's moody and critical and opinionated
and complicated. And she's clever and insightful and interesting
and passionate. She's, I think, like me: she's going to have to
grow into her personality. It definitely isn't a little girl's
personality. She's a tiny grown-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/nearlyseven.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 04:10:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>