<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description>A weblog for latte.ca</description><atom:link href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 16:49:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to Go to the Gym Every Day (Kind Of)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I work out every day. Hah, no I don't. I do work out most days, though.  I didn't used to be a workout-every-day person. I got to this point through years of incremental changes and adjustments in my habits and attitudes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are impressed that I work out. They say, "I'm so impressed that you work out so often!" They say, "That's great, that you go to the gym every day!" It's one of the few things that I get randomly acclaimed for. (Of course, that says less about the magnitude of the accomplishment and more about what we value as a society.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But valued or not, exercise is profoundly important. If there is such a thing as a panacea, it's not aspirin or vitamin D or fish oil, it's exercise. It's good for your body, it's good for your brain, and it's good for your mood. Apart from the actual doing of it, there is no downside to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the trick, though, isn't it? The actual doing. The taking time out of your day, the sweating, the special clothes. It's a bit of a drag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to enjoy the benefits of exercise, you need to minimize the drag. This is how I manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 13:28:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My problems with the new MacBooks.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was listening to &lt;a href="http://atp.fm/episodes/193"&gt;episode 193&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href="http://atp.fm/"&gt;Accidental Tech Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and one of the hosts didn’t seem like he understood why I (and apparently many other people on Twitter&lt;sup id="fnref-0"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html#fn-0"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) were uninterested or annoyed or disappointed with the new MacBook Pros.  So, being a random white dude on the Internet, I hoped that I could leave a comment explaining the various reasons, in case he was interested…  🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>apple</category><category>macbook</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:39:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Update on Gifted 3: An Unschooling Experiment</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first two installments of this very slow-moving series, Delphine was &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html"&gt;assessed as gifted&lt;/a&gt; and we &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedtwo.html"&gt;decided to check out our local gifted program&lt;/a&gt;. I posted that second post over three years ago; as you might imagine, many things have happened since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:48:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Forty-One: An Appraisal</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Monday I turned 41 years old. It came as a bit of a surprise. All my life I've felt a particular age, usually not my actual age,  and it's always been younger, as if I got 
stuck. For example, I felt 34 for at least three years after I stopped being 34, and I think the one before that was 27. 
This is the first time I've gotten ahead of myself: I feel like I'm about 44, and I keep being surprised that I'm only 41. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a rocky year. My last birthday was marked by picking up my family from the airport in Saskatoon, and picking up my mother's ashes from the crematorium on the way out of town. Then we stopped for burgers at A&amp;amp;W. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This birthday was marked by sharing a traditional memorial feast for (and with) our ancestors with good friends who also lost a grandparent on July 31. We had burgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:16:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Looking Back: 2015</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to go out on a sturdy limb and say 2015 wasn't one of my best years. It wasn't an unqualified disaster, though. Let's start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year started off phone-free, because I dropped my phone down a drain in December 2013. I stubbornly tried to manage without buying a new iPhone, but I finally gave up and blew the $600 or whatever on an unlocked replacement. I'm much more careful with my phone outside, now, so I guess I grew as a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:28:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Letter to My Mother on what would have been her 81st Birthday</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Mum,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today would have been your birthday. It’s been three and a half months since you died, and I thought you might like an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that of all the places you’re likely to be (and I expect you’re probably not actually anywhere, although Shirley thinks you’re in the blue jays) the Internet is the least likely, so I’m not sure why I’m posting this online. Maybe, like everything else post-mortem, it’s for me, not for you --- on account of you’re dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope being dead is working out for you. Wouldn’t it be nice if there were really a heaven, and you could be with your dad and your sister again? Maybe even your handsome first husband, who you loved so much. (I didn’t find any pictures of him in your stuff --- but there were pictures of Dad’s first wife. You were way prettier.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 08:05:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hey!  Let’s Write a WebExtension!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/firefox/webextensiontutorial.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(This article is also posted on &lt;a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2015/09/lets_write_a_webextension/"&gt;Mozilla
Hacks&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have heard about Mozilla’s &lt;a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/WebExtensions" title="Mozilla’s WebExtensions Wiki Page"&gt;WebExtensions&lt;/a&gt;, our
implementation of a new browser extension API for writing
multiprocess-compatible add-ons.  Maybe you’ve been wondering what it was about,
and how you could use it. Well, I’m here to help!  I think &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/Add-ons/WebExtensions" title="MDN’s WebExtensions Documentation"&gt;MDN’s WebExtensions
Docs&lt;/a&gt; have a pretty great definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebExtensions are a new way to write Firefox extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology is developed for cross-browser compatibility: to a large extent
the API is compatible with the &lt;a href="https://developer.chrome.com/extensions" title="Chrome’s Extension API"&gt;extension API&lt;/a&gt; supported by Google
Chrome and Opera. Extensions written for these browsers will in most cases run
in Firefox with just a few changes. The API is also fully compatible with
&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Firefox/Multiprocess_Firefox" title="a.k.a. Electrolysis"&gt;multiprocess Firefox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I would add is that while Mozilla is implementing most of the API
that Chrome and Opera support, we’re not restricting ourselves to only that API.
Where it makes sense, we will be adding new functionality and talking with other
browser makers about implementing it as well.  Finally, since the WebExtension
API is still under development, it’s probably best if you use &lt;a href="https://nightly.mozilla.org/" title="Download Nightly Here"&gt;Firefox
Nightly&lt;/a&gt; for this tutorial, so that you get the most up-to-date,
standards-compliant behaviour.  But keep in mind, this is still experimental
technology — things might break!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Starting off&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s start with a reasonably simple add-on. We’ll add a button, and when
you click it, it will open up &lt;a href="http://chilloutandwatchsomecatgifs.com/" title="Cat Gifs!"&gt;one of my favourite sites&lt;/a&gt; in a new
tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/firefox/webextensiontutorial.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (9 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>addon</category><category>firefox</category><category>mozilla</category><category>webextension</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/firefox/webextensiontutorial.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 18:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A long time ago, on a computer far far away…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, I started contributing to Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>anniversary</category><category>employment</category><category>mozilla</category><category>thunderbird</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2014: Ups and Downs (more Downs than Usual)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can’t say 2014 was one of my best years ever. I tried to travel, and failed; the house ate all our money; my mom got sick. On the other hand, my mom got better (and we discovered how much fun it is when I visit her without the kids), and we got kittens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:30:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Pocket of Calm</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We don’t get a fog a lot in Toronto, and on a foggy night about a month ago the Christmas lights were particularly lovely -- dreamy and soft. I was on the way home from a meeting and thought the lights on house on a corner were so pretty, I wanted to take a picture to show the girls. I paused at the curb opposite the house, and took my phone out of my pocket. I still had my mittens on, but I needed my fingers to use the phone, so I wedged the phone in my left hand, wedged between my fingers and the fleshy base of my thumb. I used my fingertips and thumb to remove the mitten from my right hand, and as I did so the phone slipped, or my grip relaxed. For the longest second ever recorded, my phone fell toward the storm drain I had just realized I was standing above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>