<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Amy Brown)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/authors/amy-brown.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 20:08:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>I Gave Up Social Media</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/quittingsocialmedia.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In December 2015, I stopped reading Twitter. It was the school Christmas break, the girls were home and I wasn't working so I wasn't on my computer much, and I was too busy to read Twitter on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I just... didn't get back on again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/quittingsocialmedia.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/quittingsocialmedia.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:28:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Work Out Every Day (Kind Of)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I work out every day. Hah, no I don't. I do work out most days, though.  I didn't used to be a workout-every-day person. I got to this point through years of incremental changes and adjustments in my habits and attitudes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are impressed that I work out. They say, "I'm so impressed that you work out so often!" They say, "That's great, that you go to the gym every day!" It's one of the few things that I get randomly acclaimed for. (Of course, that says less about the magnitude of the accomplishment and more about what we value as a society.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But valued or not, exercise is profoundly important. If there is such a thing as a panacea, it's not aspirin or vitamin D or fish oil, it's exercise. It's good for your body, it's good for your brain, and it's good for your mood. Apart from the actual doing of it, there is no downside to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the trick, though, isn't it? The actual doing. The taking time out of your day, the sweating, the special clothes. It's a bit of a drag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to enjoy the benefits of exercise, you need to minimize the drag. This is how I manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/gym.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 13:28:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Update on Gifted 3: An Unschooling Experiment</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first two installments of this very slow-moving series, Delphine was &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/gifted.html"&gt;assessed as gifted&lt;/a&gt; and we &lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedtwo.html"&gt;decided to check out our local gifted program&lt;/a&gt;. I posted that second post over three years ago; as you might imagine, many things have happened since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/giftedthree.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:48:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Forty-One: An Appraisal</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Monday I turned 41 years old. It came as a bit of a surprise. All my life I've felt a particular age, usually not my actual age,  and it's always been younger, as if I got 
stuck. For example, I felt 34 for at least three years after I stopped being 34, and I think the one before that was 27. 
This is the first time I've gotten ahead of myself: I feel like I'm about 44, and I keep being surprised that I'm only 41. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a rocky year. My last birthday was marked by picking up my family from the airport in Saskatoon, and picking up my mother's ashes from the crematorium on the way out of town. Then we stopped for burgers at A&amp;amp;W. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This birthday was marked by sharing a traditional memorial feast for (and with) our ancestors with good friends who also lost a grandparent on July 31. We had burgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday41.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:16:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Looking Back: 2015</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to go out on a sturdy limb and say 2015 wasn't one of my best years. It wasn't an unqualified disaster, though. Let's start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year started off phone-free, because I dropped my phone down a drain in December 2013. I stubbornly tried to manage without buying a new iPhone, but I finally gave up and blew the $600 or whatever on an unlocked replacement. I'm much more careful with my phone outside, now, so I guess I grew as a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2015.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:28:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Letter to My Mother on what would have been her 81st Birthday</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Mum,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today would have been your birthday. It’s been three and a half months since you died, and I thought you might like an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that of all the places you’re likely to be (and I expect you’re probably not actually anywhere, although Shirley thinks you’re in the blue jays) the Internet is the least likely, so I’m not sure why I’m posting this online. Maybe, like everything else post-mortem, it’s for me, not for you --- on account of you’re dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope being dead is working out for you. Wouldn’t it be nice if there were really a heaven, and you could be with your dad and your sister again? Maybe even your handsome first husband, who you loved so much. (I didn’t find any pictures of him in your stuff --- but there were pictures of Dad’s first wife. You were way prettier.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/lettertomum.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 08:05:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2014: Ups and Downs (more Downs than Usual)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can’t say 2014 was one of my best years ever. I tried to travel, and failed; the house ate all our money; my mom got sick. On the other hand, my mom got better (and we discovered how much fun it is when I visit her without the kids), and we got kittens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2014.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:30:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Pocket of Calm</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We don’t get a fog a lot in Toronto, and on a foggy night about a month ago the Christmas lights were particularly lovely -- dreamy and soft. I was on the way home from a meeting and thought the lights on house on a corner were so pretty, I wanted to take a picture to show the girls. I paused at the curb opposite the house, and took my phone out of my pocket. I still had my mittens on, but I needed my fingers to use the phone, so I wedged the phone in my left hand, wedged between my fingers and the fleshy base of my thumb. I used my fingertips and thumb to remove the mitten from my right hand, and as I did so the phone slipped, or my grip relaxed. For the longest second ever recorded, my phone fell toward the storm drain I had just realized I was standing above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/stuff/lostphone.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year’s Resolutions</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/resolutions2014.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know. It’s a bit late. I meant to post this earlier, but then life… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(And I realized that the reason you post your New Year’s Resolutions as soon as
you can is that it’s embarrassing to post them after you’ve already broken
them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;1. Increase my machine time at the gym from 20 minutes to 30 minutes.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gym routine is almost literally the least I can do: twenty minutes on a
machine, usually the elliptical, and then fifteen minutes or more of
stretching. I’m really there for the stretching, because if I don’t do it
regularly sooner or later my back goes into spasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I figured another ten minutes can’t be too hard to come by, and a
bit more cardio three or four times a week can’t be a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;2. Double-veg&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another simple one: whenever I have fruit or vegetables, have twice as much.
I like fruit and vegetables, and it’s really only habit which stops me from
eating more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;3. Write more.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is your classic poorly-planned, doomed-to-fail resolution. There is no
plan here, no list of steps, no schedule, just a vague intention to “write
more”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing specific, not a novel or poems or a book on the history of quick
breads, but more little things: more book reviews on Goodreads, more blog
posts, more letters to family, more entries in my journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this one needs more work. I don’t want to give it up,
though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/resolutions2014.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:28:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2013 Year in Review</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2013.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this a little late, as it's already 2014. I suppose this
way I can be sure I'm not missing anything, as one never knows if 11:42 pm on
December 31 might be the highlight of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it wasn't. But at about that time someone did ask me what the highlight
of 2013 was, and I was stumped. I thought of our trip to Buffalo, but that was
in December; not even a month prior. So to write this post I'm going to have to
look at calendars, to-do lists, photos, old emails... Clearly my own brain
won't suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January I wrapped up work on &lt;em&gt;Shamans
Among Us&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href="http://josephpolimeni.com/"&gt;Joseph Polimeni&lt;/a&gt;. I edited and typeset the book, as well as
designing the cover and overseeing proofreading and website design.  It was
a fascinating book to work on; I learned a tremendous amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after &lt;em&gt;Shamans&lt;/em&gt; wrapped I set aside my editing work to join
Greg Wilson at &lt;a href="http://www.software-carpentry.org"&gt;Software
Carpentry&lt;/a&gt;. That's a big deal, really. It's my first regular, non-freelance
job since Delphine was born. 
It's so nice to be part of a team, to be useful and wanted for
something other than knowing where the clean socks are and what we're having
for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all did a lot of travelling this year, mostly by ourselves.
Delphine went to a few Guide camps and week-long sleepover camp in summer, and
Cordelia went to Brownie camp.  Blake went to Pittsburgh, London, Brussels, San
Francisco and Minneapolis, and I went to Portland OR, Boston, and London (but
not at the same time as Blake). The girls and I went to Saskatchewan in June,
and in December we all went to Buffalo, which &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; lame but might have been
the best trip of all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June my first-cousin-once-removed Emily came to visit with her boyfriend
Dan. I never met her before (I don't think? I feel like I should know this) so
that was pretty cool, because she's awesome and Dan is too.  The girls loved
them because Emily is from New Zealand and that's pretty much Middle Earth, and
because Dan played Lord of the Rings Risk with them. (Emily was also written up
in the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/05/22/emily-does-chicago-new-ze_n_3314832.html"&gt;Huffington
Post&lt;/a&gt;, which is more than pretty much anyone else I know can say.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty uneventful year in review, so I guess 2013 was a pretty
uneventful year. I'm okay with that! I hope 2014 is also uneventful, and with
some interesting trips. And maybe more cats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/yearInReview/2013.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 04:32:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>