<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (2007)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/2007.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Christmas Concert!</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/concert.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Delphine had her first Christmas Concert on Friday so I took the day off,
and Amy and I went to watch.  Here they are — Delphine is the one in the red
dress and silver tinsel crown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="530" height="370"&gt;
  &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/p/B2A4F28C552F877E"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/p/B2A4F28C552F877E" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="530" height="370"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Higher resolution versions &lt;a href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/static/delphine/christmas2007/"&gt;are
also available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>2007</category><category>christmas</category><category>concert</category><category>delphine</category><category>youtube</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/concert.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 14:58:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bike Week 2007.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/bikeweek2007.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, Bike Week 2007 has kicked off, and contrary to the first two
years I took part, this year I actually got a pancake!  Woo!  My
secret was sleeping in, so that I couldn't make it up to Yonge and
Lawrence by 7:30, and instead heading straight to Yonge and Bloor for
8:00.  On the downside, they didn't have any t-shirts larger than a
medium, so I guess I'll need to lose a little weight before wearing
the one I got.  On the upside, I was totally at the front of the pack,
and had a perfect view of Mayor Miller catching his front tire in
something and going head-first over his handlebars!  Very exciting,
and he seemed to be fine, although he did have to trade his fancy new
road bike in for an older mountain bike to complete the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else...  It was a nice ride in, the pancakes and croissant
were pretty much as I expected them to be.  The coffee was pretty
sweet, though.  I also picked up an apple and a bottle of water, but I
haven't had them yet, so I don't know how they are.  (The apple is a
really nice dark shade of red, though, so I'm looking forward to it.)
This year's t-shirt is much prettier than the previous two years, I
feel.  I got a couple of extra bike maps, and have distributed them
among the people in my office who cycle.  Uh, I guess that's about
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I need to get the new Bike Week logo in svg somehow...  I
would use the other bike logo I've got, but it's used in the post
right below this one, and that seems kind of repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>2007</category><category>biking</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/bikeweek2007.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 15:52:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>