<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (_2006)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/_2006.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Books In August and September</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/sep11.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I feel like I haven't updated for ages, but it has only been 
a couple of weeks.  But what did I read?  I was working on
&lt;em&gt;A Son of the Circus&lt;/em&gt; by John Irving for a while,
but I got stuck on it.  I think I am trying too hard to look for 
symbolism and subtext and stuff and not just blasting through
the story like I usually do.  Or else it's just not very
interesting, I am not sure which.  I'll get back to it
sometime.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After I gave up on that I read &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloodletting And
Miraculous Cures&lt;/em&gt; by Vincent Lam&lt;/strong&gt;, a collection
of connected stories about a group of medical students in Toronto.
I quite enjoyed these stories; Lam is an effective writer
with a nice turn of phrase, and I enjoyed getting a glimpse
into the lives of medical students and doctors.  (Lam is
a Toronto doctor as well as a writer.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I feel like I must have read some more but I guess blocking
on the Irving book just felt like reading a lot. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am trying to work on keeping notes when I read but mostly I
forget to do it.  I am not sure how to take notes when I
read fiction; what should I write down?  I think I will try
noting when I think something is an image or a metaphor, and 
then go back and try and figure out what it means later.  
With non-fiction I really need to make a note at the end
of each chapter on what the chapter was about.  I recently 
recommended a book to a friend; she ended up hating it but
it has been so long since I read it that I can barely remember
what I liked about it.  So I just had to nod; "yeah, book
sucks.  Right."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Must... get... smarter... 
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/sep11.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 14:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books in August</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/aug25.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Highly Sensitive Child: Helping our children thrive
when the world overwhelms them&lt;/em&gt; by Elaine Aron&lt;/strong&gt;.  After
Delphine decided she hated music class because the leader was too
loud, a friend recommended I read this book.  It is about the
15 to 20 percent of children who are apparently highly sensitive,
and how to parent them effectively without making them miserable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So is Delphine highly sensitive?  Kind of...  she's unusually sensitive
to noises, and to the emotional state of others.  Combine the two and 
logically you could determine that she is very sensitive to 
noisy expressions of emotion, as we saw at the music class and
as Baba's friend Ann found out.  (She had cause to gasp loudly in
surprise in Delphine's presence once; Delphine cried
a lot, and ever since then Delphine has periodically mentioned,
"Ann shouted, and then I cried.  Why did Ann shout?")
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It does make her easy to discipline by shouting at her, but I'm
not a big proponent of the "Discipline by Scaring the Shit out of
your Child" method, so I try to avoid it.  (Easier said than done,
since shouting is what I do when I'm angry, and getting angry is
what I do when I'm depressed, and depressed is what I get alarmingly
easily, it seems.  More about that later, though.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine's not sensitive to other things that the book discusses
though; she doesn't care if her food touches, and she isn't bothered
by tags on clothing or seams on socks or tactile annoyances of
that nature.  Thank goodness, because it seems like it would be
irritating to have to work around those kinds of sensitivities.
I am quite sympathetic to Delphine's sensitivities because I think
I share them (I will read the adult version of the book sometime
and see) and so I can quite easily understand her and figure out
what is going to upset her, especially now that I have read this
book and know what patterns and situations to watch for.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wouldn't read this book if you don't think you have a sensitive
child, because that would be borrowing trouble — if you don't
have to worry about this stuff I would strongly recommend you 
don't.  But if you think your child might be sensitive, or seems
to react disproportionately to certain situations, this book is
probably worth a look.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vices of My Blood&lt;/em&gt; by Maureen Jennings&lt;/strong&gt;
is a murder mystery set in Victorian Toronto, which is just
brilliant.  I love getting a picture of what Toronto was like in
the past, and Jennings does a great job painting that picture.
The characters are appealing and the mystery was good; what more
can you ask?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How To Read Literature Like A Professor: A Lively
and Entertaining Guide To Reading Between The Lines&lt;/em&gt; by
Thomas C. Foster&lt;/strong&gt;.  I am frankly a little pissed off that
I haven't read this book before.  I have been hinting around needing
a book like this for ages — when I read &lt;em&gt;How To Read and 
Why&lt;/em&gt; by Harold Bloom, I thought it really failed to discuss
the How part.  This book does.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book is a high-level discussion of the symbolism found in
literature: every trip is a quest; eating is always significant,
usually of communion or trust among the eaters;
weather is usually about something other than weather; and so on.
Foster also discusses sonnets, and briefly (one chapter each)
touches on Shakespeare, the Bible, Children's Literature, and mythology
(mainly Greek) as precursors or fodder for allusions or roots or 
— there must be a word for this but I can't think of it —
anyway, stuff that writers allude or refer to in order 
to enrich their text.  Foster discusses intentionality (did the
author really mean that to be a symbol/allusion/pattern?  Answer: yes.)
and irony, and then caps the whole thing off with a short story
to practice your newfound skills on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I love this book.  I might buy a copy.  It makes me wish I had read
it before I read &lt;em&gt;Cat's Eye&lt;/em&gt; because I am sure I missed a 
whole lot in that book by just reading for plot.  But I have the
rest of my life to try and read more deeply.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It made me think, though.  First, reading like a professor seems like
a lot of work; you have to keep track of symbols, you have to look
for patterns, you have to try and figure out where you have seen this
story or this character before, you are always looking for the next
layer or layers of meaning below the simple action and dialogue in
the story.  And is it worth it?  Do you really get that much more
out of the book?  I guess you do, or else no-one would bother.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And then, after you have been doing that for a few years and get
good at it and do it automatically, mustn't it be horribly 
disappointing when you pick up a normal book, a potboiler someone
left at the cottage or something, and you keep trying to find
depths of meaning that just aren't there?  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like when you are used
to watching &lt;em&gt;Buffy&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Firefly&lt;/em&gt;, and you watch
a regular show and you realize that the enticing hints being
dropped will never be picked up on, that the characters really
are as one-dimentional as they seem, that the really obvious
foreshadowing is actually just plain foreshadowing and not the clever 
misdirect you assumed it would be.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It must be like when you
drink Manischewitz kosher wine and at first it tastes like
sweet grape juice and you are waiting for the hit of spiciness
or mellowness or depth that you would get if it were a good
wine, like maybe ice wine... but instead it just turns sour
and flat.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And another thing.  The short story he gives as an example to
practice on.  It's a lovely story and being the simple-minded
lass I am, I enjoyed it for the characters and the plot and
the setting.  Then I re-read it and tried to find the symbolism
and allusions and the meaning, and I came up with a couple of
pretty good insights.  Then I read the professor's interpretation,
and as it turns out the end of the story is a big huge, 
kind-of-obvious reference to Persephone's journey into Hades which
I &lt;em&gt;entirely missed&lt;/em&gt;, not surprisingly because I know
nothing about Greek mythology (although Foster did helpfully
present the myth earlier in the book, so I can't entirely
plead ignorance.)  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But now I have this idea that reading
like a professor is like solving a riddle, and that in this
case I have failed. I know that isn't entirely true;
I'm sure that having been able to see that allusion contributes
to one's appreciation of the story and therefore it is valuable,
but I enjoyed the story for what I got out of it without making
that connection.  But I can't help but feel like I got it wrong,
somehow, and that I have to "solve" each piece of literature as
if it were a mathematical problem.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thus I conjure up an image of myself poring through heaps
of classics trying to figure out the hidden meaning, and triumphantly
snapping each one closed and setting it aside as I "decode" it.
"Figured out that one!  Next!"  Which I am sure is not the point.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/aug25.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2006 14:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books in July and August</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/aug11.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
It has been way too long since I did this, and I have read about a
thousand books.  I hope I don't miss any.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tipping Point: How Little Things Can Make a Big Difference&lt;/em&gt;
by Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/strong&gt; is a book I read before.  Since we own a copy,
and it seems to be a book that is still being referred to quite a lot
(notably in &lt;em&gt;Child's Play&lt;/em&gt; by Silken Laumann) I thought I would give
it another whirl.  It's still an interesting and thought-provoking book
about the reasons why people do things, and I am glad I gave it another
read.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It was alarming, though, to realize how little of it I recalled from the
last time I read it.  It made me realize again how little I actually absorb
of the books I read.  So I have started taking notes while I read, which is
incredibly geeky, but it's such a waste of time to read so much and not really
take any of it in.  Plus it's an excuse to buy myself some cool notebooks
and pens.  (The real reason I had children is so I could buy school supplies
every August.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porgy&lt;/em&gt; by DuBose Heyward&lt;/strong&gt;.  I got this out of the 
library because it was mentioned on the flap of the dustjacked of a wonderful
picture-book rendition of the lyrics to Gershwin's "Summertime", and I was
intrigued that &lt;em&gt;Porgy and Bess&lt;/em&gt; started off as a novel.  A few pages
into the book I was tempted to give up on it because of the annoying
phonetic handling of vernacular ("Yo' bes sabe yo' talk for dem damn dice.") which
makes the book nigh-unreadable until you get used to it, and that creepy 
early-1900s racism ("Crown was crouched for a second spring, with lips drawn 
from gleaming teeth. The light fell strong upon thrusting jaw, and threw the 
sloping brow into shadow.")  But for all that I kept going because I wanted
to know what happened next, and I was interested in the characters, and it
turned out to be an enjoyable and thought-provoking read, with a couple of
excellent turns of plot.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Anger Hurts Your Kids: A Parent's Guide&lt;/em&gt; by Patrick 
Fanning, Kim Paleg, Dana Landis, and Matthew McKay&lt;/strong&gt;.  I ordered 
this book from the library because I have some trouble controlling my temper,
and when I get angry I tend to do the kind of mean things to my children
which appall me when I see other people do them on television.  Nothing
terrible, and I don't think it is bad enough to do any irreparable harm, but
I still don't like to be an asshole parent, even just on occasion.  Especially
since every mean thing I do to Delphine, she turns around and does to
Cordelia.  Nothing quite like the mirror of a child's mimicry to show you
how you really are.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So this book had some useful advice, most of which I already knew.  It covered
a lot of information about what to expect from children at different ages 
— apparently a lot of people who get angry at their children do it because
they have unreasonable expectations.  That's not my problem, I have a pretty
good handle on normal childhood development.  There was also information about
how to talk to yourself about a situation; instead of saying to yourself,
"She's dawdling to get on my nerves, she knows we are running late and she
is deliberately sabotaging me", you should say "she is at a stage where she
doesn't like to be hurried, I need to give her lots of warning,..."  But I don't
see Delphine as vindictive or deliberately difficult, either.   So that's not 
my problem, either.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My problem is that I get irritated when I ask her to do something and she 
doesn't, and that she is at a stage where she is defiant towards me specifically
because I am her mother, because she is asserting her independence from me.  
So I tell
her to do something, and she automatically says "no" because that is the stage
she is in.  Which is all well and good, but sometimes I am just not up to
jollying her along and distracting her and offering reasonable choices, sometimes
I just damn well want her to do what I tell her to, and now.  So I shout at
her.  My problem is that I need to get more sleep and to not be in constant
physical pain, or fear of it, so that I have the patience to deal with her.
The better news is that she seems to be moving out of that defiant phase
into something a little more reasonable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clean and Green: The Complete Guide to Non-Toxic and Environmentally
Safe Housekeeping&lt;/em&gt; by Annie Berthold-Bond&lt;/strong&gt;.  I have been looking
for a useful book on hippie housecleaning ever since the smell of my usual
all-purpose cleaner started to make me feel ill.  I read a couple that were 
useless, and
then I got to this one, which is about perfect.  It goes over all the
ingredients you will need to make your own safe(ish) cleaning supplies, 
discussing what they are and how they work, and
then offers about a million recipes for each application.  I used to seek
the one perfect recipe for each product (all-purpose cleaner, tub scourer, etc)
but I think this way is better, since it allows you to tailor your cleaners
to your needs.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I liked this book so much that I went out and bought
a copy, and it now lives in my kitchen for easy reference at any time.
I like how making your own cleaning products brings an element of creativity
to the cleaning process.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The only concern I have with this book is that it treats Borax as if it were
as non-toxic as vinegar and baking soda, which it really isn't.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Thinking Fan's Guide to the World Cup&lt;/em&gt; by Matt Weiland and
Sean Wilsey&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This book is a collection of essays, one for each team in the World Cup 
finals, about football and the countries themselves and how they relate.
Some of the essays are more about football, some of them are more about the
country, some of them aren't really about either, but most of them are good
and interesting and added another dimension to the whole World Cup 
experience.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I had this on order from the library months ago, but it only came in just
before the end of the World Cup.  I managed to squeeze in a couple of essays 
— Italy and France, of course, and Brazil and England — before
the Final.  The Brazil essay, by John Lanchester, has a wonderful description
of why football is such a beautiful game, and so thrilling and hard
to watch:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
That's what you learn, as soon as you start to play and watch 
football: that football is difficult and beautiful, and that 
the two are related.  Players kick the ball to one another, 
pass into empty space which is suddenly filled by a player 
who wasn't there two seconds ago and who is running at full 
pelt and who without looking or breaking stride knocks the 
ball back to a third player who he surely can't have seen 
who then, also at full pelt and without breaking stride, 
crosses the ball at sixty miles an hour to land on the 
head of a fourth player who has run seventy meters to get 
there and who, again all in stride, jumps and heads the 
ball with, once you realize how hard this is, unbelieveable 
power and accuracy toward a corner of the goal just exactly 
where the goalkeeper, executing some complex physics entirely 
without conscious thought and through muscle-memory, has 
expected it to be, so that all this grace and speed and 
muscle and athleticism and attention to detail and power 
and precision passion comes to nothing, will never appear 
on a score-sheet or match report and will likely be forgotten 
a day later by everybody who saw it or took part in it.  This 
is the beauty and also the strange fragility, the 
evanescence of football.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access All Areas&lt;/em&gt; by Ninjalicious&lt;/strong&gt; is a book about
urban exploration, which is the fine art of going places you're
not supposed to go, mainly abandoned buildings or parts of buildings, 
construction sites, drainage systems, and the like.  This book is very
well-written; Ninjalicious (if that is his real name!) is funny, persuasive,
passionate, and strongly moral, which makes it all the more miserable that
he died (almost exactly a year ago) of some 
&lt;a href="http://www.uer.ca/forum_showthread.asp?fid=&amp;amp;threadid=22279&amp;amp;currpage=6&amp;amp;pp#post112"&gt;stupid 
liver disease&lt;/a&gt;.  So donate
your organs, people, you won't need them after you're dead.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Affluenza: The All-Consuming Epidemic&lt;/em&gt; by John De Graaf, David 
Wann, and Thomas H. Naylor&lt;/strong&gt; is a book which I'm sure I must have read
years ago in my anti-establishment, screw-The-Man days, but which I don't
remember at all.  It is all about how Americans decided sometime in the
fifties to put money and things before time, so now we (they) are all working
their asses off to earn plenty of money to buy things they don't have time
to enjoy, and how stupid is that?  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They covered some very interesting material about philosophical insights into
leisure time; the fact that this stuff is new to me suggests that I didn't
actually read this book before, because I am all about the leisure and I
am sure I would have remembered it if I had come across it.  Apparently
plenty of very intelligent people have thought long and hard about the need
to take time away from work and walk around or read or garden or mess about
in boats.  I thought I was just lazy, but no, I was walking in the 
intellectual footsteps of some of the greatest thinkers in history.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The authors tend to profligately blame
affluenza for all the troubles of our time, from obesity to pollution, which
is mostly fair but gets a little hysterical after eight chapters.
Anyway, thought-provoking, interesting, I give it two thumbs up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bringing Back The Dodo&lt;/em&gt; by Wayne Grady&lt;/strong&gt; 
This is
a collection of essays about nature and science, quite interesting although
some of Grady's pet theories are pretty useless; the man desperately needs
to read &lt;em&gt;Guns, Germs and Steel&lt;/em&gt;.  When he's not theorizing he's 
smart and readable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Devil May Care&lt;/em&gt; by Sheri McInnis&lt;/strong&gt; is a fluffy beach 
read which I
actually read on a beach; possibly a lifetime first for me.  (I didn't care
much for beaches before I had children.  Don't care much for them now, really.)
A pleasant read with an interesting meta-physical twist and a surprisingly
ambiguous conclusion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cat's Eye&lt;/em&gt; by Margaret Atwood&lt;/strong&gt; was more enjoyable than
I thought it would be.  (I just read it because I'm Canadian and I should and 
it's good for me, kind of like I eat Red River Cereal.  Chew, chew, chew,
chew.)  It was a bit hard
to read as the mother of girls — is this what they're in for?   But I
really (really, painfully) related to the protagonist's attitude to men and
women, and after I decided not to read it at the cottage but save it for the
city, I really got into it. (It's not really a cottage book; too depressing,
too much thought required.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thousand Barrels A Second: The Coming Oil Break Point and the 
Challenges Facing An Energy Dependent World&lt;/em&gt; by James Tertzakian&lt;/strong&gt;.
There's one of those self-explanatory sub-titles for you.  This is the more
sane version of that &lt;em&gt;The Long Emergency&lt;/em&gt; book by James Kunstler I
read last year; Tertzakian thinks we are coming to a break point in the oil
economy — there is a limited supply of oil, and soon it will become
too expensive to fuel our economy in the manner to which we have all become
accustomed.  Kunstler figures there is going to be some kind of post-industrial
revolution, millions will die and the rest of us will go back to living in the 
Shire; Tertzakian thinks the change will be slow enough to allow us to adapt,
with some difficulty, and that technology will ultimately save the day.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am leaning towards Tertzakian's view, if only because it is a little less
scary.  I think life is going to become drastically different in the next
few decades, and I think the twentieth century will be looked on as one of
unparalleled energy consumption, but I think we will be able to make the
transition to a less energy-intensive society without too much pain, at least
here in nice stable Canada.  I also think cheap, consumer 
airplane travel will sooner or later
be history, so do your international trips now before the government gets smart
and starts taxing aviation fuel like they should.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Blake and I are sitting pretty in this whole situation because we have,
almost accidentally, made a life for ourselves which is much less oil-intensive
than the average North American's.  We don't have a car, Blake bikes to work,
I can do all my errands without even using public transit.  I  buy
local produce as much as I can, and lean towards organics where practical.
We live in a multi-family dwelling, so we don't spend as much on heating as
we would in a house.  All in all, when the revolution (or evolution) comes,
it is going to be much less painful for us than it will for the Joe Suburb 
family who live miles away from the grocery store and need two cars just to
carry on their business.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Not To Be The Perfect Mother&lt;/em&gt; by Libby Purves&lt;/strong&gt;.
I had to buy this from Amazon because the Toronto Public Library doesn't have
a copy, except in Cantonese.  It arrived yesterday, just in the nick of time
because I needed a morale boost.  Libby Purves is a mother of two who tells
is like it is.  Like it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; is.  On breast feeding:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Let nobody kid you that breastfeeding is not going to be hell at first.  That 
mammary lobbyists are so keen to promote 'breast is best' (well, it is) that 
many of them have tended to slide rather dishonestly over the discomfort and
exhaustion of the first weeks.  Consequently, I suspect, a lot of willing mothers
give up, convinced that they are rare cases who 'can't do it'.  And indeed,
anyone with throbbing, bleeding nipples, dreadful heavy swollen red bosoms,
sharp needling letdown pains and a baby who still demands feeding every hour
and a half at six weeks old, is entitled to any tantrum she cares to throw.
I remember waking my husband up at 3 a.m. one painful morning with the words,
'Shall I tell you something?  I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; bloody breastfeeding, that's
what!'  There are many paintings of the Madonna and Child, but in none of these
has the feeding Madonna got her teeth clenched and her toes curled, as the
dreadful infant mouth takes its first agonizing drag.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
She makes mothering a baby sound like the cross between the appalling annoyance
and the jolly adventure that it really is (often in the same hour,) and it's such
a relief to know that I am not the only one who finds it so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Another great advantage of handing new babies around to everybody ('The milk
bill?  Ah, yes, I'll just find the money — take the baby, would you?')
is that new babies need to be talked to.  And you may not feel like doing it.
Next to the section on 'bonding' in the baby books, there is generally a 
paean of praise for mothers who talk all the time to their babies, maintain
'eye contact', allow infants to study their faces endlessly, and stick out 
their tongues to test reflexes.  This is fine, when you have the time and if 
you are fortunate enough to have developed an instant adoration of the baby.
If you are busy, or tired, or depressed at your life with this unsmiling
little creature which gives nothing back and wakes you up four crippling times
a night, the task of chatting to it may loom as unwelcome as all the other
hundred jobs you have to do in your twenty-four-hour day.  Despite underlying
love, I hated talking to my second child for nearly two months; she never
smiled until then, and I was exhausted, ill, and in constant jealous demand
from the older child.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just to read someone admit that other mothers sometimes feel this way is 
immensely reassuring and makes the whole business a lot easier to deal with.
Babies are hard, dude.
Okay, just one more quote (I love this woman; I would just retype this
whole book if it wouldn't be faster to lend it to you):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
When my son was four weeks old, he had only been to three places in his life:
hospital, home and the Olympia Horse Show.  We had friends with a box, and
permanent guest tickets, and the baby's godfather John Parker was driving
his coach-and-four in the final tableau and taking a team of Hungarian greys
through an avenue of fire.  So every single night I set off across London
with the basket, wearing a loose-fitting lurex top to combine the constant
feeding with a gesture towards glamour; and every night, in the box, Nicholas
lay in state while friendly drunken Scotsmen lurched up to press lucky pound
notes into his fist.  He smiled at everyone, fed contentedly, and dozed off
while Dorian Williams bawled his commentary on the show-jumping across the vast
arena below.  'Thank God,' the baby seemed to be saying, his beady eyes
swivelling busily around the scene, 'someone has at last understood my
requirements.'  All he had ever wanted, to keep him passably amused, was ten
thousand people, four military bands, two hundred horses and a boxful of
tipsy admirers.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/aug11.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2006 18:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books in June</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/jun21.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Your Face: The Culture of Beauty and You&lt;/em&gt; 
by Shari Graydon&lt;/strong&gt; is a beauty myth primer for teens,
and as such didn't really tell me anything I didn't already
know, although I think it did me good to be reminded of this
stuff.  I've been watching too much &lt;em&gt;What Not To Wear&lt;/em&gt;
and am starting to think that it's good and right to want to
be pretty all the time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Risk: A Practical Guide for Deciding What's Really 
Safe and What's Really Dangerous in the World Around You&lt;/em&gt; by 
David Ropeik and George Gray&lt;/strong&gt;.  This is really what
it claims to be: a practical guide.  It's a huge list of
everything you think is scary -- radiation, electromagnetic
waves, pesticide residue, tap water -- with discussions of
how scared you should actually be, and why, and what you
can do to protect yourself.  This would be a handy reference
book to keep around the house.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Intelligent Person's Guide to Judaism&lt;/em&gt; by 
Shmuel Boteach&lt;/strong&gt;.  (Actually now I'm not sure whether
I got the 1999 edition by "Shmuel" or the 2006 edition by
"Shmuley".  I wonder what else changed...)  I got this because
I am vaguely interested in Judaism and also because I love
Shmuley's show on TLC.  As it turns out, Judaism is pretty
cool but I can't get past the believing in God requirement.
I guess that's a pretty fundamental part of this whole
Abrahamic religion thing but I just can't do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some other thoughts: Shmuley doesn't like Ashkenazi
culture.  What's wrong with knishes?  What's wrong with
klezmer?  Nothing, that's what!  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The part refuting the Christian idea of suffering
being a means to better oneself threw me for a loop
because I realized I have bought that concept entirely.
When someone claims that their suffering made them
stronger I nod agreeably; it had never even occurred
to me that it might not be so.  I'm still not sure
that it is always false; I think that some suffering
is good for you.  Where Shmuley and I may differ is
in the scale of the suffering under consideration;
he is talking about being, say, imprisoned and used
for creepy medical experimentation where I am thinking
more of, say, not having a TV in your bedroom.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The whole section about women was a little creepy.  I'm
just not sure where I stand on the whole gender thing
these days. Having read &lt;em&gt;Gender Wars&lt;/em&gt; (and
having a working brain) I know
that women are not identical to men; being a feminist I
believe that women are legally, morally and in every
other way equal to men; being a mathematician I know
that the differences between men and women in most
meaningful scales are less significant than the 
variation within either group; being a parent I believe
that someone has to put the home and family first
and their career second.  Shmuley thinks that the
woman is most biologically suited to that role, but
I don't think that's so.  Shmuley also says women
are naturally more spiritual than men, gentler,
more compassionate, smell better -- a lot of nice
things which make me think maybe I am being 
patronized.  Maybe not, though, perhaps I am over-sensitive
and suspicious.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I will read some more Shmuley books and see
how they are.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Better House and Planet&lt;/em&gt; by Marjorie
Harris&lt;/strong&gt; is a book about how to keep your house 
in an environmentally sensitive manner.  It's actually
one of those "1000 Household Tips"-type books that 
were popular in the eighties.  I took it out because
I wanted some tips on cleaning without using nasty
cleaning products, but this book is more like a big
game of "Bullshit or not?!"  A sliced avocado won't brown
if you don't take the stone out: bullshit or not?  
Bullshit!  I can't remember any more, but this book
had a concentration of about one urban legend per
two pages.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Very disappointing, and I still don't know
how to clean without using nasty products.  Maybe
I will just use vinegar for everything.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The World's Best Street &amp;amp; Yard Games&lt;/em&gt; by Glen 
Vecchione&lt;/strong&gt; is a collection of all the cool games
you played (or didn't play, in my case) when you were a kid,
and lots more besides.  Games for when you are feeling rowdy
or when you are all dressed up and can't get dirty; games
for day and games for night; games for the sidewalk and
games for the park.  It's an excellent collection,
and it made me wish the girls would hurry up and grow up
so we could play.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cross Bones&lt;/em&gt; by Kathy Reichs&lt;/strong&gt;.  Another
good Kathy Reichs, although again her sentence fragments —
and paragraphs consisting entirely of a single sentence
fragment — got on my nerves.  And this time her
"my subconscious is trying to tell me something"
shtick that she does at the end of every book she writes
annoyed me as well.  (Then Jeffrey Deaver did it in his
book too — do all mystery writers do it and I just
never noticed before?  Surely not.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But what annoyed me most of all was how much they screwed 
up this character and the stories when they made the TV
series &lt;em&gt;Bones&lt;/em&gt;.  It's like they threw out everything
that was good about the books, threw in David Boreanaz and
half-baked the whole thing.  Is that show even still on?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naked&lt;/em&gt; by David Sedaris&lt;/strong&gt; is very 
funny and good, although his constant moaning about what
a sad loser he is is a bit of a demotivator when after all,
he is the one who wrote the book and there you are sitting
at home reading it.  If he's a sad loser, what does that
make you?  I don't really know how he went from being a
sad loser to having his book on my shelf, but there you go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Incidentally, if you like this you might like the 
&lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/mar31.html"&gt;David
Rakoff book I read a while ago&lt;/a&gt;; they are both gay New 
Yorkers named David who do weird things and write about them
amusingly.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When You Lunch With The Emperor&lt;/em&gt; by Ludwig Bemelmans&lt;/strong&gt;.
Anyone who has read to Delphine knows that Ludwig Bemelmans
is the &lt;em&gt;Madeline&lt;/em&gt; guy, but apparently he also
wrote books for grown-ups.  This is a collection of his
autobiographical essays; witty, cutting but not catty,
poignant, favourable adjective, favourable adjective.  
I will read more of his stuff eventually; you should too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twelfth Card&lt;/em&gt; by Jeffrey Deaver&lt;/strong&gt;.
This is a Lincoln Rhyme book; if you remember the movie
&lt;em&gt;The Bone Collector&lt;/em&gt;, it was an adaptation of an
earlier Lincoln Rhyme book starring Denzel Washington
as Lincoln Rhyme in an unusual spot of race-blind casting.
Unfortunately it caused me some mild confusion at the 
beginning of this book, because the Lincoln Rhyme in the
book is not only white but is required by the plot to be
somewhat ignorant of black culture.  Once I sorted out
the "he's actually white" thing I was fine.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book was heavy on information, with lots of clunky sentences
like "Mel Cooper lifted several samples off the tape and ran
them through the gas chromatograph/mass spectrometer, the 
workhorse instrument in all forensic labs.  It separates 
unknown trace into its component parts and then identifies them."
Smooth, but then I suppose you have to get that information
out somehow, and I would rather the author just blurt it 
out rather than giving it to a character as some crude
expository dialogue: "Mrs.
Jones, this is a gas chromatograph slash mass spectrometer.
Perhaps you already know that it is the workhorse..."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I supposed the "romance" between Sachs and Rhyme (or as
I think of them, Angelina and Denzel) is developed in
one of the earlier books, but in this book I just 
couldn't see the attraction; Rhyme seemed like a
patronizing ass, and Sachs seemed to be annoyed with
him much of the time.  As I would be.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, having said all that, still an enjoyable read
with a damn good mystery, some surprising twists and a 
satisfying result.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get Your Tongue Out Of My Mouth, I'm Kissing You Goodbye&lt;/em&gt; 
by Cynthia Heimel&lt;/strong&gt;.  Despite the tacky title and 
the even tackier cover, this was a collection of good, funny
essays by an author I hadn't encountered before.  I
will see if she has written anything more recent though,
because this book was really dated: she makes references to Miatas
and &lt;em&gt;Ghost&lt;/em&gt;, she claims New Yorkers don't eat sushi
and that you shouldn't wear high heels with jeans.  It
boggles the mind, really, but I suppose that's what
happens when you write a pop culture book.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/jun21.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books in May</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/may25.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How To Cut Your Own or Anybody Else's Hair&lt;/em&gt; by
    Bob Bent&lt;/strong&gt;.  This was indeed useful -- apparently the key to
    cutting your own hair is to cut a guide section in front
    and then match all the other hair up to that section, using
    lots of mirrors to see the back.  I'm pretty sure you 
    couldn't do a complicated style in this manner, but I expect
    it would work for a simple style if you could stand a
    few weeks of wearing the results of your own practice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    Sadly some jerk decided to cut out the section on how
    to cut straight kid's hair (the straight hair of a kid, not
    the hair of a straight kid -- we don't know about that
    yet), which is of course the one thing I really wanted 
    the book for.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Bullshit&lt;/em&gt; by Harry G. Frankfurt&lt;/strong&gt;.  Of the
three bullshit books I have recently read, this is by far
the most successful, with a very intriguing conclusion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Curse of the Narrows: The Halifax 
Explosion 1917&lt;/em&gt; by Laura MacDonald&lt;/strong&gt;.
I love a good disaster book, and this is a good disaster book.
I think I would have enjoyed it more if I had not tried
to read it on vacation, surrounded by a million distractions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;False Alarm: The Truth About the Epidemic of 
Fear&lt;/em&gt; by Marc Siegel&lt;/strong&gt; approaches the current
American state of constant panic from a more medical point
of view.  I don't know if it's just me, or if it's all of
Canada, but I don't experience the kind of constant fear 
that he talks about, and I don't really know anyone who
does.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Undercover Economist: Exposing Why the Rich 
are Rich, the Poor are Poor--and Why You Can Never Buy a 
Decent Used Car!&lt;/em&gt; by Tim Harford.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is
a pretty interesting book about how economists think about
stuff (much like Freakonomics, but slightly less
amusing).  Harford leans a little further to the right
than I am used to, which got my back up a bit, but 
his arguments are convincing, so in the end I'm sure
it did me good.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/may25.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>List of Books</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/apr26.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
...now with short reviews.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accomodating Brocolli in the Cemetary or Why Can't Anybody Spell?&lt;/em&gt;
    by Vivian Cook.  Fun, more list-y than I expected.  Good for reading on
    the crapper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores The Hidden Side of 
    Everything&lt;/em&gt; by Steven D. Levitt and Stephen J. Dubner.
    Thought-provoking, stats-based perspectives on just about everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;One Summer's Grace: A Family Voyage Around Britain&lt;/em&gt; by Libby Purves.
    I love Libby Purves.  I wish she lived next door to me and could come by
    for tea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Well-Ordered Home: Organizing Techniques for Inviting Serenity Into
    Your Life&lt;/em&gt; by Kathleen Kendall-Tacket.  Apparently I already have
    a well-ordered home, because I didn't find anything particularly new
    in this book.  That is as I expected, and 
    not to say that wouldn't be useful to you, if you do not find your 
    home to be well-ordered.  (I only took it out because it's by one
    of the authors of the nursing book I just read, and I was curious.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Devil's Feather&lt;/em&gt; by Minette Walters.  Minette Walters
    is always great, and this one was better than usual because she
    didn't spend so much time being bitter and miserable about the
    English.  This book ate an entire day of my life, which is pretty
    clever considering I am supposed to spend my days looking after 
    my children, not reading thrillers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;em&gt;The World is Flat: A Brief History of the Twenty-First Century&lt;/em&gt; by
    Thomas L. Friedman&lt;/strike&gt;. I didn't finish this before it came due at the
    library; what I did get through wasn't anything 
    new to me, since it was mostly about
    the Internet revolution, and I was there studying or working in software
    when Netscape came out and when the web got big and Y2K and so on.  Towards
    the end of the book I think he gets into the social implications of the
    world being flat (ie, geography no longer being a limiting factor in
    the economy) but I didn't get to that part.  I wasn't sorry -- this was
    one of those books I read because I felt I ought to, not because I
    was really interested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Willow and Twig&lt;/em&gt; by Jean Little.  Loved this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Don't Have To Be Thin To Win: The Official Chub Club Coach's
    Workout Program&lt;/em&gt; by Judy Molnar. Inspiring, if a little impractical --
    I am not about to train for a triathlon, or even a marathon; who has
    hours every day to work out?  (Having said that, I did put 
    Cordelia in the big stroller and go for an hour-long brisk
    walk today.  Like I said, inspiring.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goblin Market&lt;/em&gt; by Christina Rosetti.  Why have I never
    come across this before?  Creepy and good -- I would love to see
    &lt;a href="http://leontinemay.blogspot.com/"&gt;Leontine&lt;/a&gt; illustrate
    this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goodnight Nobody&lt;/em&gt; by Jennifer Weiner.  I wasn't sure about
    this at first because the protagonist doesn't really seem to like
    her children very much, but as it turns out she was just having one
    of those days, and also her husband was an asshole.  I can't imagine
    dealing with kids without a good, helpful, &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt; husband
    at my side.  I think I would rather be not married at all than
    married to someone who was never home and not helpful when he was.
    But I digress.  (You have to read that in a South African accent,
    because I always say it with one in my head.  I'm not sure why.)
    Very fun book; I am happy Jennifer Weiner has written two more books
    I haven't read yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/apr26.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>End of March</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/mar31.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Jeez, I just typed out the names of the books I read since my 
last post, and it's clear I read too damn much.  Honestly, I don't
know where I find the time, so don't ask me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(I remember when I was a kid I would say -- well, brag about, really --
how many books I read, and the mothers would look at each other and
roll their eyes and say "Well, I guess you have a lot of time!"  Hah!
Take this, snarky mothers!)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I have time to read them but not blog about them, so this
is going to be short.  Ish.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Akimbo and the Elephants&lt;/em&gt; by Alexander McCall Smith&lt;/strong&gt;
is also short, a little wee thing which I think took the author as long
to write as it took me to read.  It had a hurried feel, the characters
were thin, it was all a little obvious.  As if some elephant charity had
called the author and said "Write a nice little book about elephants!"
and he knocked it off in an afternoon.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Gave My Mom A Castle&lt;/em&gt; by Jean Little&lt;/strong&gt; is a 
wonderful collection of poems about families and gifts.  Little has
a knack for capturing children's thoughts and voices.  I remember 
enjoying her stuff when I was younger; perhaps now is a good time
to revisit it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Père Goriot&lt;/em&gt; by Honoré de Balzac&lt;/strong&gt;
is one of my New Year's Resolution books, because it has a character
named Delphine in it.  It might even be the character that my Aunt
Delphine is named after, although naming your kid after this
Delphine seems like asking for trouble.  Anyway, Balzac is one
pessimistic bastard and almost everyone in this book is scheming
and dishonest, and those that aren't mostly get screwed in the end.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breastfeeding Made Simple: Seven Natural Laws for
Nursing Mothers&lt;/em&gt; by Nancy Mohnbacher and Kathleen 
Kendall-Tackett&lt;/strong&gt; is an excellent book on nursing.  I got
it out so I could look it over and decide whether to recommend
it to a friend, but I ended up learning a bunch of stuff myself.  It
approaches nursing from the perspective of what's going on and
how you can make the natural process work for you, like growing
a seed, rather than giving a series of steps on How To Nurse, like
building an Ikea bookshelf.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think this book should be recommended reading for every expectant
or nursing mother.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It also has a &lt;a href="http://www.breastfeedingmadesimple.com/"&gt;fairly
tacky website&lt;/a&gt; which might have some useful stuff in it.  Check
out that title!  Now that's professional!  (Ah yes: 
"&amp;lt;meta name="GENERATOR" content="Microsoft FrontPage 4.0"&amp;gt;"
Always a good way to make a crappy impression.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Culture of Fear: Why Americans Are Afraid Of
The Wrong Things&lt;/em&gt; by Barry Glassner&lt;/strong&gt; is a nice,
reassuring book, in the sense that you don't really have to
be afraid of all the things the media would like you to be 
afraid of, but very unreassuring in that it give you 
the sense that people are very
stupid and can't seem to think for themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sir Charles: Wit and Wisdom of Charles Barkley&lt;/em&gt; 
by Charles Barkley and Rick Reilly&lt;/strong&gt;; Charles Barkley is
a pretty funny guy, in that he says stuff that everyone else is
scared to and he's usually right.  What I would give for this kind
of self-assurance.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don't Get Too Comfortable&lt;/em&gt; by David Rakoff&lt;/strong&gt;.
Apparently if you are a good enough writer you can get someone
to pay you to do crazy stuff like visit a cryogenics lab, or fly 
the Concorde, or interview some dude at the Log Cabin Republicans,
just so you can write about it.  That's what this book is, and 
it's pretty funny and well-written and occasionally thought-provoking.
(I liked the part about the faux-poverty.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Understand Your Child's Growing Mind&lt;/em&gt; by Christine 
Healy&lt;/strong&gt; is another interesting, science-based book about
a parenting topic.  It's pretty dense, covering lots of ground
with respect to mental development, but readable.
I would recommend this to
anyone concerned with their child's intellect.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book has lots of 
neatly sidebarred tips on how to help prepare your child's mind
for reading, mathematics, etc.  Unfortunately if you added up
all the sidebars you would end up with about eight hundred
bulleted items, and if you tried to follow them you would never 
have time to brush your own teeth, you would be so busy massaging 
your kid's brain.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dress Your Best&lt;/em&gt; by Clinton Kelly and Stacy London&lt;/strong&gt;
is basically &lt;em&gt;What Not To Wear&lt;/em&gt; in book form.  It's divided
up by body type with tips for each type, but there are general tips
for everyone scattered throughout the book, so you have to read the
whole thing to get maximum utility out of it.  I managed to glean a
full page of tips from it, but sadly there was no five thousand dollar
credit card in the book, nor anyone to babysit for a week while I 
shop.  I guess looking fabulous is going to have to wait.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/mar31.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March (of the) Books</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/mar10.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Three-Year-Old: Friend or Enemy&lt;/em&gt; by 
Louise Bates Ames and Frances Ilg&lt;/strong&gt; is useful, like
the two-year-old version.  They're pretty old (this one
is from the mid-eighties) so they're weirdly time-capsulish.
This one gives a suggested plan for your kid's third birthday,
and it's all "you should be able to manage this with the
help of two or three other mothers".  Presumably Father is
in the drawing room smoking his pipe?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Call Is Important To Us: The Truth about
Bullshit&lt;/em&gt; by Laura Penny&lt;/strong&gt;.  It must be very hard
to write about bullshit, because 
&lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/december24.html"&gt;Don
Watson&lt;/a&gt; tried to do it, and failed, and now there's this.  It
started off pretty well, but eventually turned into an 
all-purpose lefty jeremiad, with the usual anti-corporate,
anti-globalization, anti-consumer (Evian is naive spelled
backwards!) stuff.  
Not so much with the bullshit.  She also handily ignores
the great steaming heaps of the stuff generated by leftish
groups like anti-GM protesters; as if conservatives have
a monopoly on bullshit!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Me and Mr. Stenner&lt;/em&gt; by Evan Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;.  I
was glad to find out that Evan Hunter is the pseudonym of 
Ed McBain (actually, vice versa, but I'm  not sure what the
latin for "real name" is) and that he's written a million books.
This one is a book for young adults, and I really enjoyed it.
Hunter is a genius at capturing dialogue, and this is no different,
except it is set (and written) in 1976 so the dialogue is
kind of quaint.  I wish he had written more young adult books --
this is as good as Judy Blume.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perfect Parents: Baby-care Advice Past and Present&lt;/em&gt; 
by Christina Hardyment&lt;/strong&gt; is a book which chronicles the changes in
advice given to parents from the 1700s until now.  This is a lovely
book because it makes you realize that despite all the crazy-ass
things people have done with their children, society still seems
to chug along.  It was a surprise to me how much variation there
has been in childcare practices; I had a vague idea that in the
Olden Days everyone was really strict, and now everyone is really
permissive, and that's all there is to it, but really there has
been a lot more subtlety in parenting practices over the centuries.
Hardyment is a historian, so there is a lot of discussion about
how historical events like wars inform parenting.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I would recommend this book to anyone who is annoyed or bewildered
by the variety of advice out there.  I only wish it were newer,
so I could hear what Hardyment has to say about the judgemental
insanity that is Dr. Sears and attachment parenting.  (Which is, 
like the curate's egg, good in parts.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Blackboard Jungle&lt;/em&gt; by Evan Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;.  Evan Hunter --
Ed McBain -- wrote &lt;em&gt;The Blackboard Jungle&lt;/em&gt;!  Cool!  So I had
to take it out of the library and have a read.  It's really good.
Can I just stop saying that Hunter/McBain books are really good?
That would save some typing.  It's about a novice teacher dealing
with the, well, crap of working at an inner-city vocational school.
There is an especially good rant in the middle about vocational
schools and teaching and what does it all mean?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Obviously, I think this would be a really interesting book for
Kathryn to read since she is also a novice teacher dealing with
lots of crap, but I am reluctant to because if she didn't like it
I would be very sad.  So Kathryn, I recommend this book but if
you don't like it please don't say anything!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/mar10.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2006 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>February Books</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/february22.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Who Runs This Country, Anyway? A Guide to Canadian Government&lt;/em&gt;
    by Joanne Stanbridge&lt;/strong&gt; is a kids' book but since I knew
    nothing about the structure of our government I needed something
    with small words and lots of diagrams.  This served the purpose
    and now I know more stuff.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fiddlers&lt;/em&gt; by Ed McBain.&lt;/strong&gt;  Ed McBain is dead.  This makes me
sad.  Ed McBain wrote lots and lots of books, and I have only begun
to scratch the surface of them.  This makes me feel a little better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;In Her Shoes&lt;/em&gt; by Jennifer Weiner
&lt;/strong&gt; is pretty good fluff.  Yeah, they made that movie about it.
I'm sure the book is better -- it's pretty thick and I'm sure they
had to cut a lot of it out to make a movie.  I won't be renting the
movie to find out though.  (It wasn't THAT good.)  The characterization
is a little suspect, though; people change but the author isn't
really convincing as to why they change.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Collapse: How Societies Choose to Succeed or Fail&lt;/em&gt; 
    by Jared Diamond
    &lt;/strong&gt; took me forever to read, not because it's badly
    written but because it's long and Diamond is teeth-achingly
    thorough.  He examines at least eight societies in minute detail
    in order to make himself clear.  It's more like taking a course
    than reading a book.  By the end you're well and truly convinced,
    though.
    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    It was an interesting read in light of the other book I read about
    how it's all going to hell, &lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/november11.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Long Emergency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; Diamond isn't as
    pessimistic but it's clear that he's thinking something big is
    going to happen within our lifetimes or those of our children
    (although probably not his since I think he's in his seventies.
    The man is awesome!  So smart and sprightly and he has that dapper
    Abe Lincoln beard-but-no-moustache thing going on.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ingrid and the Wolf&lt;/em&gt; by André Alexis
&lt;/strong&gt; is a book for young adults which I would have loved when
I was younger.  I still quite like it now.  It was too short, though --
I would have wished it had gone on for much longer.  As an adult I
see that it is a good length for the story, though.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Who's Afraid of a Large Black Man&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Barkley
&lt;/strong&gt;.  Not much to say -- this didn't suck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Your Two-Year-Old: Terrible or Tender&lt;/em&gt; by Louise Bates Ames
&lt;/strong&gt;.  You know how everyone says "my kid didn't come with a user's
manual!"  Well, here it is.  This is just a discussion of what kids
are like, and it's one of a series covering different ages.  There
isn't much specific advice, but what there is is delightfully non-judgemental
and pragmatic.  I'm reading the one about three-year-olds, and their
recommendation for dealing with three-and-a-half-year-olds?  Put
them in daycare, because they're at an age where they want to evoke
an emotional reaction in their mother, so they act up.  With a daycare
provider, no emotional reaction, no acting up, everyone is much 
happier.  Failing that, they say, get a babysitter.  Awesome!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They also give some advice which set my mind at ease: they give you
a bunch of "techniques" (ie, tricks) for dealing with your toddler
and getting things done, like saying "Let's put away your toys" instead
of telling the kid to do it and then getting into a huge battle of wills
ending with the inevitable timeout.  If you say "Let's..." then you can
just go ahead and do it without your kid's help, and no-one has lost face.
I had been thinking that I can't do stuff like that because I Have To
Show Her Who Is Boss -- Ames says it's more important just to get through
the day without a thousand battles than to make every interaction about
who is boss.  So, very useful books.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/february22.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;em&gt;Blessing of a Skinned Knee: Using Jewish Teachings to Raise Self-Reliant Children&lt;/em&gt; by Wendy Mogel</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/jan29.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The sub-title says it all.  This is a book of value both to those
both looking for advice on child-rearing and looking for guidance
on how to live according to Jewish teachings.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The thing that strikes me, as a secular Christian, about Judaism
is that it provides so much guidance on how to live daily life.
Judaism takes the sacred out of the temple or the church and puts
it in the home, it takes the worshipping out of the hands of the
priests and shamans and puts it in the hands of the mothers and
fathers.  (I guess that's what comes of centuries of persecution --
you spread your faith around so it always survives.  Kind
of the distributed computing of religions.) 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Conveniently for the rest of us, Jewish teachings with respect
to the home and the raising of children are eminently sensible
and time-tested.  This book has advice about how to appreciate
your children, how to get them to appreciate (that is, respect)
you, how to teach them gratitude, get them to do chores, 
discipline them.  The author is a psychiatrist and a mother, too,
so she puts the teachings in a modern perspective.  She's also
pretty funny.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is a useful book and an easy read, and has lots of good
recommendations for other books -- in fact, I might get this
out of the library again just for the bibliography (some of the
books she references aren't applicable to my children just yet).
You will also learn lots of useful Hebrew words like &lt;em&gt;yetzer
hara&lt;/em&gt;.  (Maybe that's Yiddish?  She doesn't say.)
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2006</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2006/jan29.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>