<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (_2005)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/_2005.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2005 Books Overview</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/overview.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
(This is going to be kind of boring for anyone who isn't me.
Precisely the kind of thing one shouldn't post on one's
website.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last year I apparently read around forty-five books -- those
were the ones I remembered to log, anyway, and I think I remembered
just about all of them last year.  I read eight of them from January
until May, and the other thirty-nine from June on -- yay, first
trimester fatigue.  Twenty-two since Cordelia was born -- yay,
breastfeeding!  I read fifteen fiction and
thirty-one non-fiction, and two collections of short stories.
I'm really into non-fiction these days; I find non-fiction books
to be more rich with ideas than novels are, and I'm very
keen on thinking about the world lately.  There's a lot to think
about...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm glad I started reading again -- for a while, starting in
high school, I hardly read at all, but I have learned so much
in the last few years from reading books written by clever people.
I shudder to think how boring and ignorant I would be if I 
hadn't read the books that I have read.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In short: books, good.  News at eleven.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/overview.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 02:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>December Books</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/december24.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
My list of books read but not written about is getting unwieldy:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Death Sentences: How Cliches, Weasel Words and Management-Speak
are Strangling Public Language&lt;/em&gt; by Don Watson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think Don Watson is just a cranky guy.  I thought this would be a
good book, along the lines of &lt;em&gt;Eats, Shoot and Leaves&lt;/em&gt;, but
it was mostly just Watson complaining vaguely about the way public
figures speak these days.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Don't get me wrong; I hate management speak and blather and bafflegab.  
I wish marketers and
athletes and politicians would use plain language and say what they
mean.  (Yesterday on TV they were interviewing the super of a building
which had had flooding due to a water main break.  The interviewer 
said "What about the possessions of the people with basement apartments,
are they destroyed?"  The super said "Well, there was extensive
flooding in the basement area of the building and that would include
the apartment areas, so the residents will experience some property
damage."  What would be wrong with "I'm afraid so, yes"?  Don't want
to cut short your fifteen minutes by being concise?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The problem with Watson's book is that he doesn't give enough examples
of what he doesn't like, and suggestions for improvement.  He also
asserts that this kind of imprecise language leads to imprecise or
even deceitful behaviour, but he doesn't give any examples or concrete
basis of any kind for that assertion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I would give this book a miss.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;102 Minutes: The Untold Story of the Fight to Survive Inside the
Twin Towers&lt;/em&gt; by Jim Dwyer and Kevin Flynn&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I felt a little bad about reading this book.  I thought, "I guess it's 
been long enough since September 2001 that I can read about the 
destruction of the World Trade Center for my amusement".  But this
isn't all that sensational; it's a description of how various individuals
coped, helped, and escaped (some of them) the attack.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book
also details how the attack and the collapse happened, with a 
focus on the myriad things which were done incompetently, or not
done at all.  Do you know when they tested the fireproofing for the
steel beams in the Towers?  Summer of 2004.  Yeah.  Although it
probably all shook off from the impact of the planes, anyway.
Generally it was a collosal fuckup in many ways.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book is well- and engagingly-written and sheds light on how
decent people can be in a crisis.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Who should read this book:  I think Morgan might like it; normally
her thing is natural disasters but the man-made kind are interesting
too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making The Cat Laugh: One Woman's Journal of Single Life on the 
Margins&lt;/em&gt; by Lynne Truss&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is like a really well-written blog of a clever, funny, single
English woman.  There's not much else to say about it, but I liked
it very much.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Who should read this book: my brother Dave would probably like it; in
fact I tried to send him a copy but my local Indigo didn't have it.
Kathryn should &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; read this book; I think she will
really enjoy the humour, and the English-ness of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stiff: The Curious Life of Human Cadavers&lt;/em&gt; by Mary Roach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a book about all the things that happen to human bodies after
they die.  Roach covers the usual stuff: burial and cremation; but 
she also goes into some weirder options: being rotted to study how
to determine time of death, being smashed into in the name of crash-test
research, being dissolved in lye or composted, being used to teach
anatomy, being cut up so your organs can be used to extend the 
lives of others, being plastinated...  being dead is almost as interesting
as being alive.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Roach is a very funny writer, and I look forward to reading more of
her work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Who should read this book:  I think  Kate from The Usual Suspects might
like it; I think she liked &lt;em&gt;corpse&lt;/em&gt;, which is a similar sort
of thing.  Maybe Morgan, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why Gender Matters: What Parents and Teachers Need to Know About The
Emerging Science of Sex Differences&lt;/em&gt; by Leonard Sax&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a book which refutes the hippy-dippy idea that boys and girls
are naturally identical and any difference between their behaviour is
socially constructed, a fact which anyone with small children could
have told you is nonsense.  In fact, it's surprising it took this 
long to throw that idea out the window, since there's a pretty quick refutation:  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See, the hippy
idea is that the kid thinks something like this:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am a boy.&lt;br&gt;
Boys play with trucks and balls.&lt;br&gt;
Therefore I must play with trucks and balls.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The problem is that kids as young as eighteen months show gender
differences in play, and eighteen-month-olds don't know if they're
a boy or a girl.  Delphine is two-and-a-half and she still asserts
her boyhood sometimes.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sax starts out with a description of what we know about the differences
between boys and girls,  then he gets into how to apply that knowledge
when raising or teaching children.  The advice seems pretty sound,
although he strays pretty far from gender-based advice
later in the book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Who should read this book: Beth (thursday) because it might give her
some insight into her (very boyish) boys, Kathryn because she has
to deal with boys and girls every day at work, and Ellen because
I know she's interested in this stuff.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/december24.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 18:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/december.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potty Training Your Baby: A Practical Guide for Easier Toilet Training&lt;/em&gt; by 
Katie Van Pelt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I didn't actually get all the way through this book.  I threw it across
the room on the page where she suggests you don't have your child wash
their hands every time they go to the toilet because you don't want them
to think that peeing and pooing and private parts are dirty.  I have news 
for you, stupid
lady: peeing and pooing and private parts &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; dirty.  And if they 
aren't, your bathroom
probably is.  If you can't get straight in your head the difference
between literal, germy dirtiness and figurative, sexual dirtiness
then may I suggest you have a problem?  Also, I'm not shaking hands 
with you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She also suggests that there is an epidemic of adult constipation
caused by parents being negative about their kids' poo in childhood.
She provides no evidence, of course, but apparently if you so much
as wrinkle your nose at your child's fetid diapers, you will damage
them and their bowel health for life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And last but not least, she says you can't possibly begin potty training
until nine months, which directly contradicts the &lt;em&gt;Trickle Treat&lt;/em&gt;
book, which incidentally comes off as the height of reasonableness
compared to this one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Honestly, I'm almost sorry I read about potty training.  I got more
value out of a conversation I had with another mum at the library than
I have out of these books.  I have decided I am just going to switch
Delphine to big girl pants in the new year, and clean up messes until
she figures it out.  What the hell, I launder diapers anyway, and
it's not like I have expensive carpets.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Incidentally, both I and a friend with kids the same age have decided
we will put our babies on the potty as soon as possible this time around.
No more waiting for them to figure it out on their own.
In fact, her six-month-old has already peed in the potty more times than her two
and a half year old.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Men's Style: The Thinking Man's Guide to Style&lt;/em&gt; by Russell Smith&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Russell Smith is a men's fashion columnist for the Globe and Mail, and
he has written this book about men's fashion.  He covers the history 
of modern men's fashion and gives instructions on such things as how to
tie different tie knots, or what "black tie" means, as well as giving
his opinion on various style options.  As such this is a useful reference
book and I might even buy a copy.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's also very funny, particularly when he says "if you do such and such,
you will look like a..." whatever.  I already sent the book back to the
library so I can't give you any quotes, you'll just have to read it yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I can't agree with all his style opinions, though.  I think a man in a
sweater can be very attractive, and rust is a fine colour.  He's right about
three-piece suits, though: SEXY.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/december.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2005 20:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three More Books</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/november18.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anne of Avonlea&lt;/em&gt; by Lucy Maud Montgomery&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I wanted to know what happened next, so I read this book despite having
heard, on numerous occasions, that the other Anne books aren't as good
as &lt;em&gt;Anne of Green Gables&lt;/em&gt;.  Well, they were right.  This is
almost comical in it's not-as-goodness.  Lousy characterization,
telling-not-showing, awkward dialogue.  I don't know what came over
LMM, but it wasn't good.  I wonder if her other stuff is good, or
if &lt;em&gt;Anne of Green Gables&lt;/em&gt; was a freak occurrence.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering&lt;/em&gt; by Robert L. Glass&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Why am I reading about Software Engineering?  Because I have decided when
I grow up I would like to be a software manager.  Not a librarian or a
teacher or an opera singer or a photographer, or any of the other interesting
things which have come to mind in the last, oh, ten years.  No sir, I
am plunging headlong back into software, with ambition, this time.  
Ambition to become... &lt;em&gt;middle management&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
How do I know it will work out for me?  Because I am reading books like
this.  For fun!  And it was fun, and interesting and edifying (since
it is pretty much the first book I have read on the topic.)  Fortunately
Glass is not skimpy with his references, so I have a whole list of other
books to look up*.  Some of which I remember from the shelves of the
Computer Science Club.  Oh, how far I have come to be back where I
started.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
* Most of which the Toronto Public Library doesn't own!  Argh!  Do they
care nothing for software engineering?  I will have to see how well 
their "buy this book for me" system works.  Also, if anyone has any 
recommendations on the topic, I would be glad to hear them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trickle Treat&lt;/em&gt; by Laurie Boucke&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a book about how to potty train your baby from infancy.  The
theory is sound and the author gives a pretty good description of how
to implement it. However, as with so many other parenting books, it
is bogged down the author's sense of superiority and her disdain for
those who parent any other way than hers.  She even goes so far as 
to imply (based on a single anecdote from a friend) that diapering
your child and subsequently potty training in toddlerhood will 
emotionally damage your child for life.  I am surprised the 
attachment parenting folks haven't gotten ahold of this method, it's
right up their alley.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also the name makes me gag.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/november18.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 18:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Early November Reading</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/november11.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Long Emergency: Surviving the End of the Oil Age, Climate
Change , and Other Converging Catastrophes of the
Twenty-First Century&lt;/em&gt; by James Howard Kunstler&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've read Stephen King, I've read Dean Koontz, I've read Clive
Barker, Lovecraft, Poe.  I have read some scary shit, but this
is the scariest book I have ever read.  It's about all the bad
stuff which is coming down the pipe: the inevitable flu
pandemic, climate change, and the end of the fossil fuelled
economy.  Basically he says, if we get through all this without
blowing ourselves up or dying of thirst, we will be back in a
pre-industrial-type society (he doesn't think much of the 
alternative fuel options), along with a vastly curtailed 
population.  He thinks cities are doomed, he hates suburbs with
a vigor unrivalled since my office mate Rajko, and he thinks
towns and small cities are where it's at.  He also thinks you
should work on a post-industrial trade. He plans to publish
a newsletter.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The guy is deadly serious.  I have to find out if he's a kook
or not.  The book has no bibliography or index, which is certainly
a bad sign.  On the other hand it's clear to me that our society
relies on fossil fuels to an alarming and unneccessary extent.
Do we really need mangoes in February?  Holidays in Hawai'i?  Hot
showers every day?  Well, maybe that last one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The fact that the oil reserves and other fossil fuels are running
out sheds an interesting light on the issue of global warming.  
We're going to use all the available fossil fuels sooner or later.
Does it make any difference if we use them up in fifty years or 
two hundred?  The process of climate change is so slow and gradual
and complex that I don't think it would make a difference, although
as always I could be wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Bottom line, this was a thought-provoking and easy (and scary) read.  
Kunstler
is a cranky old man -- he hates the suburbs and he has some
rude things to say about Southerners -- and it's always fun to
hang out with the cranky, for a little while at least.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seize the Daylight: The Curious and Contentious Story
of Daylight Saving Time&lt;/em&gt; by David Prerau&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My problem with daylight saving time has always been that I don't 
understand why people don't just get up early, if they're so
keen to have more sunshine.  It drives me nuts when they say
"you get more daylight".  No you don't!  There is the same amount
of light, idiot!  And, despite the fact that people stare at
me uncomprehendingly when I say that now, apparently that was one
of the main objections to DST when it was first proposed.
Apparently the deal is that, sure the individual could just wake
up early, but it's really hard to get businesses to open earlier
and close earlier, so just fake 'em out by changing the clock.  
Having read the book I am now a proponent of DST, or double-DST,
or whatever it takes to fit clock-time to sun-time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It was a pretty good read, although I got a little tired of
daylight saving time by the end of it.  There is only so much
you can say about people arguing over the clock, I guess.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Everything Potty Training Book&lt;/em&gt; by Linda Sonna&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Everything it certainly is.  This book covers plenty of different
methods, including a hard-core one-weekend method which requires
you to be a drill sergeant, and a potty-train-your-infant method
which sounds intriguing.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every other book mocks the grandmotherly
claim that babies were trained before a year of age in the days
of yore, but apparently it was done.  Which, having read the 
&lt;em&gt;Long Emergency&lt;/em&gt; book, makes sense.  No-one is going to
put up with handwashing shitty diapers &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt;
for three years if there is any possible alternative.  It seems
the baby-training method is more like training a puppy, whereas
the toddler training methods require more conscious effort on
the part of the child.  She recommends a couple of books on
the infant training method, so I will read further.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The problem with this book is that it covers many different methods
and they get all muddled in your head.  With some methods, you
get the kid to help clean up their accidents, with some you
don't.  With some methods you reward success on the potty, with
some you don't.  It's hard to keep track of which is which,
let alone which one you are using.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joss Whedon: The Genius Behind Buffy&lt;/em&gt; by Candace
Havens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As you may guess from the title, this is pretty much a 162-page
fellation of Joss Whedon.  It's kind of cheap and tacky too,
with a large font, lots of pull quotes and pictures, and some
fairly bad writing.  I think people would take Whedon more
seriously if stuff about him and his work wasn't so Tiger Beat-ish.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/november11.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2005 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some More Books I have Read in October</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/october.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;French Women Don't Get Fat: The Secret of Eating for Pleasure&lt;/em&gt; 
by Mireille Guiliano&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This book lets the women of the world in on the French secret, how
French women manage to stay slim in a culture which loves to eat
butter and bread and meat and all those things which are forbidden
to erstwhile skinnies here in North America.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Clearly it was the subtitle which appealed to me; I love to eat.
I could stand to be slimmer, so I thought this book might give
me some good ideas, and indeed it did.  Mostly, though, it gave
me a heartening impression of sanity.  Guiliano loves to eat too;
great swaths of the book are dedicated to discussion of her favourite
foods and recipes, none of which contain sugar substitutes or 
applesauce instead of fat.  In fact, you would be hard pressed to
identify any of them as recipes from a diet book (with the
exception of the dubious leek soup recipe which she recommends
to kickstart your diet.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One of the nice things about this book is that the author doesn't
talk down from atop a lofty pinnacle of genetic and cultural 
superiority.  She lives in the US and when she first moved here
she gained a bunch of weight, which is why she had to consciously
rediscover all the French secrets herself.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So what are the secrets?  Nothing earth shattering; eat good food
with lots of flavours instead of crap -- if you eat crap, she says,
you have to eat more of it to satisfy yourself.  Prepare your
own food -- most packaged food uses salt and fat to conceal the
fact that it doesn't really taste good.  Have meals with multiple
courses -- a salad or soup, the main, and then a sensible dessert  --
again to satiate yourself with variety and ceremony rather than
quantity.  Don't eat standing up, and don't eat while you are 
doing something else; set the table nicely and sit down with your
family and enjoy the ritual of eating.  And of course, control your
portion sizes, probably the least fun and hardest of all her 
recommendations.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She also says don't go to the gym.  The gym, she says (and I
heartily agree) is a waste of time and money. Why pay to 
sweat on a machine when you can burn calories by walking to the store, 
biking to work, climbing stairs instead of taking the escalator,
kneading your own bread instead of getting a machine to
do it for you, and so on.  There are countless opportunities to
burn calories every day, if you watch out for them.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The bottom line is to put a lot more consideration into what you
eat, respect the food and you will derive more value out of less
of it.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anne of Green Gables&lt;/em&gt; by Lucy Maud Montgomery&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I got this out of the library because I needed to get the
Cordelia quote out of it, and because I hadn't read it for a while.
I don't remember Anne being so annoying, although when I was younger
I had less qualms about skipping over the annoying bits.  The 
big difference this reading was how I related to Marilla now that
I am a mother of girls.  (There's an essay by Margaret Atwood at the end of 
the book which says that the book is really about Marilla's journey
from being chilly and distant to being loving.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's funny, being a parent.  You suddenly find yourself on the other
side of a glass wall, seeing the world from a slightly new angle.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slack: Getting Past Burnout, Busywork and the Myth of Total
Efficiency&lt;/em&gt; by Tom DeMarco&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a book about how being super-efficient -- that is, cutting
out all the spare time and spare people -- screws over companies.
He argues that if every minute of a worker's day is spent doing
"work", tangible, billable, 
write-it-in-your-weekly-log-for-your-pointy-headed-boss work, you
don't have any time left to think about how you could be doing
things better, nor do you have enough flexibility to respond when
your co-workers need you.  It's a pretty compelling book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately it doesn't argue well for my version of "slack",
which is really just "screwing around".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toilet Training without Tears or Trauma&lt;/em&gt; by
Penny Warner and Paula Kelly, MD&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pee,
Poop and Potty Training&lt;/em&gt; by Alison Mackonochie&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of these two books, &lt;em&gt;Pee, Poop&lt;/em&gt; is the more useful, because
it discusses all the issues relating to your child's rear end --
general information on how the digestive system works, 
diapering, potential problems -- not only potty training.  It
also details  a few different approaches for potty training.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Toilet Training&lt;/em&gt; actually mocks books which provide
several different approaches, and purports to be less confusing
by describing only one method, presumably the definitive method.
Anyone who has been parenting long enough to be potty training
knows that there is no one method, for anything, which works for
all children.  So my bullshit detector went off on page 4; never
a good sign.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I also like that the other book is colour with lots of pretty
photographs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cutting Your Family's Hair&lt;/em&gt; by Gloria Handel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I got this out because I ballsed up Delphine's last haircut and
wondered what I should do differently next time.  I learned a
few handy techniques from this book, but unfortunately it seems
that executing a succesful haircut involves a subject who will
sit still for more than, oh, twenty-four seconds.  So Delphine
is going to have to wait for her first decent haircut.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The haircuts in this book, as shown in the photographs, actually
look kind of cheap and amateurish.  They look like the kind of
haircut you get at a ten dollar place out in the boonies.  You
would think they would try harder to get the pictures in the book
to look good.  The book is also badly edited.  For example, she 
starts off by describing how you cut guides -- basically a fringe
of hair around the head which you cut to the desired length and then
use as a template for the rest of the hair.  But the steps given 
for the first haircut in the book don't include cutting the guides --
are you just supposed to do them automatically?  Is this a cut which
doesn't require guides, and if so, how many other cuts don't require
guides?  I
don't know -- she doesn't say.  It's confusing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;100 Best Books For Children&lt;/em&gt; by Anita Silvey&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of the best things about having kids is getting to revisit
children's literature.  This book is a list of one hundred really
good kids' books, sorted by age and type.  The fun thing is that
Silvey gives you lots of insider information about the authors
and illustrators, and what the books go through before and
after publishing.  For example, did you know that Ezra Jack Keats's
&lt;em&gt;The Snowy Day&lt;/em&gt; was greeted with controversy?  Did you
know Ezra Jack Keats wasn't black?  I didn't know that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think I might buy a copy of this book for reference.  The
only issue I have with it is that it's American and so the books
she recommends tend to be American, but it balances nicely with
my favourite meta-book, Dorothy Butler's &lt;em&gt;Babies Need Books&lt;/em&gt; 
which is Australian and is satisfyingly Anglo-centric.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/october.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;em&gt;The Rebel Sell: Why The Culture Can't Be Jammed&lt;/em&gt; by Joseph Heath and Andrew Potter</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/heathpotterdiamond.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
This book should be subtitled "Everything You Thought You Knew Is Wrong",
especially if you are or have had any contact with "radicals" or 
"non-conformists" or "progressives", if you think everyone (else) is
walking around in a corporate-induced stupor of materialism, or
if you have ever read &lt;em&gt;Adbusters&lt;/em&gt; and felt smug and
superior to everyone who wasn't reading &lt;em&gt;Adbusters&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since that describes pretty much everyone I know, including myself,
I should say this book was a bit of an eye-opener.  I have to admit
that when I went around reading &lt;em&gt;Adbusters&lt;/em&gt; and all that stuff,
it didn't really ring true to me.  I went along with it because
it seemed like everyone else thought it was true, and I wasn't 
confident enough in my own good sense to go against the crowd.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This book, however, does ring true; it has the unmistakable stench
of common sense about it.  Heath and Potter argue that the counter-culture
revolutionary types are basically screwing themselves (and the rest of
us) because they refuse to accept incremental changes to 
our society (like, say, minimum wage laws); they think that our
society is so profoundly screwed up that nothing short of a 
complete overhaul, a revolution, will fix it.  Accepting incremental
changes would imply that society is generally okay and just
needs a few tweaks.  Heath and Potter call bullshit and explain
why in fairly convincing, and amusing, terms.  Also they smack down 
Naomi Klein and Kalle Lasn pretty good, which is fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guns, Germs and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies&lt;/em&gt; 
by Jared Diamond&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In this book Diamond attempts to explain why Eurasians have so
much cargo (you know, the stuff we're all brainwashed into wanting
by evil corporations) and why they (we) basically stomp over every
other culture we come into contact with.  It's because we have
the guns, the germs, and the steel.  But why?  Diamond knows.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This book ends up being a history of the world, and the most interesting
one I have ever read.  I am much smarter now that I have read 
this.  You should read it too (except you probably already have;
I am kind of behind the curve here.)
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/heathpotterdiamond.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2005 16:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two More Mysteries</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/mysteries.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Morality for Beautiful Girls&lt;/em&gt; by Alexander MacCall Smith
was nice but I am going to have to spread these books far apart, because
I seem to get tired of them quickly.  I'm not sure why.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Forty Words for Sorrow&lt;/em&gt; by Giles Blunt was really good.  It's
nice to read a book set in Canada, and this guy is a hell of a mystery
writer.  It was kind of gruesome, but I seem to be sensitive to that
these days, so it was possibly no more gruesome than most murder
mysteries.  I will read more by this guy.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/mysteries.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2005 13:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;em&gt;Black Like Me&lt;/em&gt; by John Howard Griffin</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/griffinblacklikeme.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I read this in high school as part of a Black culture and racism section.  At
the time I thought it was weird and stupid that we should study black
culture and racism in a school in a town that was forty percent Native
and very racist, but now I wonder if they were smart enough to know
that studying Native culture and racism would be close enough to home
that most kids would just shut down, defensively, and ignore any potential 
lessons, whereas studying Black culture would be distant enough for comfort
but still make the brighter kids think about issues closer to home.  I
may be giving the school administration too much credit here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I thought it was time for a re-read because the book made a big
impact on me when read it the first time, and indeed I am still very moved
by it.  I feel like I should have something more intelligent and
cynical to say about it now, but I don't.  I haven't really studied
or considered race relations much in the intervening fifteen years so
maybe that accounts for my lack of insight, or maybe it's just still a really
good book.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/griffinblacklikeme.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 13:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;em&gt;The Great Betrayal: Fraud in Science&lt;/em&gt; by Horace Freeland Judson</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/judsonbetrayal.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I think I should have enjoyed this more than I did, but perhaps I am
more interested in science itself than in when the processes that
make up modern science go wrong.  Still, the book is an examination
of the current state of science: peer review, refereeing, and so on,
and it was good to get an overview of that along with an analysis of
how it's not really working, and what is going to change it.  (Hint:
the Internet is going to change it.)  Also I can't be too annoyed with
a book which spends a couple of paragraphs talking about TeX and LaTeX.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Judson is an impeccable writer and not afraid to put together really
long (grammatically perfect) sentences, which means you can't read this
book in a half-assed manner, when you are watching TV or half-asleep.
I haven't read a book that required actual concentration and focusing
on the words on the page for a while, so it was a bit of a shock.   I
need to read harder books more often.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>_2005</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/books/_2005/judsonbetrayal.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 13:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>