<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (alternative)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/alternative.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Forecast - In The Shadow Of Two Gunmen</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/reviews/forecast.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;When I listened to the first song, they sounded like a band I listened
to back in university.  Something like a cross between Sloan and Live,
or The Lowest of the Low.  Live, maybe?  It wasn't any of those but
that was the sort of genre it reminds me of...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I'm trying to say there is that as far as I can tell,
it's classic Indie Rock, circa 1994, and god help me, I love it.  I'm
sure the muscial landscape has changed in the last 12, no, wait, 13
years, but it's good to see that there are still bands out there who
are playing the things I used to hear.  Damn, does that means that I'm
old, when I start liking songs like the ones I used to hear?  I'll
just chalk it up to nostalgia instead of age.  Shut up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should probably put in &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/music/The+Forecast"&gt;a link&lt;/a&gt; to more info,
shouldn't I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I know I totally missed the 1500 character target, but
man, this reviewing thing is hard.  All the harder when I'm only
listening to music at the office, where I'm really trying to
concentrate on my job, instead of on the music.  The first few times I
listened to the album, I was halfway through the following album
before I realized that I should have been listening.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>alternative</category><category>from_jessica</category><category>music</category><category>new_music</category><category>review</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/reviews/forecast.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 22:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>