<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about biking)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/biking.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Birthday Excitement</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my thirty-third birthday.  Thirty-three
isn't a very interesting number, but it's one of the 
ones you have to get through on the way to ooooold.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake's first present to me was to tell the girls
not to fight on my birthday.  If you know any 
two- and five-year-old sisters you will know how
long that lasted, but they did try.  For at least
an hour.  The next nice thing was that Blake let
me languish in bed while he went downstairs with
the girls and made tea and toast for me.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After
breakfast we opened presents: Delphine got me a
strand of blue silk flowers and beads on a wire,
to decorate things with.  Cordelia got me a wire
and bead ladybug (and then broke it, but not 
fatally), and Blake got me a Moleskine notebook
for Writing Things Down In.  I loved everything.
Blake thought I might not like the girls' things
because of their tchotchke-like nature, but it's
surprising how much I completely adore them just
because my girlies picked them out.  I put the
blue flower garland on the banister and I put the
ladybug... well, I put it up high.  Hopefully I 
can put it somewhere else soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite it being my birthday we still had a million
errands to run (partly because we're going to 
Sask next week) but I had a nice time.  I spent
far too much money on clothes for Delphine (but
they were on sale!  And so cute!) and far too much
money on a present for my cousin.  We met up with
our friends Tanya and Ursa and continued
the tradition started last year of 
decorating cupcakes (which is to say,
burying them in as many sprinkles as they will hold).
Tanya and I got some very rare talking-together-like-grownups
time while the little ones slept and the five-year-olds
played with Playmobil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Tanya and Ursa left, Blake came home with 
KFC (my annual treat) and more presents!  A
beautiful &lt;a href="http://www.basil.nl/assortiment_detail.asp?titel_var=2&amp;amp;lang=3&amp;amp;id=1864"&gt;Basil pannier&lt;/a&gt; and the Torchwood
season one DVD!  He tried to get the latter 
signed, but I'm glad he didn't manage it
 because I would have
died of jealousy if he had met John Barrowman 
without me.  Well, maybe not died, quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then more company; Kat came over and watched
our TV while the children were in bed, and we
went for a walk and had coffee.  We came home,
watched the first episode of Torchwood (I think
we may have converted Kat) and went to bed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All
in all, a super birthday, but my first full day
of being thirty-three was fabulous too.  Kat 
stayed over and we went to yoga together in the
morning.  Yoga was fun, as usual, but my hamstrings
are astonishingly tight and there were some postures
I couldn't even consider.  As usual, though, yoga
threw me some ego-boosting soft pitches:  I can balance!
I can ... well, mainly  I can balance! But there's a
lot of that in yoga!  The thing I like about yoga is 
that you might try a posture one minute that seems
completely impossible — you look at the person next to you
and wonder if perhaps there is some optical illusion
involved — but the very next posture is something you can
not only do, but do the "if you want a little more challenge"
variation!  Yoga wants you to feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the best thing of all was that today Delphine
learned how to ride a bike!  She went off with Blake
to practice riding in the school ground, and when they
got back she was riding all by herself.  I could
hardly believe my eyes!  This summer has been
great for her; she learned to climb a tree, she is
reading (not entire books but words and phrases), and
now riding a bike.  Wow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>birthday</category><category>delphine</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:06:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>5000 kilometers.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/fivethousand/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/bike/5000km_l.jpg"&gt;&lt;img align="right" src="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/bike/5000km_s.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Today, I finally reached 5000km of biking.  I forgot the camera, so I
don’t have a picture of the odometer at exactly 5000.0, but I took
this one when I got home, and it’s close enough.  I guess that’s all,
but I wanted to throw up a picture, as proof.  So here you go:
&lt;br clear="all"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>5000</category><category>biking</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/fivethousand/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 01:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Inconvienient Ride</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/inconvienientride/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew when I woke up this morning that it would be an annoying ride
in.  It was raining fairly hard, but there was a breakfast at &lt;a href="http://www.thebikejoint.com/"&gt;The
Bike Joint&lt;/a&gt;, and they usually have one
of the better breakfasts.  It’s the same coffee, muffins, bagels, and
fresh fruit as filling.  As it turns out, this year they got an
espresso machine, so instead of the normal coffee, I had a very nice
latte along with my chocolate chip muffin, but along the way I got
almost completely soaked and tore a hole in the crotch of my biking
jeans.  The hole wasn’t a complete surprise; the other side had gone a
couple of weeks ago, and I had patched it with some old t-shirt.  I
guess it’s time to re-do the patch, and extend it to cover both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I got there, had some coffee and a muffin, and as I got on my
bike after crossing the street when I noticed that my rear wheel
didn’t really feel right.  I looked behind me and found that it had
gone completely flat while I was standing around eating breakfast.  I
wheeled the bike back to &lt;a href="http://www.thebikejoint.com"&gt;the store&lt;/a&gt;,
Derrick replaced the tube, and I was on my way just as it started to
rain again.  And then my front light fell off and broke into three
pieces.  Fortunately, that was easy enough for me to snap back
together, and be on my way once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all that, I ended up being late for the 10:00am Status Meeting
at work, which was the cherry of annoyance on top of the annoying
ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day, so far, has gone much better.  I listening to a
not-particularly-interesting &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/5oag85"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; about
bicycle touring at &lt;a href="http://www.mec.ca/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt;, and while I was there
bought a bell.  My current bell works just fine, but it’s one of the
&lt;em&gt;ding&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ding&lt;/em&gt; ones, and no-one seems to recognize it as a bike bell,
so I got one that goes &lt;em&gt;ringggg&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ringgg&lt;/em&gt;, which is the canonical bike
bell noise, and I hope that’ll help.  Work is good too, if a little
busier than I might like.  And I finally got emacs working with
Markdown pretty much the way I want, so all in all, woot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Update: The ride home went mostly well, although there were spatters
of rain throughout the trip.  Around Sherbourne and Bloor, my rear
tire started to slow wayyyy down, and then stop.  When I flipped the
bike over, I noticed that it was jammed right up against the frame, so
I loosened it, straightened it, re-tightened it, and kept on going.
Still, that’s never happened to me before, and was pretty strange.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>breakfast</category><category>flat</category><category>rain</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/inconvienientride/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:32:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On the road again…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ontheroadagain/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, I finally got the garage door open, after it had been
frozen in a block of ice for most of the winter, and got my bike out.
So this morning, I biked to work for the first time in, uh, I don’t
even know how long.  It was a pretty sweet ride, all in all.  There
were any number of reasons not to do it; my biking jeans are dirty,
it’s too cold, I couldn’t down-shift, but as always there was one
reason that trumped them all.  I wanted to ride again.  And so I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I forgot about during my hiatus were how good that
first cup of coffee tastes after you’ve been riding in -5° weather,
what a rush it is to pass cars as they’re sitting, idling in
stop-and-go traffic, and how invigorated I feel when I finally get to
the office, and sit down.  Oh, also how sore my butt is.  Damn, that’s
a small hard seat.  I can’t wait to get used to it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s about it.  I made it in safely, and I’m sure I’ll be
doing it again, and again, and pocketing the $22.50/week that would
have gone to the TTC, to spend on random upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>cold</category><category>first_ride</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ontheroadagain/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 14:31:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Hands of Karma</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/thehandsofkarma/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/Karma.jpg"&gt;&lt;img align="right" src="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/small/Karma.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As I was riding to work
today, just after crossing the railroad bridge, heading on to
Summerhill, I noticed a man poking at his bicycle.  I stopped, and
asked if he needed a hand, and sure enough, he did.  He seemed to have
gotten his chain wedged around his &lt;a href="http://sheldonbrown.com/gloss_bo-z.html#bottom"&gt;Bottom
bracket&lt;/a&gt;, in such a way that the arms of the &lt;a href="http://sheldonbrown.com/gloss_sp-ss.html#spider"&gt;Spider&lt;/a&gt;
were attempting to push the top and bottom pieces of the chain
&lt;i&gt;through&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;a href="http://www.sheldonbrown.com/gloss_ch.html#chainstay"&gt;chainstay&lt;/a&gt;.  That obviously wasn’t working, so I grabbed my
multitool, and attempted to use the largest &lt;a href="http://www.sheldonbrown.com/gloss_aa-l.html#allen"&gt;Allen key&lt;/a&gt;
to try to lever it out.  When that too failed, I pulled out the one
tool in my collection I’ve never used: The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chain_tool"&gt;Chain Tool&lt;/a&gt;.  After
a few tries, I eventually got the chain apart, after which it was an
not-so-easy matter of threading it out through the gap between the
spider and the chainstay, re-threading it onto the &lt;a href="http://www.sheldonbrown.com/gloss_ch.html#chainring"&gt;chainring&lt;/a&gt;,
and re-connecting it.  As a final gesture of goodwill/parting gift, I
gave him my last 2007 &lt;a href="http://www.toronto.ca/cycling/map/index.htm"&gt;Bike Map&lt;/a&gt;.
(Yeah, I know the link is to the 2006 page.  They really have to
update that sometime...)  After all that, I got to the office 15
minutes late.  (Well, 15 minutes later.  I didn’t have a meeting or
anything, and our core hours don’t start until 10:00.)  But I’ve got
to say, that was 15 minutes well spent, since it made the rest of my
ride in seem extra-pleasant.&lt;br clear="both"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>nice</category><category>tools</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/thehandsofkarma/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 17:14:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When will I learn?</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ouch3/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I fell again, in a rather spectacular fashion.  I was
crossing St. Clair on Mt. Pleasant, and had just passed a
right-turning bus (on the left!  I’m not dumb enough to try to pass a
right-turning bus on the right!), and was signaling that I was going
to go back to the right-hand side of the lane (and therefore only had
one hand on the handles) when &lt;b&gt;*BUMP*&lt;/b&gt;, I hit a large ridge in
the road, which turned the tire sideways, and I went straight over the
handlebars, skidding to a stop near the curb.  My bike flew overtop of
me, crashing into a hedge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I got up, I noticed that the crash had apparently turned both my
front light and my bike computer around, which was quite a shock until
I realized that it was actually the whole handlebars which had gotten
turned around.  I spun it back and then just sort of stood there for a
while, catching my breath and calming down a little.  A lady driving
by asked me if I was okay, and if I needed a ride somewhere, but I
told her I was fine, which wasn’t entirely the truth.  My knees are
pretty much fine, a little scrape, perhaps.  My elbow is completely
ripped up, and even though I cleaned it thoroughly with soap and water
and a lot of scrubbing, it still looks pretty ugly, and is probably
going to scab up something awful.  Worse than that, my shoulder is
really sore again, in the same way that it was after &lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/Ouch2.html"&gt;my last fall&lt;/a&gt;, which can’t
be good.  I really need to get that looked at sometime.  The
&lt;i&gt;worst&lt;/i&gt; thing, however, is that I ripped the elbow of my &lt;a href="http://www.mec.ca/Products/product_detail.jsp?PRODUCT%3C%3Eprd_id=845524442618331&amp;amp;FOLDER%3C%3Efolder_id=2534374302692363&amp;amp;bmUID=1185298111978"&gt;cycling shirt&lt;/a&gt;.  Yeah, I can darn it, but darn it, I liked that
shirt!  But with every negative, there comes a positive.  The power
button on my Palm TX started working again.  Weird.  Maybe the next
time I fall, the sound will come back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in summary, signaling on a bicycle is bad!  No, not really.
Maybe the lesson is more that bumps in the road aren’t the greatest,
especially when you don’t have your hands on the handlebars.  Other
than that, I don’t really think I have any takeaways from this one.
That intersection of St. Clair and Mt. Pleasant is treacherous,
perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>ouch</category><category>pain</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ouch3/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 17:41:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bike Week 2007.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/bikeweek2007/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, Bike Week 2007 has kicked off, and contrary to the first two
years I took part, this year I actually got a pancake!  Woo!  My
secret was sleeping in, so that I couldn't make it up to Yonge and
Lawrence by 7:30, and instead heading straight to Yonge and Bloor for
8:00.  On the downside, they didn't have any t-shirts larger than a
medium, so I guess I'll need to lose a little weight before wearing
the one I got.  On the upside, I was totally at the front of the pack,
and had a perfect view of Mayor Miller catching his front tire in
something and going head-first over his handlebars!  Very exciting,
and he seemed to be fine, although he did have to trade his fancy new
road bike in for an older mountain bike to complete the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else...  It was a nice ride in, the pancakes and croissant
were pretty much as I expected them to be.  The coffee was pretty
sweet, though.  I also picked up an apple and a bottle of water, but I
haven't had them yet, so I don't know how they are.  (The apple is a
really nice dark shade of red, though, so I'm looking forward to it.)
This year's t-shirt is much prettier than the previous two years, I
feel.  I got a couple of extra bike maps, and have distributed them
among the people in my office who cycle.  Uh, I guess that's about
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I need to get the new Bike Week logo in svg somehow...  I
would use the other bike logo I've got, but it's used in the post
right below this one, and that seems kind of repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>2007</category><category>biking</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/bikeweek2007/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 15:52:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thoughts from a cyclist in the rain.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/thoughts/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div style="width:6.53em; height:3.79em; float:right"&gt;
  &lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 653 379"&gt;
    &lt;defs&gt;
      &lt;lineargradient id="g1" x1="10%" y1="15%" x2="85%" y2="85%"&gt;
        &lt;stop stop-color="blue" offset="0%"&gt;&lt;/stop&gt;
        &lt;stop stop-color="green" offset="100%"&gt;&lt;/stop&gt;
      &lt;/lineargradient&gt;
    &lt;/defs&gt;
    &lt;path fill="url(#g1)" d="M182.766,143.177l35.788-98.732l-11.341-19.344l22.681-24.682h48.695l0.667,14.009h-42.691l-8.672,9.339
	l10.006,18.01l-12.582,44.596h174.757l2.67-8.156c-14.046-1.828-38.271-10.48-44.058-15.507c-5.785-5.027-0.719-9.647,5.871-9.862
	c34.492-1.467,85.734-4.356,95.47-4.398c9.733-0.043,10.729,4.852,4.215,11.98c-6.518,7.127-12.211,13.543-36.898,17.369
	l-6.671,18.011l41.354,51.229c19.489-11.831,43.063-17.987,65.97-17.987c68.72,0,124.767,56.047,124.767,124.767
	c0,68.719-56.047,124.766-124.767,124.766c-56.534,0-106.245-38.989-120.856-92.874l-37.997,6.828
	c-1.626,4.479-5.419,7.914-9.947,10.603l6.778,32.146h8.672l0.666,8.672l-27.35,1.334v-9.339h6.672l-8.264-32.126
	c-12.291-2.013-18.732-12.535-15.072-22.979l-124.131-140.39l-5.559,15.062c30.128,23.732,48.16,60.285,48.16,98.3
	c0,68.719-56.047,124.766-124.766,124.766c-68.719,0-124.766-56.052-124.766-124.771c0-68.718,56.047-124.765,124.766-124.765
	C144.985,129.05,165.455,133.923,182.766,143.177z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;path fill="#FFFFFF" d="M427.353,260.018l85.419-13.942l-53.834-69.928C431.033,200.477,427.563,229.684,427.353,260.018z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;path fill="#FFFFFF" d="M403.856,265.133c-0.14-3.031-0.625-7.904-0.625-11.316c0-34.604,11.192-68.229,41.574-96.178
	l-31.642-37.883l-48.973,149.4L403.856,265.133z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;path fill="#FFFFFF" d="M215.885,116.44l2.716-8.314l174.429-0.229l-46.401,140.667l-2-14.676h5.336l-0.667-9.339H325.95
	l0.666,8.673h6.004l1.334,16.01C333.954,249.232,216.553,117.108,215.885,116.44z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;path fill="#FFFFFF" d="M138.632,251.566c23.425-18.604,41.658-36.34,54.806-71.825c20.753,18.825,32.592,46.056,32.592,74.073
	c0,55.645-45.383,101.026-101.026,101.026S23.977,309.459,23.977,253.814c0-55.644,45.383-101.025,101.026-101.025
	c17.759,0,35.912,5.13,50.55,13.771c-9.908,31.311-19.547,47.458-50.033,71.999c-7.4,0.313-13.028,6.254-13.028,13.342
	c0,7.349,5.993,13.342,13.341,13.342C133.181,265.241,138.632,259.248,138.632,251.566z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;path fill="#FFFFFF" d="M430.933,281.48c11.428,42.58,52.075,73.362,97.063,73.362c55.645,0,101.028-45.384,101.028-101.028
	c0-55.644-45.385-101.026-101.028-101.026c-17.759,0-38.308,4.19-53.298,12.967l54.834,72.804
	c6.707,0.104,12.545,6.099,12.545,13.342c0,7.349-5.994,13.342-13.342,13.342c-2.033,0-4.169-0.521-5.974-1.37L430.933,281.48z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
  &lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a certain point, you don't really get any wetter.&lt;br&gt;
Even though it's really cold, and I'm totally soaking, it's not a bad ride.&lt;br&gt;
Wow, it takes a long time to stop.  (I already knew this, and I'm going way slower than I normally would, but that doesn't make it any less true.)&lt;br&gt;
I could probably do with a new pair of biking gloves.&lt;br&gt;
The headband I stole from Amy is working wonderfully, though.&lt;br&gt;
I hereby transfer all the karma I got from giving my tires to &lt;a href="http://www.bikepirates.com/"&gt;Bike Pirates&lt;/a&gt; to the nice person in the car (a Beemer, even!) who let me turn left into the cemetary front of them.&lt;br&gt;
Although, thinking about it, I might not have that much karma left, since I'm biking on the sidewalk.  (Up Mount Pleasant beside the Cemetary.  In this weather, there's no way I would feel safe on the road, and there aren't any cross roads or pedestrians, so I'm probably way safer than I would normally be on the sidewalk.)  &lt;a href="http://www.michaelwalker.ca/"&gt;Mr. Walker&lt;/a&gt;, a bike lane down Mount Pleasant would be most appreciated.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>rain</category><category>svg</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/thoughts/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:53:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Bike Week Group Commute</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/groupcommutepost2006/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that was kind of fun, but the TTC strike, instead of being
the huge boon that I had hoped it would be, turned out to result in
millions of cars backing their way up Yonge Street, almost all the way
to Lawrence.  Since we were all in a group, we couldn't (or didn't
want to) filter past them on the right, so instead of half an hour, it
ended up taking us 45 minutes to get from Lawrence to Bloor, by which
point all the other commuters had left.  By the time we got to the
pancake breakfast, the line was far too long for me, and so I just
went straight to work.  (I should probably mention that this happened
to me last time, and so I had already packed a container of Cheerios
and powdered milk which I ate when I got to the office.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An idea for next time might be to head down one of the side
streets, maybe even one with a bike lane?  That way it would both be a
faster ride, and would show people how they might get down to work on
their bikes when they didn't have police blocking traffic for them.
(I wouldn't commute down Yonge street every day, so it's not really a
great introduction to bike commuting in the city.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from those minor problems, it was good to meet &lt;a href="http://bikerefugee.blogspot.com/"&gt;Darren&lt;/a&gt;, who had twice as
many people show up for his unofficial commute as I did, (two,
counting himself, as opposed to one, counting myself, ;) and I got
interviewed for a video of some sort.  I'm afraid I didn't come off
that well.  I seemed to be repeating myself, and stammering a lot, but
I hope whomever it was got some useful footage out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e6pYBW0gB9A&amp;amp;search=bicycle%20mountain"&gt;ouch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/groupcommutepost2006/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Unofficial Pre-Group Commute North</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/groupcommute2006/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bikerefugee.blogspot.com/"&gt;Darren&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="http://bikerefugee.blogspot.com/2006/05/unofficial-group-commute-north-updated.html"&gt;a spectacular idea&lt;/a&gt; for people who don't work downtown, but still
want to be part of the Bike Week Group Commute.  So in a similar vein,
I'ld love to be part of a Pre-Group Commute from Yonge and Davisville
up to Yonge and Lawrence.  I plan on leaving at about 7:00 to make it
an easy ride to Yonge and Lawrence by 7:30.  The route will be over to
Duplex, and then up to Roehampton (just North of Eglinton), and then
up Yonge to Lawrence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll be wearing an orange jacket and a golden helmet, and the back
of my bike will have a black pannier. Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; If this &lt;a href="http://bwinton.latte.ca/camera/weblog/on-143_metric_e.html"&gt;weather&lt;/a&gt;
holds up, I'll skip the orange jacket and just go with a black "&lt;a href="http://www.goldenpalacemobile.com/"&gt;GoldenPalace.com&lt;/a&gt;"
t-shirt instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/groupcommute2006/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>