<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about birthday)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/birthday.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Birthday Excitement</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my thirty-third birthday.  Thirty-three
isn't a very interesting number, but it's one of the 
ones you have to get through on the way to ooooold.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake's first present to me was to tell the girls
not to fight on my birthday.  If you know any 
two- and five-year-old sisters you will know how
long that lasted, but they did try.  For at least
an hour.  The next nice thing was that Blake let
me languish in bed while he went downstairs with
the girls and made tea and toast for me.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After
breakfast we opened presents: Delphine got me a
strand of blue silk flowers and beads on a wire,
to decorate things with.  Cordelia got me a wire
and bead ladybug (and then broke it, but not 
fatally), and Blake got me a Moleskine notebook
for Writing Things Down In.  I loved everything.
Blake thought I might not like the girls' things
because of their tchotchke-like nature, but it's
surprising how much I completely adore them just
because my girlies picked them out.  I put the
blue flower garland on the banister and I put the
ladybug... well, I put it up high.  Hopefully I 
can put it somewhere else soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite it being my birthday we still had a million
errands to run (partly because we're going to 
Sask next week) but I had a nice time.  I spent
far too much money on clothes for Delphine (but
they were on sale!  And so cute!) and far too much
money on a present for my cousin.  We met up with
our friends Tanya and Ursa and continued
the tradition started last year of 
decorating cupcakes (which is to say,
burying them in as many sprinkles as they will hold).
Tanya and I got some very rare talking-together-like-grownups
time while the little ones slept and the five-year-olds
played with Playmobil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Tanya and Ursa left, Blake came home with 
KFC (my annual treat) and more presents!  A
beautiful &lt;a href="http://www.basil.nl/assortiment_detail.asp?titel_var=2&amp;amp;lang=3&amp;amp;id=1864"&gt;Basil pannier&lt;/a&gt; and the Torchwood
season one DVD!  He tried to get the latter 
signed, but I'm glad he didn't manage it
 because I would have
died of jealousy if he had met John Barrowman 
without me.  Well, maybe not died, quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then more company; Kat came over and watched
our TV while the children were in bed, and we
went for a walk and had coffee.  We came home,
watched the first episode of Torchwood (I think
we may have converted Kat) and went to bed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All
in all, a super birthday, but my first full day
of being thirty-three was fabulous too.  Kat 
stayed over and we went to yoga together in the
morning.  Yoga was fun, as usual, but my hamstrings
are astonishingly tight and there were some postures
I couldn't even consider.  As usual, though, yoga
threw me some ego-boosting soft pitches:  I can balance!
I can ... well, mainly  I can balance! But there's a
lot of that in yoga!  The thing I like about yoga is 
that you might try a posture one minute that seems
completely impossible — you look at the person next to you
and wonder if perhaps there is some optical illusion
involved — but the very next posture is something you can
not only do, but do the "if you want a little more challenge"
variation!  Yoga wants you to feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the best thing of all was that today Delphine
learned how to ride a bike!  She went off with Blake
to practice riding in the school ground, and when they
got back she was riding all by herself.  I could
hardly believe my eyes!  This summer has been
great for her; she learned to climb a tree, she is
reading (not entire books but words and phrases), and
now riding a bike.  Wow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>birthday</category><category>delphine</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:06:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordelia Is Two!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia turned two on Thursday, which was kind of sucky for
her because it was her fourth day of nursery school and so she's
still suffering from lots of separation anxiety.  I felt like
a monster leaving her crying and miserable in the arms of
Lakeisha the teacher on her birthday, but when I waved at her
through the window on the way out she was already smiling a
little bit.  They made up for it by giving her cake because 
it just happened to be the day for their September birthday
celebration.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Altogether, counting the nursery school party, Cordelia had
four birthday parties; one last weekend at Baba and Zaida's
with a chocolate cake and presents, one on Thursday night
at home with a plain cake with pink icing and more presents 
— we got her one of those rugs with roads and railways
and stuff printed on it (Delphine's idea), and &lt;em&gt;Hop on 
Pop&lt;/em&gt; — and yet another this weekend when we 
made a dinosaur-shaped cake just for the fun of it.  We
like cake, what can I say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nursery school&lt;/strong&gt; is going well.  I signed 
her up not to give myself a break — I think it's
actually created more work for me — but because I thought
it was time she started to have a life of her own, to
gain some independence away from me, and to be exposed
to all the rich and interesting things they offer at 
nursery school.  It seems to be a really good facility;
they always have lots of interesting activities set
up when we get there in the morning, the teachers are
lovely, they have a real music teacher with a guitar
in every other week, and every week they take a picture
of your child and save it in a portfolio that you get
to keep at the end of the year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only catch is that the school is about one and a
half kilometers from home, around a fifteen minute
walk.  I originally thought it was going to be a longer walk than
that, before I actually tried it, so I was quite pleased.
On Thursday I strapped on my running shoes and put the
girls in the expensive but very cool jogging stroller /
bike trailer and ran up there, which of course also 
took about fifteen minutes because I am that slow and
also running with a stroller sucks.  But it's better 
than running at 7:30 at night when all I want to do is
collapse on the couch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia can &lt;strong&gt;count to twenty&lt;/strong&gt;, which
is kind of odd for a two-year-old.  She loves to count,
but she's not really counting &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;.  I think 
she knows about counting in some sense; she knows you
do it when you have a lot of something, and that you 
count for a while and then stop and the number you stop
at means something, but she really doesn't map the 
actual number of things to the words she's saying. She
loves to over-count and usually ends up with "seven" 
of whatever it is.  Also when people ask her how old
she is she says "three!"  She just likes numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Incidentally, Delphine's friend Ursa also loved 
counting and numbers, to the extent that she still
calls both letters and numbers "numbers". This is
interesting because Delphine used to call numbers
"letters".  Shall we typecast them as the Wordy One
and the Mathy One already?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;talks in full sentences&lt;/strong&gt;, 
and she has reached
that age when she comes out with syntactically perfect
sentences which leave me speechless.   "Help me put
 my sweater on!"  I hear it and it's a perfect sentence,
and then I realize it came from my tiny baby!
 She doesn't do full sentences all the 
time, though. Mostly she's still trying to cobble together
communication with the few words and bits of grammar she knows,
backed up with pointing and when all else fails, shouting
really loud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Communicating is complicated by the fact that she 
&lt;strong&gt;doesn't
know her colours&lt;/strong&gt; yet; when Delphine was this age at
least we could figure out what she wanted by saying, "What 
colour is it?"  Cordelia, for whatever reason, can't get
her colours straight.  For a couple of weeks everything
was blue ("bah-loo!") and now things seem to be mostly
red.  If you drill her you can get her to get a colour
right for a few minutes but then if you go back to it
later, she goes back to guessing.  I find this rather
perplexing; she doesn't seem to have trouble learning the
words for anything else.  Either she can't map the colours
to the names, or she can't distinguish the colours for
some reason.  Anyway, you aren't really expected to know
your colours until you're three or even four, so maybe 
there is some mental or visual development yet to come
which will resolve this.  In the meantime all the grandparents
have made it their mission to help her learn colours.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;sleeps&lt;/strong&gt; from about six thirty
until six thirty or seven in the morning.  Well, I put
her to bed at six thirty; usually she stays awake talking
and singing to herself until seven.  She also naps from
one until two or two thirty.  (I got all my sleep advice 
from &lt;em&gt;Healthy Sleep Habits, Happy Child&lt;/em&gt; by
Marc Weissbluth, so if you want a narcoleptic child and
a rich adult-only evening life you should read it too.)
She scared me on Friday by not napping at all; I wondered
if she had decided that since now she's two she doesn't
need a nap.  But then she napped yesterday and today, so
I think I still have a napper.  It's nice because she
naps while Delphine is in kindergarten, so I get some time
to get stuff done in the afternoons.  If I am not too tired
to think; afternoon is not my brightest time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia has &lt;strong&gt;peed in the potty&lt;/strong&gt; exactly twice, both times
under the tutelage of Baba.  I suppose she is more or less
ready to be properly potty-trained, which is exciting in
the sense of no more diapers, but I am not looking forward
to the process, the constant trips to the potty and 
interrogation regarding her need for the same.  "Do you have
to go pee?  Do you have to poo?  Do you want to sit on the
potty?"  However, it has to happen sometime!  The nursery
school teachers say they are happy to help, so maybe I
will rope them in and see if we can get it over with.
That would be awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tomorrow is Monday, and October, and I have a million
things to do so I had best get to bed so I am not tired
and grumpy all day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>birthday</category><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>