<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (career)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/career.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:56:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Things on my mind.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/thoughts.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was chatting with a friend and former co-worker of mine today, and
asked him why I was never a part of the group guiding where the
company was going.  (Okay, I actually asked why I was never a part of
the management, but in retrospect that was the wrong question, for
reasons detailed below.  I should have asked the question I said
above.)  His answer basically boiled down to “You never wanted to be.”
One of the things he mentioned was that when I traded salary for extra
vacation days (something I was fairly proud of thinking of, since it
makes me an easier sell to the CFO, and the two are pretty much equal,
if you’re allowed to cash out unused vacation days), it indicated that
my priorities lay more with my family than with the company, with the
unspoken implication that that attitude isn’t one that will lead to a
position of power within the company.  That initial assumption led to
a series of misunderstandings, and miscommunications, until I was
effectively shut out of helping to guide the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that’s fair enough, kinda, but it’s a shame that people think
that having interests outside of the office means that I’m somehow
less interested in the success of the company.  Particularly since I
didn’t take the vacation days, and was always intending on cashing
them out.  So, for my next job, I think I’m going to take that option
off the table, since I didn’t use the vacation days anyways.  (I had
27 days built up when I was laid off!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also asked him what I could do to get into management next time, but
I’m not really sure that’s really where I want to be.  I know a few
people who have moved into management, and then found it hard to get a
job when they were laid off.  Along the same lines, I still believe
I’m a far better architect and coder than manager, and so it’s sort of
foolish for a company to hire me for my managerial skills when my
coding skills are far superior.  And I really &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like
programming.  &lt;strong&gt;Really&lt;/strong&gt;.  With the spare time I had after I was laid
off, I wrote code for an iPhone game.  For fun I read up on
programming languages I haven’t seen before, and solve &lt;a href="http://projecteuler.net/"&gt;Project
Euler&lt;/a&gt; problems with them.  But I don’t
know if there’s a way to parlay my architecture and coding prowess
into the ability to help guide a company, since that seems to be the
exclusive province of people who manage other people.  (Of course, my
work on &lt;a href="http://www.basieproject.org"&gt;Basie&lt;/a&gt; last term also has me
wondering if I’m actually a mediocre manager, or if I may be better at
it than I always thought I was.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose there’s always one way to find out how good a manager/team
lead I am, and I expect I’ll start moving that direction in my next
job.  I can always write code on evenings and weekends, right?  Well,
either way, it’s not something I’ll worry about until I get another
job.  And certainly not something I should be worrying about this
late at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>coding</category><category>management</category><category>work</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/thoughts.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 03:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>