<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (code)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/code.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to break web applications.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/codeanddata.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m watching a video on my new iTouch about how to break web
applications, and it presented the idea that Javascript is the same as
stack overflows which are also the same as getting free phone calls by
whistling a note into a payphone…&lt;br&gt;
They're all examples of bad things happening when you intermingle code
(javascript/return addresses/command tones) and data (html/arrays on
the stack/your voice).  I guess it’s sort of expensive to set up two
connections for every connection, but that seems to be the only way to
avoid stuff like this, which has apparently been happening for
years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s a lot I can do with this new idea, but it
seemed interesting, so I figured I’ld record it for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>code</category><category>data</category><category>hacking</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/codeanddata.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 01:25:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 6…  Uh, 7?</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine6.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what happened to last night’s update.  Well, that’s
not entirely true.  I was at a FogBugz demo given by &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/"&gt;Joel Spolsky&lt;/a&gt;, and Delphine
had a sleep-over at her Baba and Zaida’s, so I took the time to write
&lt;a href="http://pyblosxom.sourceforge.net/2.0/plans/archiveaccess.html"&gt;a spec&lt;/a&gt;, and that led me to whip out a bunch of code.  The spec is
written in something called &lt;a href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/rst/restructuredtext.html"&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt; (uh, that’s the link to the spec, which probably
&lt;i&gt;isn’t&lt;/i&gt; the best way to learn about it, but &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the
document I’ve been using the most), but my favourite Mac text editor
(&lt;a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/textwrangler/index.shtml"&gt;TextWrangler&lt;/a&gt;) doesn’t support it in any way, shape, or form.  So
I started writing &lt;a href="http://bzr.latte.ca/files/restwrangler/head"&gt;a plugin&lt;/a&gt; that
would teach TextWrangler what the heck reStructuredText was.  (You can
apparently get a tarball of the project from &lt;a href="http://bzr.latte.ca/tarball/restwrangler/3"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;, if
you’re so inclined, or if you’re not, you could just try &lt;a href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/static/blake/reST.dmg"&gt;the compiled plugin itself&lt;/a&gt;.  Just
double-click the .dmg file, then double-click the .bblm file inside of
it, and it’ll tell you what to do.  Or mail me, and I will.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, a busy, busy night, but I got to sleep in until 7:00,
which was really nice.  Today was more of the same, except it was
really hot out when Delphine got out of kindergarten, so instead of
playing in the school playground, Delphine and I decided to go to &lt;a href="http://www.torontolife.com/guide/food/dairies/hollywood-gelato/"&gt;Hollywood Gelato&lt;/a&gt;, the local ice cream store.  Tasty.  Tomorrow
Amy gets home, so it’s looking like it’ll be a pretty busy day as
well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>code</category><category>restructuredtext</category><category>specifications</category><category>textwrangler</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine6.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 00:47:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>