<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (cold)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/cold.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>On the road again…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ontheroadagain.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, I finally got the garage door open, after it had been
frozen in a block of ice for most of the winter, and got my bike out.
So this morning, I biked to work for the first time in, uh, I don’t
even know how long.  It was a pretty sweet ride, all in all.  There
were any number of reasons not to do it; my biking jeans are dirty,
it’s too cold, I couldn’t down-shift, but as always there was one
reason that trumped them all.  I wanted to ride again.  And so I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I forgot about during my hiatus were how good that
first cup of coffee tastes after you’ve been riding in -5° weather,
what a rush it is to pass cars as they’re sitting, idling in
stop-and-go traffic, and how invigorated I feel when I finally get to
the office, and sit down.  Oh, also how sore my butt is.  Damn, that’s
a small hard seat.  I can’t wait to get used to it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s about it.  I made it in safely, and I’m sure I’ll be
doing it again, and again, and pocketing the $22.50/week that would
have gone to the TTC, to spend on random upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>cold</category><category>first_ride</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ontheroadagain.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 14:31:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>