<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (conversations)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/conversations.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Conversations with Cordelia</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/conversations/conversation00.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia is so funny and verbal that I think
we almost take the cute things she says for
granted, but I'm going to try and write some
of them down for posterity, and Delphine's
too!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Today,
Cordelia had just woken up from her nap and 
she accompanied me into the bathroom while
I peed.  After I finished peeing she said
"You need paper?"  I agreed and she got
me one little piece of toilet paper, crumpled
up into a tiny ball.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I looked at it and  said, "I have to get some 
more because my bits are very big."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
She said, "I like your hairy and big, strong
bits!"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Thank you!"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"And also your slippers."
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/conversations/conversation00.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversations with Kindergarteners</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/apples.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The other day I went with Delphine's class on a field trip
to the Toronto Botanical Gardens.  I was put in charge of
Delphine; Annie, with long blonde hair in a messy ponytail and
huge blue Cindy Loo Who eyes; and Alyssa, tiny and cheerful
and not particularly inclined to stay with the group.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After all the festivities of looking at leaves and planting
garlic cloves and holding compost worms, we all stopped for
a snack.  The children got granola bars, but I had packed myself
an apple because I knew I would be hungry too.  (I eat like a 
little kid, lots of snacks.)  Alyssa asked what kind of apple
it was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"It’s a Honeycrisp.  I haven't tried them before but I really
like it; it's crispy and juicy and sweet.  We usually get Royal Gala."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"We get Honeycrisp," said Alyssa.  "I like them."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"We get Golden Russet," said Annie.  I asked if she liked
them and she said she did.  "They're brown and the skin is
kind of rough."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I said I would try them next time I bought apples, but
they didn't have any at the grocery store yesterday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Isn't that a weird conversation to have with four and five
year-olds?  I guess that's when you get when you live in
a neighbourhood of foodies.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><category>delphine</category><category>food</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/apples.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 19:43:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Whatever happened to...</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/dinosaurs.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Delphine loves to know whether things are real or pretend,
so after a lengthy discussion about ghosts (starting with
"what do ghosts eat?") she changed the subject:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Are dinosaurs real?"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Not any more.  They're all dead."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Why are they all dead?"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Well, that's a good question."  (The lovely thing about
having children is that you can occasionally answer questions
with that &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; meaning "I don't know.")  I then
took a big breath, about to explain the asteroid theory
(because who doesn't love the idea of a flaming rock flying
at us from space?) when Delphine advanced her own theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"Maybe they're all dead because people took the bones out
of them to put in museums."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, I can't say I'd thought of that.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><category>delphine</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/dinosaurs.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 21:43:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversations With Delphine, Part VII: Beer</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations7.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
One the way home from daycare I stopped off at the LCBO 
to buy beer because it was just that hot.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Erik likes this," said Delphine as we walked through
the store.  "Erik likes these", she said, as we walked
into the beer section.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Mummy likes these too, and Auntie Morgan," I said.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"No!  Just Erik.  What is this called?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"It's called beer."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Oh.  I don't drink beer.  I'm too little."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"That's right."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"When I am older I will drink beer.  But not now.
I am still young."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's good to have something to look forward to.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations7.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversations with Delphine, Part 6</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations6.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
She doesn't say such curious things any more, because
her language skills are better, but she's still pretty
amusing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Today I went to pick her up from daycare, and asked
if she wanted to wear her sweater home.  She said
"I would rather not wear my sweater."  We don't 
talk down to her or modulate our vocabulary or
grammar, so she comes out with these very 
grown-up-sounding words and constructs.  Maybe they're only
funny if you can hear them coming out of a three-year-old.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On the way home we walked past another mother with a
baby, and Delphine said, loudly and in a scandalized
tone, "The baby has no shoes on!"  Fortunately the other
mother just laughed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After supper Blake arrived home, having biked.  It's
warm today so he was pretty sweaty.  Delphine said
"You're wet like water, Daddy!  We could swim in
you!"
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations6.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Things Delphine Says</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations14.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Delphine, being only three and a half, still has lots of those
little kid speech peculiarities which are so adorable that parents
insist on talking about them for years, and even try and teach
them to their grandchildren (ask Blake's father about "meemor" 
and "monsert" some time.  Or don't.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine's most distinctive one is switching consonant sounds
within words, for example "bastick" for "basket", or "bistick"
for "biscuit".  Our doctor's name is Dr Paquette, and Delphine
calls her "Dr Pateck".  Since she also has trouble with the
word "protect" she decided that Dr Pateck is called that because
she patecks us.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Delphine Tells A Joke&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday Delphine received her first issue of the magazine &lt;em&gt;Chirp&lt;/em&gt;,
which is targetted to three- to seven-year-olds.  That's a pretty big
range, so a lot of the magazine is over her head, including the page of
jokes at the end.  I read a couple of riddles to her, but she remained
characteristically stone-faced; however when I read her the knock-knock
joke she laughed.  Encouraged, I read it a couple more times, and then we 
practiced doing it properly, with me taking the lead:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Knock knock!"&lt;br&gt;
"Who's there?"&lt;br&gt;
"Anita!"&lt;br&gt;
"Anita who?"&lt;br&gt;
"Anita cup of hot chocolate!"&lt;br&gt;
Peals of laughter from Delphine.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I thought I would get her to go and tell Daddy the joke as a
surprise.  I coached her a little bit, and sent her off.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here's
how it went:
"Knock knock!  Who's there?  Daddy!  Daddy who?  Daddy cup of hot
chocolate!"  And she laughed and laughed, and Blake was bewildered.
Still funny, but not in quite the same way.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations14.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversations with Delphine, Telephone Edition.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations13.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday I was talking to Auntie Morgan on the telephone.
Delphine wanted to talk to her so I put her on.  They talked
for a while and then Delphine told Morgan about her new
balloon.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"It's over there," she pointed.  "I will show it to you."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then she spent some time trying to  figure out how to get
the phone out of the kitchen (where it is attached to the
wall) into the living room where her balloon was.  Finally
I asked her if she would like me to hold the phone for her
while she went to get her balloon.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Yeah, you hold it.  Don't talk though!  Don't talk!
Just hold it!"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So Morgan and I had a secret whispered conversation while
Delphine went to retrieve her balloon.  Then after she had
"shown" the balloon to Morgan she started playing with it
and got distracted from her telephone conversation.  After
I said "Don't forget to talk to Auntie Morgan!" a couple
of times, Morgan said "Should we say 'good-bye' now?" and
Delphine said "Bye." and handed the phone back to me.
She's a charmer, that one.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She just came running out of the bedroom, said "You're
not my friend, Cordelia," and ran back in.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations13.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversations With Delphine</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations12.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Blake and I usually tidy up the living room every
night after the girls are in bed, but last night we
were just too tired and couldn't be bothered.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This morning Delphine was appalled when she came
into the living room.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"It's so messy!  It was messy ALL NIGHT!  You guys were supposed
to tidy up!"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think 4:30 has just officially become "Tidy-Up 
Time".  "You guys" indeed!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations12.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why?</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/why.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Delphine (still) asks us why a lot.  Sadly, sometimes I don't have a
good answer, which sort of led to the conversation we had this
afternoon.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[First scene.  Two cactuses are dancing.]&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: "Why are the cactuses?"&lt;br&gt;
Me: "Well, uh, they just are.  Questions about why a thing is don't really
have answers."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[Next scene.  A goat has paint on himself.]&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: "Why is he dirty?"&lt;br&gt;
Me: "..."&lt;br&gt;
Delphine: "He's dirty cause he was painting."&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I guess some questions about why a thing is something are easy to
answer but some questions about why a thing is something have no good
answer.  Can anyone tell me what the difference between the questions
is, and how to explain it to a three-year-old without using words like
"intrinsic", or "just because"?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/why.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 18:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The English Language is Putty In Her Hands</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations11.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday Delphine and Cordelia and I went out to run some errands.
On the way home Delphine said, "Do you remember the Vikings?  In 
Daddy's movie?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I didn't remember, but she went on to tell me the story of the 
Vikings, most of which I missed but which ended with "They went
home.  The end."  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then she decided she was going to be a Viking, so she put on her
imaginary
Viking helmet and charged around happily shouting "Vike!  Vike!
Vike!"
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/conversations11.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>