<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (cordelia)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/cordelia.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Cordelia is...</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;...independent!  We had Cordelia's parent-teacher "chat" today,
with her nursery school teachers.  I love talking about my 
children, so I was very excited to be there, and of course Blake
doesn't have a job so he came along 'coz he doesn't have anything
else to do.  Just kidding; he had taken the morning off to
come anyway, before the company folded (or whatever it's in
the process of doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simone and Sameera were very happy to talk about Cordelia too.
Apparently she's a delight at school.  (I bet they say that
to all the parents.)  She's very independent; she puts on
her own outside clothes and clears up after snack by
herself.  This is a revelation to me because like idiots 
we're still helping her on with her snowsuit and boots,
and begging her to take just one thing into the kitchen
after meals.  Suckers, we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her favourite things are sensory activities:
playdough, cornstarch, sand.  Anything messy.
She's still focused to the point of being oblivious to
what's going on around her (she gets that from Blake),
and she's happy playing by herself, to the point that
her teachers are actually engineering situations to
force her into talking and playing with other kids.  They
are going to hook me up with some good playdate matches
for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's their only concern for kindergarten, that she
won't be able to make connections with other kids and
with the teacher.  Academically, in terms of colours,
shapes, letters and numbers, she's just fine!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><category>school</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 13:35:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hallowe'en and Other Things</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're in the midst of the fall festive season, and
as anyone who is less than four feet tall knows, 
that means it's Hallowe'en.  Both Delphine and Cordelia
are very excited, and it's clear that Cordelia
remembers a thing or two about last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine is planning to be a penguin this year.  We haven't bought a penguin costume; rather we
are hoping to kludge something together with 
a white shirt and a black hoodie and orange 
construction paper beak and feet.  I hope it
works because we haven't had a chance to
try it out and we're running out of pre-Hallowe'en
weekend.  Delphine has a pretty convincing penguin
waddle which would sell the lamest costume,
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordelia has independently decided to be a black
cat.  For a while there she was going with
ghost and I thought we would have to find and
then butcher a white sheet — you always see
that white-sheet-with-holes ghost costume in
cartoons and stuff but I've never seen it
in real life.  I thought it would be cool to try
it out.  But about a week ago she switched
to black cat, so I dropped a whopping $19 on
ears and a tail, which together with black clothes
and some eyeliner whiskers will make a convincing
and adorable cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Hallowe'en is that it gives
you lots of chances to talk about such topics of 
childhood interest as death and scary things.  Last
year we spent a lot of time talking about being dead
and what death is (and who Death is — a house around
the corner has an inflatable Grim Reaper).  This year
we are leaning more towards Hallowe'en imagery and
what is scary.  Delphine wanted to know why someone
had fake gravestones on their lawn.  "Gravestones
aren't scary", she said.  I said they mark where dead people
are buried, but she was unmoved by that because to
her mind dead people aren't scary.  And of course 
by extension, skeletons aren't scary either.  What
&lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; scary?  Witches, spiders and ghosts are apparently
scary.  I don't think bats are and rats definitely 
aren't, although we did decorate with black rubber 
rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine likes Monopoly.  I know, weird.  I wouldn't
have occurred to me to put her in front of a game of
Monopoly, but my friend Tanya, who is nothing if not
ambitious with what she exposes her kid to, brought it
over and Delphine loves it.  She loves the money: she
likes to sort it out, stack it up, pay for things and
get money from other people.  She likes choosing which
piece she will be, and she loves to move around the
board.  She got tired of it, though, after maybe forty minutes,
and started acting up.  "I'm so bored of giving people
money!"  Yeah, tell me about it.  So for Christmas I
got her &lt;em&gt;Monopoly Junior&lt;/em&gt;.  I'm normally not in favour
of kiddified versions of things, but this looks like
it retains the main elements of the adult version
(including the lovely money) but goes faster.  Plus
the setting is a carnival, not some boring old city.
Delphine loves carnivals and fairs and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cordelia went for her birthday sleepover at Auntie
Morgan's house this weekend.  Unfortunately I have
no idea what they did because Cordelia said she had
fun but she didn't want to talk about it.  I know
what Delphine did, though, because she stayed home
for what we have termed a "sleepunder", which is
what you get when you're the sister who stays
home and has Mum and Dad to herself.  Mostly we
played Monopoly.  Delphine chose KD for supper, and
we read lots of chapters at bedtime because we
didn't have to put Cordelia to bed.  In the morning
Delphine decreed that Blake should get up early (that
is, when Delphine and I got up) and join us for a 
breakfast of French toast and pancakes.  Then more
Monopoly, and then we went out to get Cordelia back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Incidentally, the thing with Blake getting up with us turned
out abysmally.  Usually he stays in bed for an hour
or more on weekend mornings while I get up with the
kids and make breakfast and read the paper.  Having
missed that extra sleep, however, he was logy and 
grumpy all day.  He napped twice but it didn't help.
God knows what he's like during the week, but from
now on I will gladly let him get his morning beauty
sleep.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sleepunder was lovely.  Unfortunately at the moment the girls
are much more pleasant to be around one at a time than
together.  Delphine alone is insightful and contemplative
and interesting, Cordelia alone is funny and clever and
demonstrative.  Together they are whiny and scrappy 
and tiresome.  Not all the time, but often enough that
it wears me out.  Hopefully between them they will eventually
grow out
of it and figure out how to enjoy each other's company
more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>holidays</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 19:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Home alone</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/homealone.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Amy mentioned in the previous post, her father passed away.  So she’s
gone out to Saskatchewan to spend some time with her mother.  This means
that for the next seven days, I get to stay home and take care of the
kids, making sure that they have food to eat, clothes to wear, and get
to wherever they’re going when they need to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day went pretty well, the only casualty being a
slightly-charred side of a grilled bacon-tomato-cheese sandwich.  And
today has been going pretty well too, with a load of laundry washed and
hung, the dishwasher currently running, and tonight’s meal (beef stew in
the crock pot) already cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large part of why it’s all running so smoothly is my parents.  They
have totally stepped up, helping me by taking Delphine and Cordelia
places, or just looking after them while I do the stuff that needs to be
done around the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine has been a huge help too.  This morning, while I was in the
shower, she got dressed, came downstairs, got out three bowls and three
small spoons, some cereal, and the milk from the fridge.  She then
poured cereal for herself and Cordelia, and the two of them were done
breakfast before I was dressed.  I know she’s five and all, but
sometimes she’s so grown up it astonishes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, they’re currently out on an adventure with Zaida, so I’ld
better get to folding the laundry, because it ain’t gonna fold itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>family</category><category>home</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/homealone.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 14:12:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What We Did On Our Summer Vacation</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/summervacation.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's cool today, and rainy, but I opened the doors and
windows anyway, because it's the last day of summer vacation
and I want to get as much of that summer air in the house
as I can before we get back to the routine of walking here,
walking there, packing snacks, hurrying up and going.  This
year I have got myself yet more taking and fetching to do
in the form of an eight-year-old boy I'm looking after 
before and after school.  He won't make much more work for
me (I think, unless he turns out to be horrible, which
I'm pretty sure he isn't) and he makes me quite a lot more
money, so I expect that will be a net win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's what's happening next, and I wanted to post
about what we did this summer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we did in summer vacation was a trip to
the ROM, on the very first day after school ended.  Getting there
turned out to be quite an ordeal; the subway wasn't running,
so we tried in various ways to outsmart the crowded
shuttle buses; we took the number 11 back to Mount Pleasant,
tried to catch a Mount Pleasant bus (almost lost Cordelia),
then got back on another number 11 which magically turned
into a Yonge Street shuttle.  (We missed the most 
obvious workaround which is to take the normal 97 Yonge 
St bus.)  All
our fooling around killed enough time that they managed
to get the subway running again by the time we got to St
Clair, and we were back en route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all that we had a nice visit to the ROM, and saw both
the Darwin and Wedgewood exhibits.  Because my mother is
from North Staffordshire of course we think we're related
to both Wedgewood and Darwin, so I particularly enjoyed 
the exhibits.  For that reason and also  because both Staffordshire
pottery and evolution are particularly close to my heart.
And did you know ceramics and fossils have similar
chemical properties?  It's all connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned we almost lost Cordelia, but what I should say
is that she almost lost us.  We were all standing at the
corner waiting for the bus, and the girls were fooling around
on a little staircase, hanging on the banisters, walking down
the hill, the usual fidgety little kid stuff.  Suddenly Cordelia
took off running in the opposite direction, crying and shouting.
I wondered if perhaps she had been bitten by something, or
seen a scary dog.  I shouted her name but she didn't turn around,
so Blake took off after her.  She was running full-tilt so she
got half a block before he caught up with her, and apparently
she had lost track of us and thought we had lost her.  She was
petrified!  She has a fear of being left behind or leaving
someone else behind — if I don't stop and wait for Delphine
while we're out walking she screams "Mummy 'top!" — and I 
guess she panicked and forgot to, oh, look around a full 360°
before running for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another adventure was a trip downtown to have lunch with Daddy.
I wasn't sure whether simply going downtown would be enough
excitement for two little kids, but Delphine kept saying "I love
downtown!"  We went to Queen and stopped at The Bay for some 
kid undergarments, and then walked along to John to Grange Park.
Delphine and I had already walked along Queen a few weeks earlier 
when we went to the ballet, and I think she got a kick out of
seeing places again.  "This is where they always have a ice
cream truck and a french fries truck!"  We stopped for a snack
on the landscaped median of University, under the statue of
Adam Beck who apparently invented hydro-electricity.  Apparently
it still isn't cheap enough, because the fountain at his feet
wasn't running.  As we were sitting, Delphine looked up and
said "That building says 'Canada Life'."  Which it does!  She
reads everything now, signs and the writing on trucks and 
labels, which I remember doing as a kid and apparently Blake
did too.  Actually I still do it; if it's printed I have to
read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our goals for this summer was to go out on a boat, 
so one fine Monday morning the girls and I went down to the 
Harbourfront.  We walked along the boardwalk admiring the
boats and ships, and looking for ducks, until I found someone
selling boat rides.  I asked him which was the cheapest one, and he
said we could all go out on the Ste Marie for $11; it was 
to be a 45 minute ride leaving at 11:15, so we signed on.  We
turned out to be the only passengers on a tour around the 
Toronto islands; we saw nature preserves and Centre Island,
swans and cygnets, and learned all about Ned Hanlan.  Delphine
won herself and Cordelia a lollipop each in a one-question trivia
contest: "What lake are we on right now?"  "Ontario Lake!"  I
had told her that very morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest adventure this summer was a surprise trip to
Saskatchewan, surprise because I had intended to go at
Christmas until I realized it would be fully twice a much
money, to the tune of $4000 instead of $2000, to go at
Christmas instead of summer.  So we decided to go in 
August instead.  I flew out there with the girls first,
and my mother's saintly friend Shirley picked
us up from the airport in Saskatoon.  Blake came a few days
later, and picked up a rental car and drove to Big River 
by himself, almost without incident!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shirley also engineered
the high point of the visit, a fishing trip in her
motor boat.  Delphine got to reel in a fish, and I also
fished for the very first time.  Blake caught the biggest
fish of the day, but we released all of them in favour of
some already-clean fish from Shirley's freezer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to stay quite busy in Saskatchewan, going out
for lunch a couple of times, driving down to PA to see an
old school friend, going to the school playground, visiting
the farmer's market, shopping in Debden, or just going to
get the mail.  The girls had a great time with my mum; she
let them watch as much TV as they wanted, eat cookies and
play with all her thousands of tchotchkes.  Blake said
that between the cookies and fishing and &lt;em&gt;Wheel of Fortune&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt; it was just like his visits to his grandparents
in Winnipeg when he was a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited my Dad in the nursing home a couple of times.
Last year, when Cordelia and I were in Sask in September, my dad
had just moved into the nursing home and we visited every day.
We chatted with him and had a nice time.  This year I literally
didn't recognize him at first: he was tucked up in a giant
bed-like wheelchair and he had lost a lot of weight.  With his
teeth out he just looked like some generic old guy, skinny and
wrinkly and not like
my dad at all.  It took a minute to recognize that nose and
those ears, things that don't change, and then I realized
that old guy was really my dad.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day we were there
he didn't open his eyes or acknowledge us at all, apart from
tapping his foot apparently in response to the songs that
the girls and I sang for him.  I was so
shook up it took me a couple of days to gather the nerve to go
again, but when I did I was sorry I had waited, because Dad
opened his eyes and looked at me and the girls and smiled at us.
But the next time we visited, again he didn't open his eyes.  All
I could do for him was ask the nurses to play music for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were in Sask the hospital called my mother to let her
know that they are discontinuing his diabetes medication because
he's not eating.  I know my poor Dad is just trying to go, and
there's no legal way we can make it easier for him.  Humanity my ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls took it all in their stride.  They asked why Grandpa
doesn't talk or open his eyes, and I said he's really old and
sick and he needs to sleep all the time.  I said he's too tired
to open his eyes or talk.  They weren't upset about it at all,
because they are still young enough that they take it in their
stride, and because neither of them really knew him when he was
lucid.  Dad got to meet Delphine when she was three, but I don't
know how much of that either of them remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother, on the other hand, is doing well by herself.  She
has friends and neighbours who help her out with things like
mowing the lawn.  The people in town — the pharmacist, 
the postmaster, the plumber (just like in a Richard Scarry book)
— know her and look out for her.
And of course she has her cats to torment her and keep her
on her toes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when the children were younger the travel itself
was the big worry, but there was hardly anything to talk about
this time; I loaded up with activity books and little 
plane-friendly toys — a magnetic dress-up doll, some brilliant
Micro Playmobil in its own little box, sticker books — and
plenty of snacks, and we managed the three hours on the plane
and two and a half hours in the car without much ado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we got home from Sask we haven't had any  grand adventures, although
we have had a steady stream of playdates and visits.  School
starts next Wednesday and Delphine is looking forward to it.
She was scared that she wouldn't like her teacher, until she
received a welcome letter from said teacher in the mail and 
now she's excited and happy.  Cordelia's school starts the
following Monday — she's doing Monday, Wednesday and Friday
this year.  I don't know how that's going to go; she has
been very clingy lately.  I expect she will howl terribly,
I will leave and she'll be fine within five minutes.  I
expect further that after a couple of weeks of school
she will no longer be so clingy.  There's nothing like
confronting your fears, even when you're two and your mother
makes you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this has been a great summer.  At the beginning I
wondered if I should have enrolled my kids in a thousand
camps and programs, like everyone else does (nevermind that
we don't have the money).  I decided I would rather not
spend my entire summer ferrying everyone around, and that
we would make our own fun, and so we did.  There was a 
little whining that there's nothing to do, that we never
go to the park, that our backyard is the worst in the world,
and that everyone else gets to go away on holiday, but for the
most part we got along with each other and found interesting
things to do both near and far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>saskatchewan</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/summervacation.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 19:28:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More pictures.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/jul19.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This afternoon, Cordelia wanted to “paint on your computer”!  so after
I finished my game, I fired up Sketches, and this is what she ended up
painting.  It’s nothing in particular, but kind of pretty nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/delphine/2008-07-19/Cordelia.jpg"&gt;&lt;br clear="all"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>images</category><category>itouch</category><category>pictures</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/jul19.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 22:41:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Graduation Videos</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/gradvids.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Here is Cordelia watching, bemused, as everyone else participates
in "Sticky Bubblegum":
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;
  &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/lNoEYU5GL4M"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/lNoEYU5GL4M" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And here is Delphine and her class performing a chant about
recycling:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;
  &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/qdtJ7ueQ95c"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/qdtJ7ueQ95c" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>video</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/gradvids.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:25:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First Hallowe'en in the New House!</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/halloween07.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Our neighbourhood loves Hallowe'en.  At least half of the 
houses, it seems, are decorated, and the sidewalks were so
thick with trick or treaters last night that most people
weren't even bothering to close their doors between
visitors.  On our block most of our neighbours were sitting
on the front porch steps chatting; some with wine, some
without.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We decorated our house with three pumpkins (remember when
one jack o' lantern was enough?) and three bats made from
our leftover NDP campaign sign, painstakingly cut out and
coloured with black magic marker.  We also used the 
uprights upon which said sign was mounted to string a 
spiderweb to which I glued a spider, also made from
the sign.  (I decided I wasn't going to buy anything
last month so we had to make our own decorations from
whatever we had at hand.  Thank goodness there had been
an election!)  It all looked pretty awesome,
and all the more satisfying since we didn't just buy it
at the dollar store.  I guess today I should
take it all down.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Last night Cordelia was dressed as a bumblebee, with 
yellow and black
tights and a pair of sparkly wings.  (The headband with 
antennae came off pretty early and Morgan and I ended
up wearing it.)  She loved trick or treating, and she
wouldn't let anyone else hold her bag of candy even when
it was almost too heavy for her to carry.  She learned
to say "t'ick a t'eat!" and "t'anks!" right away.  Well,
with prompting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Delphine was a bunny, with fluffy ears, a beige hoodie (bunnyhug!) 
and a cottontail sewed to her white skirt.  She was into
trick or treating until she hit the Brick Wall of Sleepiness
at around 7:15 and refused to get off the 
&lt;a href="http://www.lascal.se/html/kb_models01.aspx"&gt;kiddy 
board&lt;/a&gt; until we got home.  Cordelia trick or treated
at a couple of different houses after that and when Delphine
was asked if she wanted some candy she said "No thanks."
When that kid is tired, she is tired.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After we got home and sorted through Delphine's candy,
and ate some, we put the girls to bed (an hour late!)
Then Blake and I picked through their respective booty
and set aside the thirty most succulent (and safe, and
appropriate) pieces (one for
each day in November) for each girl, and kept the rest for ourselves!
Well, Blake will take them to work and fatten up his
colleagues.  Then we sat and watched &lt;em&gt;Band Candy&lt;/em&gt; and
ate chocolate until we were done eating chocolate.  Which,
for reference, means we ate a lot of chocolate.  Mmmm...
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>holidays</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/halloween07.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 18:45:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordelia Is Two!</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia turned two on Thursday, which was kind of sucky for
her because it was her fourth day of nursery school and so she's
still suffering from lots of separation anxiety.  I felt like
a monster leaving her crying and miserable in the arms of
Lakeisha the teacher on her birthday, but when I waved at her
through the window on the way out she was already smiling a
little bit.  They made up for it by giving her cake because 
it just happened to be the day for their September birthday
celebration.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Altogether, counting the nursery school party, Cordelia had
four birthday parties; one last weekend at Baba and Zaida's
with a chocolate cake and presents, one on Thursday night
at home with a plain cake with pink icing and more presents 
— we got her one of those rugs with roads and railways
and stuff printed on it (Delphine's idea), and &lt;em&gt;Hop on 
Pop&lt;/em&gt; — and yet another this weekend when we 
made a dinosaur-shaped cake just for the fun of it.  We
like cake, what can I say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nursery school&lt;/strong&gt; is going well.  I signed 
her up not to give myself a break — I think it's
actually created more work for me — but because I thought
it was time she started to have a life of her own, to
gain some independence away from me, and to be exposed
to all the rich and interesting things they offer at 
nursery school.  It seems to be a really good facility;
they always have lots of interesting activities set
up when we get there in the morning, the teachers are
lovely, they have a real music teacher with a guitar
in every other week, and every week they take a picture
of your child and save it in a portfolio that you get
to keep at the end of the year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only catch is that the school is about one and a
half kilometers from home, around a fifteen minute
walk.  I originally thought it was going to be a longer walk than
that, before I actually tried it, so I was quite pleased.
On Thursday I strapped on my running shoes and put the
girls in the expensive but very cool jogging stroller /
bike trailer and ran up there, which of course also 
took about fifteen minutes because I am that slow and
also running with a stroller sucks.  But it's better 
than running at 7:30 at night when all I want to do is
collapse on the couch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia can &lt;strong&gt;count to twenty&lt;/strong&gt;, which
is kind of odd for a two-year-old.  She loves to count,
but she's not really counting &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;.  I think 
she knows about counting in some sense; she knows you
do it when you have a lot of something, and that you 
count for a while and then stop and the number you stop
at means something, but she really doesn't map the 
actual number of things to the words she's saying. She
loves to over-count and usually ends up with "seven" 
of whatever it is.  Also when people ask her how old
she is she says "three!"  She just likes numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Incidentally, Delphine's friend Ursa also loved 
counting and numbers, to the extent that she still
calls both letters and numbers "numbers". This is
interesting because Delphine used to call numbers
"letters".  Shall we typecast them as the Wordy One
and the Mathy One already?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;talks in full sentences&lt;/strong&gt;, 
and she has reached
that age when she comes out with syntactically perfect
sentences which leave me speechless.   "Help me put
 my sweater on!"  I hear it and it's a perfect sentence,
and then I realize it came from my tiny baby!
 She doesn't do full sentences all the 
time, though. Mostly she's still trying to cobble together
communication with the few words and bits of grammar she knows,
backed up with pointing and when all else fails, shouting
really loud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Communicating is complicated by the fact that she 
&lt;strong&gt;doesn't
know her colours&lt;/strong&gt; yet; when Delphine was this age at
least we could figure out what she wanted by saying, "What 
colour is it?"  Cordelia, for whatever reason, can't get
her colours straight.  For a couple of weeks everything
was blue ("bah-loo!") and now things seem to be mostly
red.  If you drill her you can get her to get a colour
right for a few minutes but then if you go back to it
later, she goes back to guessing.  I find this rather
perplexing; she doesn't seem to have trouble learning the
words for anything else.  Either she can't map the colours
to the names, or she can't distinguish the colours for
some reason.  Anyway, you aren't really expected to know
your colours until you're three or even four, so maybe 
there is some mental or visual development yet to come
which will resolve this.  In the meantime all the grandparents
have made it their mission to help her learn colours.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;sleeps&lt;/strong&gt; from about six thirty
until six thirty or seven in the morning.  Well, I put
her to bed at six thirty; usually she stays awake talking
and singing to herself until seven.  She also naps from
one until two or two thirty.  (I got all my sleep advice 
from &lt;em&gt;Healthy Sleep Habits, Happy Child&lt;/em&gt; by
Marc Weissbluth, so if you want a narcoleptic child and
a rich adult-only evening life you should read it too.)
She scared me on Friday by not napping at all; I wondered
if she had decided that since now she's two she doesn't
need a nap.  But then she napped yesterday and today, so
I think I still have a napper.  It's nice because she
naps while Delphine is in kindergarten, so I get some time
to get stuff done in the afternoons.  If I am not too tired
to think; afternoon is not my brightest time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia has &lt;strong&gt;peed in the potty&lt;/strong&gt; exactly twice, both times
under the tutelage of Baba.  I suppose she is more or less
ready to be properly potty-trained, which is exciting in
the sense of no more diapers, but I am not looking forward
to the process, the constant trips to the potty and 
interrogation regarding her need for the same.  "Do you have
to go pee?  Do you have to poo?  Do you want to sit on the
potty?"  However, it has to happen sometime!  The nursery
school teachers say they are happy to help, so maybe I
will rope them in and see if we can get it over with.
That would be awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tomorrow is Monday, and October, and I have a million
things to do so I had best get to bed so I am not tired
and grumpy all day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>birthday</category><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We're Back!</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/back.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia and I are back from Saskatchewan so Blake's adventure
in single parenthood is over.  He was obligingly overwhelmed by
it — “I hardly had any time to read at all!”, and that's
with only one kid, and the easy one at that.  Yeah, keeping house
and raising babies is, in fact, a lot of work.  Who knew?  I am
only kind of being sarcastic here; I used to think I would feel
guilty about staying home until I realized how much damn work it
is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But anyway, Saskatchewan.  We went to visit my parents, and the
timing was good because my dad just went into a nursing home
so my mom needed help with getting him settled in and getting
the house sorted out so she can manage on her own.  We cleaned
and sorted and went out for lunch and shopped (as much as you
can shop in Big River); it was a regular ladies' week.  Cordelia
was a huge hit with my mum; they read the Sears catalog and 
watched TV and looked at all the stuff my mum has.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia and I visited my dad at the home every day, and Cordelia
was a huge hit with the grannies and grandpas, with her big grin
and very loud observations.  “Dinosaur there!”  “See fishies!”
She also pulled out all the grandbaby stops on the last day
and gave my dad lots of nice hugs and kisses.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So there is a huge blog entry just waiting to be written, 
about this summer and how Delphine and Cordelia are doing,
about my thirty-second birthday;  all that narcissistic 
blather you have come to expect from this blog.  Whether I
will ever get around to writing that entry is yet to be
seen, but I have high hopes for this next month, what with
school and all.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>saskatchewan</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/back.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 01:19:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven and A Half Months</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/sevenmonths.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Cordelia is seven and a half months, and she is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleeping in her own bed all night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eating vegetables, fruit, cereals, milk products, and some meat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chewing!  So I can give her little pieces of toast and stuff
    and she doesn't gag.  Hooray!  Table food!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulling herself up to standing (and then falling over)...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...but not crawling properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although she does get around pretty well doing the worm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still really charming and smiley, but...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...showing some separation anxiety.  Whenever a stranger
   stops to talk to her she gets this slightly worried (but
   friendly) expression and looks at me to make sure everything
   is okay. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19 pounds -- still large for her age, but well-proportioned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muscular and strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/sevenmonths.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>