<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (delphine)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/delphine.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My First Entry</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/myfirstentry.html</link><dc:creator>Delphine Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My name is Delphine.  There’s another Delphine in the school I go to.  I go
to a K-6 school in Toronto.  My friend at my school’s name is Darina.  She
really likes bugs.  She’s going to dress up as a moth for Halloween.  I’m
dressing up as an elf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, me and my dad cooked dinner.  We had sandwiches, soup, and mini
pizzas.  It was fun to make dinner with Dad.  I liked making the
sandwiches.  I made five sandwiches.  They were tomato, mayonnaise and
cheese sandwiches.  Dad made the soup, and it was very good.  The mini
pizzas were kind of hard to make, because they took a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Ursa has gone to Winnipeg.  We feed her cats.  Her cats’ names
are Hebi-Chan and Columbus.  Here’s a joke: What do you call a locomotive
with a cold?  An achoo-choo train!  One more: Where would you weigh a
whale?  At the whale-weigh station!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Monday.  I’m going to go to school.  I like art.  I do not like
math.  The end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>first</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/myfirstentry.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 14:43:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Poems By Delphine</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/pomes.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine has written one poem and and two, um, prose pieces which
might be poems.  Here they are, preserving random capitals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;me you we&lt;br&gt;
A soiN. A Bote.&lt;br&gt;
Me AND You tRNiNg&lt;br&gt;
iN toWe.&lt;br&gt;
Musis togetheR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OBWisANA&lt;br&gt;
An AFRKNSoiNg&lt;br&gt;
tAte i LiKe&lt;br&gt;
MUsistogetheR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sEa&lt;br&gt;
DoLPhiNS AND FiSh.&lt;br&gt;
AND SEahors too.&lt;br&gt;
thosoR the thiNgs iN the SEa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>writing</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/pomes.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 02:01:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hallowe'en and Other Things</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're in the midst of the fall festive season, and
as anyone who is less than four feet tall knows, 
that means it's Hallowe'en.  Both Delphine and Cordelia
are very excited, and it's clear that Cordelia
remembers a thing or two about last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine is planning to be a penguin this year.  We haven't bought a penguin costume; rather we
are hoping to kludge something together with 
a white shirt and a black hoodie and orange 
construction paper beak and feet.  I hope it
works because we haven't had a chance to
try it out and we're running out of pre-Hallowe'en
weekend.  Delphine has a pretty convincing penguin
waddle which would sell the lamest costume,
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordelia has independently decided to be a black
cat.  For a while there she was going with
ghost and I thought we would have to find and
then butcher a white sheet — you always see
that white-sheet-with-holes ghost costume in
cartoons and stuff but I've never seen it
in real life.  I thought it would be cool to try
it out.  But about a week ago she switched
to black cat, so I dropped a whopping $19 on
ears and a tail, which together with black clothes
and some eyeliner whiskers will make a convincing
and adorable cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Hallowe'en is that it gives
you lots of chances to talk about such topics of 
childhood interest as death and scary things.  Last
year we spent a lot of time talking about being dead
and what death is (and who Death is — a house around
the corner has an inflatable Grim Reaper).  This year
we are leaning more towards Hallowe'en imagery and
what is scary.  Delphine wanted to know why someone
had fake gravestones on their lawn.  "Gravestones
aren't scary", she said.  I said they mark where dead people
are buried, but she was unmoved by that because to
her mind dead people aren't scary.  And of course 
by extension, skeletons aren't scary either.  What
&lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; scary?  Witches, spiders and ghosts are apparently
scary.  I don't think bats are and rats definitely 
aren't, although we did decorate with black rubber 
rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine likes Monopoly.  I know, weird.  I wouldn't
have occurred to me to put her in front of a game of
Monopoly, but my friend Tanya, who is nothing if not
ambitious with what she exposes her kid to, brought it
over and Delphine loves it.  She loves the money: she
likes to sort it out, stack it up, pay for things and
get money from other people.  She likes choosing which
piece she will be, and she loves to move around the
board.  She got tired of it, though, after maybe forty minutes,
and started acting up.  "I'm so bored of giving people
money!"  Yeah, tell me about it.  So for Christmas I
got her &lt;em&gt;Monopoly Junior&lt;/em&gt;.  I'm normally not in favour
of kiddified versions of things, but this looks like
it retains the main elements of the adult version
(including the lovely money) but goes faster.  Plus
the setting is a carnival, not some boring old city.
Delphine loves carnivals and fairs and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cordelia went for her birthday sleepover at Auntie
Morgan's house this weekend.  Unfortunately I have
no idea what they did because Cordelia said she had
fun but she didn't want to talk about it.  I know
what Delphine did, though, because she stayed home
for what we have termed a "sleepunder", which is
what you get when you're the sister who stays
home and has Mum and Dad to herself.  Mostly we
played Monopoly.  Delphine chose KD for supper, and
we read lots of chapters at bedtime because we
didn't have to put Cordelia to bed.  In the morning
Delphine decreed that Blake should get up early (that
is, when Delphine and I got up) and join us for a 
breakfast of French toast and pancakes.  Then more
Monopoly, and then we went out to get Cordelia back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Incidentally, the thing with Blake getting up with us turned
out abysmally.  Usually he stays in bed for an hour
or more on weekend mornings while I get up with the
kids and make breakfast and read the paper.  Having
missed that extra sleep, however, he was logy and 
grumpy all day.  He napped twice but it didn't help.
God knows what he's like during the week, but from
now on I will gladly let him get his morning beauty
sleep.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sleepunder was lovely.  Unfortunately at the moment the girls
are much more pleasant to be around one at a time than
together.  Delphine alone is insightful and contemplative
and interesting, Cordelia alone is funny and clever and
demonstrative.  Together they are whiny and scrappy 
and tiresome.  Not all the time, but often enough that
it wears me out.  Hopefully between them they will eventually
grow out
of it and figure out how to enjoy each other's company
more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>holidays</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 19:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Home alone</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/homealone.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Amy mentioned in the previous post, her father passed away.  So she’s
gone out to Saskatchewan to spend some time with her mother.  This means
that for the next seven days, I get to stay home and take care of the
kids, making sure that they have food to eat, clothes to wear, and get
to wherever they’re going when they need to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day went pretty well, the only casualty being a
slightly-charred side of a grilled bacon-tomato-cheese sandwich.  And
today has been going pretty well too, with a load of laundry washed and
hung, the dishwasher currently running, and tonight’s meal (beef stew in
the crock pot) already cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large part of why it’s all running so smoothly is my parents.  They
have totally stepped up, helping me by taking Delphine and Cordelia
places, or just looking after them while I do the stuff that needs to be
done around the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine has been a huge help too.  This morning, while I was in the
shower, she got dressed, came downstairs, got out three bowls and three
small spoons, some cereal, and the milk from the fridge.  She then
poured cereal for herself and Cordelia, and the two of them were done
breakfast before I was dressed.  I know she’s five and all, but
sometimes she’s so grown up it astonishes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, they’re currently out on an adventure with Zaida, so I’ld
better get to folding the laundry, because it ain’t gonna fold itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>family</category><category>home</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/homealone.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 14:12:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First Day of Senior Kindergarten</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/firstdaysk.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday was Delphine's last day of summer vacation.
We stuck labels on her &lt;a href="http://www.landsend.com/pp/SolidClassMateJuniorBackpack~146384_-1.html?bcc=y&amp;amp;action=order_more&amp;amp;sku_0=::PRO&amp;amp;CM_MERCH=IDX_00004__0000000491"&gt;new backpack&lt;/a&gt;, 
lunch bag and 
&lt;a href="http://zeta.zappos.com/product/7319163/color/16179"&gt;shoes&lt;/a&gt;, and speculated about her new teacher, which
of last year's kids would be in this year's class, and 
whether the JKs would be cute or not.  While we were
eating lunch I wondered how we had felt on the same day last
year, Delphine's last day before Junior Kindergarten. 
Were we excited, were we nervous?  I don't know, and I
never will because I never wrote it down.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year Delphine was a little nervous.  She was 
scared that the teacher wouldn't like her, although
that fear was largely soothed by the arrival of a 
lovely letter from Mrs Thompson to Delphine (in the
mail, no less!)  saying how excited she was to 
meet Delphine and what fun they would have in 
kindergarten, learning letters and numbers.  Delphine
was a bit offended by that last bit — "I already
know letters and numbers!" — but I said Mrs T
probably sent the same letter to the SKs and JKs, 
who might not know their letters and numbers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, too, was a little nervous, probably more so than
last year because this year I know what is coming —
a lot of getting people places on time and not much
time in between to take stock.  But only a little
nervous, because this year I do know what's coming,
and I have a plan, and perhaps most importantly I
have accepted that taking people places is my main
job during the school year (well, along with feeding
and clothing them), and anything else I can
get done apart from that is pretty much bonus.  So
rather than regarding the commuting as an inconvenient
interruption to my life, I now just go along with it.
Think of all the exercise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine's first day of school was last Wednesday.
She's still in afternoons, and she's in the same classroom
as last year, and as it turns out, all the Seniors were
in her class last year.  The first day of school
was only Seniors, so she got to renew some old friendships
and get to know her new teacher.  Delphine loves Mrs Thompson!
Mrs Thompson smiles a lot, and on the first day she wore a pink
dress — I don't know if that was calculated to win the
favour of a roomful of five-year-old girls (the Seniors
are six girls and two boys) but if it was, it worked.
Delphine says Mrs Thompson does everything in the
wrong order (which is to say, not the way Mrs
Hollister did it) but she seems willing to indulge her
errors.    Mrs Thompson taught her a new song!
In fact, yesterday Mrs Thompson taught her the 
Macarena!  And they say public schooling is inferior!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine has now had four days of SK.  She wasn't
impressed by the JKs on day two — they were noisy
and talked too much — but yesterday she kind of made
friends with one of them.  She had gym on Thursday 
(her teacher's name is Mr Laundry!  Actually it's
Mr Landry, but 'Mr Laundry' cracks her up) and Library
on Friday, and everything seems to be going fabulously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Delphine learned to read over the summer, and
SK/Grade 1 is supposed to be when you learn to read,
I'm going to talk to Mrs Thompson about what, if any,
other goals Delphine should work towards over the 
school year, and what kinds of enrichment she can
offer her.  She's beyond the basic "k-k-k-kite"
Jolly Phonics stuff this year, so I hope we can manage
not to bore her out of her tree.  Especially 
considering there are only eight SKs.  But I'm
borrowing trouble, I'm sure we'll work something out.
Now it's time to make lunch and haul everyone off to
school, at least once I manage to get some clothes
on Cordelia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>school</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/firstdaysk.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 18:59:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What We Did On Our Summer Vacation</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/summervacation.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's cool today, and rainy, but I opened the doors and
windows anyway, because it's the last day of summer vacation
and I want to get as much of that summer air in the house
as I can before we get back to the routine of walking here,
walking there, packing snacks, hurrying up and going.  This
year I have got myself yet more taking and fetching to do
in the form of an eight-year-old boy I'm looking after 
before and after school.  He won't make much more work for
me (I think, unless he turns out to be horrible, which
I'm pretty sure he isn't) and he makes me quite a lot more
money, so I expect that will be a net win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's what's happening next, and I wanted to post
about what we did this summer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we did in summer vacation was a trip to
the ROM, on the very first day after school ended.  Getting there
turned out to be quite an ordeal; the subway wasn't running,
so we tried in various ways to outsmart the crowded
shuttle buses; we took the number 11 back to Mount Pleasant,
tried to catch a Mount Pleasant bus (almost lost Cordelia),
then got back on another number 11 which magically turned
into a Yonge Street shuttle.  (We missed the most 
obvious workaround which is to take the normal 97 Yonge 
St bus.)  All
our fooling around killed enough time that they managed
to get the subway running again by the time we got to St
Clair, and we were back en route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all that we had a nice visit to the ROM, and saw both
the Darwin and Wedgewood exhibits.  Because my mother is
from North Staffordshire of course we think we're related
to both Wedgewood and Darwin, so I particularly enjoyed 
the exhibits.  For that reason and also  because both Staffordshire
pottery and evolution are particularly close to my heart.
And did you know ceramics and fossils have similar
chemical properties?  It's all connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned we almost lost Cordelia, but what I should say
is that she almost lost us.  We were all standing at the
corner waiting for the bus, and the girls were fooling around
on a little staircase, hanging on the banisters, walking down
the hill, the usual fidgety little kid stuff.  Suddenly Cordelia
took off running in the opposite direction, crying and shouting.
I wondered if perhaps she had been bitten by something, or
seen a scary dog.  I shouted her name but she didn't turn around,
so Blake took off after her.  She was running full-tilt so she
got half a block before he caught up with her, and apparently
she had lost track of us and thought we had lost her.  She was
petrified!  She has a fear of being left behind or leaving
someone else behind — if I don't stop and wait for Delphine
while we're out walking she screams "Mummy 'top!" — and I 
guess she panicked and forgot to, oh, look around a full 360°
before running for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another adventure was a trip downtown to have lunch with Daddy.
I wasn't sure whether simply going downtown would be enough
excitement for two little kids, but Delphine kept saying "I love
downtown!"  We went to Queen and stopped at The Bay for some 
kid undergarments, and then walked along to John to Grange Park.
Delphine and I had already walked along Queen a few weeks earlier 
when we went to the ballet, and I think she got a kick out of
seeing places again.  "This is where they always have a ice
cream truck and a french fries truck!"  We stopped for a snack
on the landscaped median of University, under the statue of
Adam Beck who apparently invented hydro-electricity.  Apparently
it still isn't cheap enough, because the fountain at his feet
wasn't running.  As we were sitting, Delphine looked up and
said "That building says 'Canada Life'."  Which it does!  She
reads everything now, signs and the writing on trucks and 
labels, which I remember doing as a kid and apparently Blake
did too.  Actually I still do it; if it's printed I have to
read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our goals for this summer was to go out on a boat, 
so one fine Monday morning the girls and I went down to the 
Harbourfront.  We walked along the boardwalk admiring the
boats and ships, and looking for ducks, until I found someone
selling boat rides.  I asked him which was the cheapest one, and he
said we could all go out on the Ste Marie for $11; it was 
to be a 45 minute ride leaving at 11:15, so we signed on.  We
turned out to be the only passengers on a tour around the 
Toronto islands; we saw nature preserves and Centre Island,
swans and cygnets, and learned all about Ned Hanlan.  Delphine
won herself and Cordelia a lollipop each in a one-question trivia
contest: "What lake are we on right now?"  "Ontario Lake!"  I
had told her that very morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest adventure this summer was a surprise trip to
Saskatchewan, surprise because I had intended to go at
Christmas until I realized it would be fully twice a much
money, to the tune of $4000 instead of $2000, to go at
Christmas instead of summer.  So we decided to go in 
August instead.  I flew out there with the girls first,
and my mother's saintly friend Shirley picked
us up from the airport in Saskatoon.  Blake came a few days
later, and picked up a rental car and drove to Big River 
by himself, almost without incident!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shirley also engineered
the high point of the visit, a fishing trip in her
motor boat.  Delphine got to reel in a fish, and I also
fished for the very first time.  Blake caught the biggest
fish of the day, but we released all of them in favour of
some already-clean fish from Shirley's freezer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to stay quite busy in Saskatchewan, going out
for lunch a couple of times, driving down to PA to see an
old school friend, going to the school playground, visiting
the farmer's market, shopping in Debden, or just going to
get the mail.  The girls had a great time with my mum; she
let them watch as much TV as they wanted, eat cookies and
play with all her thousands of tchotchkes.  Blake said
that between the cookies and fishing and &lt;em&gt;Wheel of Fortune&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt; it was just like his visits to his grandparents
in Winnipeg when he was a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited my Dad in the nursing home a couple of times.
Last year, when Cordelia and I were in Sask in September, my dad
had just moved into the nursing home and we visited every day.
We chatted with him and had a nice time.  This year I literally
didn't recognize him at first: he was tucked up in a giant
bed-like wheelchair and he had lost a lot of weight.  With his
teeth out he just looked like some generic old guy, skinny and
wrinkly and not like
my dad at all.  It took a minute to recognize that nose and
those ears, things that don't change, and then I realized
that old guy was really my dad.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day we were there
he didn't open his eyes or acknowledge us at all, apart from
tapping his foot apparently in response to the songs that
the girls and I sang for him.  I was so
shook up it took me a couple of days to gather the nerve to go
again, but when I did I was sorry I had waited, because Dad
opened his eyes and looked at me and the girls and smiled at us.
But the next time we visited, again he didn't open his eyes.  All
I could do for him was ask the nurses to play music for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were in Sask the hospital called my mother to let her
know that they are discontinuing his diabetes medication because
he's not eating.  I know my poor Dad is just trying to go, and
there's no legal way we can make it easier for him.  Humanity my ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls took it all in their stride.  They asked why Grandpa
doesn't talk or open his eyes, and I said he's really old and
sick and he needs to sleep all the time.  I said he's too tired
to open his eyes or talk.  They weren't upset about it at all,
because they are still young enough that they take it in their
stride, and because neither of them really knew him when he was
lucid.  Dad got to meet Delphine when she was three, but I don't
know how much of that either of them remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother, on the other hand, is doing well by herself.  She
has friends and neighbours who help her out with things like
mowing the lawn.  The people in town — the pharmacist, 
the postmaster, the plumber (just like in a Richard Scarry book)
— know her and look out for her.
And of course she has her cats to torment her and keep her
on her toes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when the children were younger the travel itself
was the big worry, but there was hardly anything to talk about
this time; I loaded up with activity books and little 
plane-friendly toys — a magnetic dress-up doll, some brilliant
Micro Playmobil in its own little box, sticker books — and
plenty of snacks, and we managed the three hours on the plane
and two and a half hours in the car without much ado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we got home from Sask we haven't had any  grand adventures, although
we have had a steady stream of playdates and visits.  School
starts next Wednesday and Delphine is looking forward to it.
She was scared that she wouldn't like her teacher, until she
received a welcome letter from said teacher in the mail and 
now she's excited and happy.  Cordelia's school starts the
following Monday — she's doing Monday, Wednesday and Friday
this year.  I don't know how that's going to go; she has
been very clingy lately.  I expect she will howl terribly,
I will leave and she'll be fine within five minutes.  I
expect further that after a couple of weeks of school
she will no longer be so clingy.  There's nothing like
confronting your fears, even when you're two and your mother
makes you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this has been a great summer.  At the beginning I
wondered if I should have enrolled my kids in a thousand
camps and programs, like everyone else does (nevermind that
we don't have the money).  I decided I would rather not
spend my entire summer ferrying everyone around, and that
we would make our own fun, and so we did.  There was a 
little whining that there's nothing to do, that we never
go to the park, that our backyard is the worst in the world,
and that everyone else gets to go away on holiday, but for the
most part we got along with each other and found interesting
things to do both near and far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>saskatchewan</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/summervacation.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 19:28:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Big Birthday Excitement</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my thirty-third birthday.  Thirty-three
isn't a very interesting number, but it's one of the 
ones you have to get through on the way to ooooold.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake's first present to me was to tell the girls
not to fight on my birthday.  If you know any 
two- and five-year-old sisters you will know how
long that lasted, but they did try.  For at least
an hour.  The next nice thing was that Blake let
me languish in bed while he went downstairs with
the girls and made tea and toast for me.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After
breakfast we opened presents: Delphine got me a
strand of blue silk flowers and beads on a wire,
to decorate things with.  Cordelia got me a wire
and bead ladybug (and then broke it, but not 
fatally), and Blake got me a Moleskine notebook
for Writing Things Down In.  I loved everything.
Blake thought I might not like the girls' things
because of their tchotchke-like nature, but it's
surprising how much I completely adore them just
because my girlies picked them out.  I put the
blue flower garland on the banister and I put the
ladybug... well, I put it up high.  Hopefully I 
can put it somewhere else soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite it being my birthday we still had a million
errands to run (partly because we're going to 
Sask next week) but I had a nice time.  I spent
far too much money on clothes for Delphine (but
they were on sale!  And so cute!) and far too much
money on a present for my cousin.  We met up with
our friends Tanya and Ursa and continued
the tradition started last year of 
decorating cupcakes (which is to say,
burying them in as many sprinkles as they will hold).
Tanya and I got some very rare talking-together-like-grownups
time while the little ones slept and the five-year-olds
played with Playmobil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Tanya and Ursa left, Blake came home with 
KFC (my annual treat) and more presents!  A
beautiful &lt;a href="http://www.basil.nl/assortiment_detail.asp?titel_var=2&amp;amp;lang=3&amp;amp;id=1864"&gt;Basil pannier&lt;/a&gt; and the Torchwood
season one DVD!  He tried to get the latter 
signed, but I'm glad he didn't manage it
 because I would have
died of jealousy if he had met John Barrowman 
without me.  Well, maybe not died, quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then more company; Kat came over and watched
our TV while the children were in bed, and we
went for a walk and had coffee.  We came home,
watched the first episode of Torchwood (I think
we may have converted Kat) and went to bed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All
in all, a super birthday, but my first full day
of being thirty-three was fabulous too.  Kat 
stayed over and we went to yoga together in the
morning.  Yoga was fun, as usual, but my hamstrings
are astonishingly tight and there were some postures
I couldn't even consider.  As usual, though, yoga
threw me some ego-boosting soft pitches:  I can balance!
I can ... well, mainly  I can balance! But there's a
lot of that in yoga!  The thing I like about yoga is 
that you might try a posture one minute that seems
completely impossible — you look at the person next to you
and wonder if perhaps there is some optical illusion
involved — but the very next posture is something you can
not only do, but do the "if you want a little more challenge"
variation!  Yoga wants you to feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the best thing of all was that today Delphine
learned how to ride a bike!  She went off with Blake
to practice riding in the school ground, and when they
got back she was riding all by herself.  I could
hardly believe my eyes!  This summer has been
great for her; she learned to climb a tree, she is
reading (not entire books but words and phrases), and
now riding a bike.  Wow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>birthday</category><category>delphine</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/birthday33.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:06:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Graduation Videos</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/gradvids.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Here is Cordelia watching, bemused, as everyone else participates
in "Sticky Bubblegum":
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;
  &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/lNoEYU5GL4M"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/lNoEYU5GL4M" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And here is Delphine and her class performing a chant about
recycling:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;
  &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/qdtJ7ueQ95c"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/qdtJ7ueQ95c" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>video</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/gradvids.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:25:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More pictures.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/jun12.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently installed a new version of Sketches, and today Delphine
asked if we could draw another picture.  So we did.  Then we emailed
it to Amy, and I got Delphine to tell me what letters to write for her
sentence.  (I also told her about putting a space between each word,
which is something that Ms. Hollister said that we could tell her
about if we wanted.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sentence was “Ths is a heis on a hil wth to bsis.”, which I’m sure
you can all read as “This is a house on a hill with two bushes.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/delphine/2008-06-12/Sketches.jpg"&gt;&lt;br clear="all"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>images</category><category>itouch</category><category>pictures</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/jun12.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 02:40:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More pictures.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/mar16.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since Delphine has wanted to play on my little
computer at bedtime.  We’ve been too busy reading old, old books about
animals of various kinds.  Yesterday, we both seemed to realize this,
and decided that tonight we would play on the little computer instead
of reading books.  I’m sure Delphine was thinking something more along
the lines of “We’ll play on the little computer, and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; read
books”, but that was never going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commentary on this is “It’s a head.  On a slide.  With a hat,
and the sun.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/delphine/2008-03-16/Sketches.jpg"&gt;&lt;br clear="all"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>images</category><category>itouch</category><category>pictures</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/pictures/mar16.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 00:54:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>