<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about deploy)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/deploy.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Pushing code to a remote server the volo way.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/volodeploy/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/bwinton/australis-customization/"&gt;side-project&lt;/a&gt; I’m working
on is coming along nicely, and so I figured it was time to let other people
see it.  Now, I could just have everyone huddle around my screen, but since
many of the people who would be interested aren’t in the same city (or even
same timezone) as I am, that wouldn’t work out so well.  We tried screen-
sharing, but a lot of what’s being worked on is animation, and the frame-rates
of the screen-sharing application we were using weren’t up to the task.  To
get around that, I could have recorded a video, but since a lot of the value
of a prototype like this is being able to play around with it, that’s also not
a great solution.  So, obviously, the best thing to do would be to put it on a
publicly available server, and let people run it in their own web browser,
whenever they wanted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m running a server or two that I could put it up on, but since the
project is related to Mozilla, and since Mozilla offers some personal webspace
on &lt;a href="http://people.mozilla.org/"&gt;one of their servers&lt;/a&gt;, I figured I might as
well put it up &lt;a href="https://people.mozilla.com/~bwinton/australis/customization/mac/?scroll"&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to make it easy for me to remember to build and upload the code (and to
prevent me from trying to figure out all the correct options to rsync every
time I wanted to upload the code), I took a couple of minutes to &lt;a href="https://github.com/bwinton/australis-customization/blob/master/australis/customization/mac/volofile#L23"&gt;add a
command&lt;/a&gt; to my volofile, which lets me merely type &lt;code&gt;volo deploy&lt;/code&gt;, and have it
optimize the code, and copy only the changed files to the remote server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>deploy</category><category>mozilla</category><category>remote</category><category>rsync</category><category>server</category><category>volo</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/volodeploy/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 18:04:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>