<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (development)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/development.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:56:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Cordelia is...</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;...independent!  We had Cordelia's parent-teacher "chat" today,
with her nursery school teachers.  I love talking about my 
children, so I was very excited to be there, and of course Blake
doesn't have a job so he came along 'coz he doesn't have anything
else to do.  Just kidding; he had taken the morning off to
come anyway, before the company folded (or whatever it's in
the process of doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simone and Sameera were very happy to talk about Cordelia too.
Apparently she's a delight at school.  (I bet they say that
to all the parents.)  She's very independent; she puts on
her own outside clothes and clears up after snack by
herself.  This is a revelation to me because like idiots 
we're still helping her on with her snowsuit and boots,
and begging her to take just one thing into the kitchen
after meals.  Suckers, we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her favourite things are sensory activities:
playdough, cornstarch, sand.  Anything messy.
She's still focused to the point of being oblivious to
what's going on around her (she gets that from Blake),
and she's happy playing by herself, to the point that
her teachers are actually engineering situations to
force her into talking and playing with other kids.  They
are going to hook me up with some good playdate matches
for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's their only concern for kindergarten, that she
won't be able to make connections with other kids and
with the teacher.  Academically, in terms of colours,
shapes, letters and numbers, she's just fine!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><category>school</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 13:35:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>P-t-e-r-a-n-o-d-o-n spells Pteranodon!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/earlyreading.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The other day Delphine peered intently at the world map
we got for my birthday for a while, and then announced
"I read San!  S-a-n is San!"  That's the first word she
has read apart from her name and a few words that she'd
memorized like "o-f-f off" and "n-o no".  And it's in
Spanish!  She's bilingual!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then later she read the first syllable of "Doritos", which
is now that I think about it, faux-Spanish.  I'm going to
assume that's a coincience until I get more data.  Anyway
the point is she's almost reading!  Hooray!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>development</category><category>reading</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/earlyreading.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 19:21:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordelia Is Two!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia turned two on Thursday, which was kind of sucky for
her because it was her fourth day of nursery school and so she's
still suffering from lots of separation anxiety.  I felt like
a monster leaving her crying and miserable in the arms of
Lakeisha the teacher on her birthday, but when I waved at her
through the window on the way out she was already smiling a
little bit.  They made up for it by giving her cake because 
it just happened to be the day for their September birthday
celebration.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Altogether, counting the nursery school party, Cordelia had
four birthday parties; one last weekend at Baba and Zaida's
with a chocolate cake and presents, one on Thursday night
at home with a plain cake with pink icing and more presents 
— we got her one of those rugs with roads and railways
and stuff printed on it (Delphine's idea), and &lt;em&gt;Hop on 
Pop&lt;/em&gt; — and yet another this weekend when we 
made a dinosaur-shaped cake just for the fun of it.  We
like cake, what can I say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nursery school&lt;/strong&gt; is going well.  I signed 
her up not to give myself a break — I think it's
actually created more work for me — but because I thought
it was time she started to have a life of her own, to
gain some independence away from me, and to be exposed
to all the rich and interesting things they offer at 
nursery school.  It seems to be a really good facility;
they always have lots of interesting activities set
up when we get there in the morning, the teachers are
lovely, they have a real music teacher with a guitar
in every other week, and every week they take a picture
of your child and save it in a portfolio that you get
to keep at the end of the year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only catch is that the school is about one and a
half kilometers from home, around a fifteen minute
walk.  I originally thought it was going to be a longer walk than
that, before I actually tried it, so I was quite pleased.
On Thursday I strapped on my running shoes and put the
girls in the expensive but very cool jogging stroller /
bike trailer and ran up there, which of course also 
took about fifteen minutes because I am that slow and
also running with a stroller sucks.  But it's better 
than running at 7:30 at night when all I want to do is
collapse on the couch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia can &lt;strong&gt;count to twenty&lt;/strong&gt;, which
is kind of odd for a two-year-old.  She loves to count,
but she's not really counting &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;.  I think 
she knows about counting in some sense; she knows you
do it when you have a lot of something, and that you 
count for a while and then stop and the number you stop
at means something, but she really doesn't map the 
actual number of things to the words she's saying. She
loves to over-count and usually ends up with "seven" 
of whatever it is.  Also when people ask her how old
she is she says "three!"  She just likes numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Incidentally, Delphine's friend Ursa also loved 
counting and numbers, to the extent that she still
calls both letters and numbers "numbers". This is
interesting because Delphine used to call numbers
"letters".  Shall we typecast them as the Wordy One
and the Mathy One already?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;talks in full sentences&lt;/strong&gt;, 
and she has reached
that age when she comes out with syntactically perfect
sentences which leave me speechless.   "Help me put
 my sweater on!"  I hear it and it's a perfect sentence,
and then I realize it came from my tiny baby!
 She doesn't do full sentences all the 
time, though. Mostly she's still trying to cobble together
communication with the few words and bits of grammar she knows,
backed up with pointing and when all else fails, shouting
really loud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Communicating is complicated by the fact that she 
&lt;strong&gt;doesn't
know her colours&lt;/strong&gt; yet; when Delphine was this age at
least we could figure out what she wanted by saying, "What 
colour is it?"  Cordelia, for whatever reason, can't get
her colours straight.  For a couple of weeks everything
was blue ("bah-loo!") and now things seem to be mostly
red.  If you drill her you can get her to get a colour
right for a few minutes but then if you go back to it
later, she goes back to guessing.  I find this rather
perplexing; she doesn't seem to have trouble learning the
words for anything else.  Either she can't map the colours
to the names, or she can't distinguish the colours for
some reason.  Anyway, you aren't really expected to know
your colours until you're three or even four, so maybe 
there is some mental or visual development yet to come
which will resolve this.  In the meantime all the grandparents
have made it their mission to help her learn colours.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia &lt;strong&gt;sleeps&lt;/strong&gt; from about six thirty
until six thirty or seven in the morning.  Well, I put
her to bed at six thirty; usually she stays awake talking
and singing to herself until seven.  She also naps from
one until two or two thirty.  (I got all my sleep advice 
from &lt;em&gt;Healthy Sleep Habits, Happy Child&lt;/em&gt; by
Marc Weissbluth, so if you want a narcoleptic child and
a rich adult-only evening life you should read it too.)
She scared me on Friday by not napping at all; I wondered
if she had decided that since now she's two she doesn't
need a nap.  But then she napped yesterday and today, so
I think I still have a napper.  It's nice because she
naps while Delphine is in kindergarten, so I get some time
to get stuff done in the afternoons.  If I am not too tired
to think; afternoon is not my brightest time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia has &lt;strong&gt;peed in the potty&lt;/strong&gt; exactly twice, both times
under the tutelage of Baba.  I suppose she is more or less
ready to be properly potty-trained, which is exciting in
the sense of no more diapers, but I am not looking forward
to the process, the constant trips to the potty and 
interrogation regarding her need for the same.  "Do you have
to go pee?  Do you have to poo?  Do you want to sit on the
potty?"  However, it has to happen sometime!  The nursery
school teachers say they are happy to help, so maybe I
will rope them in and see if we can get it over with.
That would be awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tomorrow is Monday, and October, and I have a million
things to do so I had best get to bed so I am not tired
and grumpy all day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>birthday</category><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/two.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordelia is Fifteen Months Old</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/fifteenmonths.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia is my little monkey.  She is fearless and ambitious —
this morning she was hauling the cat carrier around the house,
dragging it behind her and bashing into every damn thing.  She
dragged it into the kitchen and before I could turn around she had
climbed on it and was messing around on the counter.  She
does appalling things like that every day; I certainly didn't
get any experience with this kind of behaviour from Delphine.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last time I posted about Cordelia, she had just started
walking.  Well, she's been walking for four months now and
she's pretty darn good at it.  Mostly.  The other day I put
her down in  the front yard and she took off like a flash down
the path; there's a little step right before the path meets
the sidewalk, and she stepped down it.  Unfortunately the
step is about four inches, and Cordelia's leg is also about
four inches, and so after her foot made contact with the
ground, her right hand did, then her left, and then... her
head. She hardly cried at all, but I had to pick some grit
out of her, and now she's walking around with a gnarly big
scab on her forehead.  She doesn't care; it makes her
look fierce.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She says a few words now: cat, up, milk, ball, book, 
Mimi (which applies to all cats), Daddy, Mummy, duck, 
and of course, "no", with a
little head shake.
She always says "no" when you ask her a question;
I think she just likes shaking her head.  She had her
eye on my tea — the child is always thirsty — and asked 
for it, but then answered her own question by shaking
her head sadly: "no".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Fifteen months is the age Delphine was when we started
putting her down to sleep alone; Cordelia has been sleeping
alone for almost a year.  She sleeps from six or six-thirty
until six in the morning, and she goes down without a
fight.  Last night I was nursing her to sleep and she 
stopped nursing and looked around.  I issued my usual
ultimatum: "Boobie or bed!"  Her typical response is
to latch right back on in a hurry, but last night she
said "Bed!", and sat up to be put in the crib.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She's down to one nap a day, mostly — she just suddenly
stopped needing a morning nap one day.  The catch is
that when she's sick she still needs two naps some days,
and I'm never sure whether any given day will be a one-napper or
a two-napper.  Makes planning ahead hard.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Being in the house with Cordelia is also really hard; if I
want to go upstairs or to the basement, I have to pick her
up; I can't work in the basement with her because there
are too many hazards: cat litter, stairs, unexpected pointy
things.  Upstairs we don't have a baby gate for stairs, so 
I have to pick a room to work in, shut the door, and stay
there.  So mostly we stay on the main floor, which makes
unpacking and doing laundry and any other multifloor
pursuit very difficult.  I do miss having everything on the
same floor, but I have to remind myself that one day
Cordelia will be able to handle stairs and being by herself,
so I will be able to get stuff done much easier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And in the meantime, she makes me laugh every single
day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>development</category><category>house</category><category>sleep</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/fifteenmonths.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>