<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (diversions)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/diversions.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Urbane and Mellow</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/sounds.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
One of the things -- one of the many things -- I love about
this condo is that it's right on a major street, so when
I open the windows the sounds of the city come into my 
living room.  Traffic, sirens, the "beep, beep, beep" of
a truck backing up, people shouting to their friends...
crazy people yelling, the odd car crash.  To most people,
I guess, this doesn't sound so hot, but I like the
feeling of being in the middle of something without
having to actually leave the house.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Today a lone saxophonist plays on the corner outside
Starbucks, adding an urbane, mellow touch to the
sunny afternoon soundscape.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/sounds.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Week At The Cottage</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/cottage.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
We just got home from a week at the cottage; at &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;
cottage, I should say, a place we (or more accurately, Blake's
parents) rented for a week up on Georgian Bay.  The cottage
was right on the beach, and we spent a restful week playing
in the water, sitting on the beach, eating corn and ice
cream and making sand castles.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The first day we were there Cordelia started standing on
her own, and she spent the rest of the week practicing;
she can stay up for about twenty seconds before she plops
down onto her bottom.  As soon as we got home we set her
up with Delphine's old push cart thing, and she loves to
zoom around with it (although she can't steer yet —
she goes in a straight line until she runs into something).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine spent the week basking in all the attention
from her Baba and Zaida, and conquering her fear of
the water.  She's scared of pretty much everything
these days, so it was great for her to have an 
opportunity to confront something scary with the
support of such tireless cheerleaders.  And she
did great — by the end of the week she was 
happily walking into the lake by herself, jumping
over waves and playing in the water.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Blake and I had a nice week too, as you can imagine 
with two extra sets of hands around to help look after
the girls.  We both got lots of reading done, and 
we fit in a romantic walk on the beach and a nice
dinner as well.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine also went through a lot of books; I packed
a couple of Pooh books, a Stella and Sam book and
another library book with a watery theme.  Unfortunately
the cottage we rented came ready-stocked with some
crappy kids books which, of course, Delphine loved.
(I have heard from a couple of sources that children
will naturally gravitate towards quality books,
but Delphine certainly doesn't; some of her favourite
books are garbage and I have to "lose" them because
I can't bear to read them any more.)  Among a 
whole selection of
lousy books (and a couple of good ones; a Robert
Munsch and some Arthur books) at the cottage 
were picture-book-length adaptations
of &lt;em&gt;Disney's Aladdin&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Disney's The Little
Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Disney's The Jungle Book&lt;/em&gt;.
(Spotting a trend here?)  You can't really fit an
hour and a half of movie into thirty paragraphs, so
there was a lot of "Suddenly!" and sentences like
"Aladdin tricked
the genie into taking them out of the cave on a 
magic carpet," or "It took a lot of tricks for Baloo
and Bagheera to free Mowgli from the monkeys!"  
I don't remember the movies, but something
tells me that's at least fifteen minutes of film
and no small amount of characterisation and action
squeezed into one lousy little sentence. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine's favourite of those three was Aladdin.
Her favourite character was the genie, and her 
favourite line, which she repeated all
week, was "Proceed!  Touch nothing but the lamp!'  
which is a pretty great sentence when uttered
completely out of any context in a &lt;em&gt;very gruff&lt;/em&gt;
voice by a three-foot-tall girl.  "&lt;em&gt;Proceed!
Touch nuffing but da lamp!&lt;/em&gt;"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The girls each had their own bedroom at the cottage,
and the result of that was that they both slept
better; Cordelia was sleeping until 6:30 instead
of 5:30, and Delphine started sleeping until after
seven!  I am pretty excited about buying a house
now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All in all, the week at the cottage was a success 
— we expect we will do it again next year,
even Blake who hates the great outdoors.  We will
probably try and get a nicer cottage next year; this
one was kind of, um, retro.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/cottage.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 01:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coppa Del Mundo</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/worldcup.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Now that both England and Brazil are out of the World Cup
finals I'm having a hard time getting excited about the
last few games.  At least Italy are in; they are always
a useful second backup after Brazil, but while I am glad
to see them play, I don't really care all that much whether
they win or lose.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, it's hard watching football around here.  Watching a 
football match properly calls for a degree of attention
that is impossible while you are making sure that Child 2
isn't choking on some abandoned crayon, and at the same
time reading Pooh (with all the right voices) to Child 1.
So mostly it's been on as background noise for the last 
month, a screen saver for the television.  It's the most
TV Delphine has ever watched, I think.  We talk
about where the players come from, and what their names
are.  (Delphine now knows that Germany is a country.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I will be sorry when it's all over; I have tried being
interested in league football, but I just don't care,
and even the Euro Cup (or whatever it's called) isn't
all that interesting.  You have to have the little 
African countries to root for, and the wonderful 
South Americans.  So I'll put my fan hat away until 
2010, when Delphine will be seven and Cordelia
will be three and a half -- older than Delphine is
now.  (Last World Cup we had no children at all!)  And
maybe next time England will win...
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/worldcup.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2006 17:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Huh?</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/huh.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Okay, I am deleting this whole post on the grounds that it makes
me look stupid, and it's my website, I can feign intelligence
if I want to.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Look away, look away.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/huh.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2006 18:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Stuff I Bought</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodstuff.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
You know how all makeup claims it's the best thing since they
invented makeup, and it will change your life?  Well, Cover Girl 
LashExact won't change your life, but it does do what it claims, which
is not clump.  As far as I can tell the goo in the bottle is
the same as ever, but the wand is new technology; it's not
regular bristles like a normal mascara brush, but little plastic
bristles very evenly spaced.  It works a dream.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The next thing I like is something my mother sent us, a set of
three CDs called &lt;a href="http://www.cduniverse.com/productinfo.asp?pid=6717773&amp;amp;style=music&amp;amp;cart=312913608&amp;amp;BAB=E"&gt;100 Silly Songs&lt;/a&gt;. 
It has every kid's song you have ever heard, plus a few
that haven't been heard for decades because they're quite
politically incorrect, like "The King of the Cannibal
Islands", or "I Wish I Were A Little Bar of Soap".  They're 
all nicely arranged and well-sung, with
complete verses.  It's almost like a reference CD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The last thing I have bought that I like is my new
&lt;a href="http://www.myfullerbrush.com/tidy.htm"&gt;crumb sweeper&lt;/a&gt;.
I didn't get that brand -- mine is much cuter -- but the idea
is the same.  It works really well at picking up the crumbs
off the tablecloth after Delphine the barbarian has
eaten -- I just, swoosh, sweep it across the table and the
crumbs are gone as if by magic.  
(I use a tablecloth because our table is wood and I
want to keep it nice until the children have manners and are
less prone to drumming on the table with their forks and
such.)  I am looking forward to the post-croissant cleanup on
Sunday.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodstuff.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 22:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Day</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodday.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Delphine and I had a good day yesterday.   It was sunny and warm, the
first real spring day of the year.  In the morning we went down to the
office to fix something, and then picked up some groceries on the way
home.  Lunch was ham sandwiches and coleslaw (Delphine picked out and ate
the ham and left the bread, so I finished hers) and then we had a nap
together on the couch, which might be my very favourite thing to do
in the whole world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After the nap we collected ourself and went out for a walk, up to
the green grocer to get some lettuce for salad.  Because it was so
mild out we went at Delphine's pace instead of mine, so we climbed the
stairs at Starbucks, touched the flowers at the flower shop, walked
on the snow bank at Rogers, climbed the stairs at the bank about twenty 
times, and tried to get money out of the machine (I said she would have to
get a card, and a bank account, and a job first).  Then she was tired of
walking so I picked her up for the rest of the walk to the store.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
At the green grocer she learned about mushrooms (she has learned to say
"what's that?" instead of "ga-duh?") and green beans ("noodle?"), and then
we walked back.  She decided to take a detour at the LCBO because they
have lots of good snow to walk on, and that took us to the school.
That was an excellent choice, because we were able to visit with the
kids and ladies at daycare, and then play in the extensive and deep
puddles in the school ground.  I had to drag her away from there after
at least half an hour of splashing, and by the time we got home our
trip to the green grocer had taken a couple of hours.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I cannot say enough about how much I enjoy her company these days.  I'm
so happy to have a verbal little kid instead of a baby, and I am 
astonished at how much personality she has, which apparently sprung
forth fully-formed.  I am finally starting to feel like I, as the 
stay-at-home parent, have the better side of the deal.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodday.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 03:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books Good</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/booksgood.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
In the past, as you have been unfortunate enough to witness, 
I have been miserable about my life, feeling like it's not going
anywhere or I'm not doing good enough or I'm not achieving anything or
whatever.  Recently, however, that feeling has subsided.  I'm feeling
mellow, like whatever needs doing will get done, and I'll be able to
deal with stuff as it comes up, and I'm not a big loser.  It's
refreshing!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To what do I attribute this change?  If only I knew.  But I'm working on
a theory that it has something to do with all the 
&lt;a href="http://www.latte.ca/~arbrown/reading.html"&gt;books&lt;/a&gt; 
I've been reading lately,
really good books about normal people living their normal lives.  Like
&lt;em&gt;The Curious Incident of the Dog in the Night-time&lt;/em&gt; and 
&lt;em&gt;Captain Corelli's Mandolin&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Clare Callan&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;The Brothers K&lt;/em&gt;.  I don't have a lot more to this theory,
other than that maybe reading all these books has made me pull my 
head out
of my own ass and think about other people instead of just sitting around
worrying about my own "problems".  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I also haven't read any parenting advice books lately, I bet that helps.
There's nothing that makes you think your life is so significant than
reading a book all about what's wrong with it and what you have to do to
make it better.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="30%"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By the way, the reason for all these books is that I finally got off my
ass (actually got &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; my ass) and figured out how to use the 
Toronto Public Library inter-library loan system on the Internet.  Now
I barely have to do more than think "Huh, I'd like to read that book", and
I get a call from a nice recorded lady telling me that the book is 
waiting for me at my local branch.  It's amazing, except that
&lt;em&gt;About a Boy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Due Preparations
for the Plague&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Diary of Samuel Pepys&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A Fine
Balance&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; arrived
at the same time, just after I had taken out &lt;em&gt;The Brothers K&lt;/em&gt;.
That's almost 3500 pages of book.  Good thing I also know how to renew over
the Internet.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/booksgood.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 00:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Black Eyed Peas</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/040201.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.blackeyedpeas.com/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.latte.ca/camera/weblog/ElephunkSmall.png" align="right"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Can I just say I love where music is going now?  We got the
Black Eyed Peas CD and it's all over the place, it's funk,
it's hip-hop, it's metal, it's pop.  And it's pretty much all
good.  I'm so glad to get some new music in the house, I was 
feeling pathetic and unhip listening to classical radio 
all day.  (Although for all I know, Black Eyed Peas are
pathetic and unhip; that's how pathetic and unhip I am.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I'm feeling pleased with myself because I looked up
The Apl Song and figured out that the stuff which isn't in
English is Tagalog.  I guess if I were smarter I would have
listened to the English lyrics and caught the reference to
the Phillipines, but hey, with Google you don't need to be
smart.  Tagalog sounds cool, it's all bubbly and flowy.  I'd
like to speak it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>diversions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/040201.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>