<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (drum_and_bass)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/drum_and_bass.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dieselboy - The Human Resource</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/reviews/dieselboy.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty sweet.  They were described to me as "slightly-harder drum
and bass", which worried me a little, since I didn't know if I would
be up for something heavy, but either it was only slightly-harder, or
I don't know how hard regular drum and bass is, or I ended up being in
a heavier mood than I thought I was, because I thoroughly enjoyed the
album.  It sort of drifted into the background, which is exactly what
I'm hoping for when I listen to music at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not entirely sure what else to say here.  I suppose I could add
that they didn't seem as minimal as the Plastikman/FUSE albums I've
got, and they were a lot less sample-heavy than Mushroom Jazz by Mark
Farina, but I don't think that really tells you much about the music
itself.  Hopefully, with more exposure to some quality drum and bass,
I'll be able to give more informed opinions, but for now, I guess this
will have to be my baseline for future reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, one more thing, the next few reviews might run a little late,
because even though I've listened to the music, I only have a couple
of hundred words written about each of them, and I'm guessing that
it'll take some re-listening to think of more things to say.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>drum_and_bass</category><category>from_jon</category><category>music</category><category>new_music</category><category>review</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/reviews/dieselboy.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 19:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>