<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about email)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/email.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Adventures in Mail Servers (or, how I wasted my Sunday afternoon)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/configuringservers/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think what I want is pretty simple, or at least, reasonably common.
I’m just looking for a couple of programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SMTP server which will accept mail for the accounts at latte.ca, and deliver
it to a Maildir of my choosing, and let me send mail through it if, and only if,
I’ve logged in with the password to that account.  (Being able to define a few
aliases would also be nice.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And an IMAP server which will expose the previously-mentioned Maildir, after
I’ve logged in with the password to that account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, every time I try to set that up, something completely falls over for no
particularly understandable reason, and I end up wasting an afternoon (or more)
of my life.  I had hoped this time would be different, since I decided not to
install and configure everything myself, but instead bought a copy of OS X Lion
Server which was supposed to do all the hard work for me.  I’m not going to
enumerate all the problems I ran into, but I will say that I still haven’t
managed to get there.  I’m just done for tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, if anyone reading this has a working setup that meets the requirements
(and the added requirement of needing to use Dovecot and Postfix, since those
are what’s installed), I would love to get a copy of their config files.  And in
the meantime, I might seriously look into getting a refund for Lion Server,
given how badly it’s failed me.  :P&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dovecot</category><category>email</category><category>fml</category><category>osx</category><category>postbox</category><category>server</category><category>wtf</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/configuringservers/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 01:52:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>