<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (employment)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/employment.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:56:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A long time ago, on a computer far far away…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, I started contributing to Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>anniversary</category><category>employment</category><category>mozilla</category><category>thunderbird</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/sixyears.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some VSS to Subversion notes.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newtools.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;From various places around the net.  (Hint: Google "vss to subversion".)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tortoisesvn.sourceforge.net/docs/release/TortoiseSVN_en/ch05s18.html"&gt;Lock-modify-unlock for Svn.&lt;/a&gt;  Not that that's what I think we should 
    bd doing, but if I've got to sell it, and that's a sticking point, at least
    I have an answer now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subversion is said to be much faster.  "Our CC.NET build went from 3
    minutes to 35 seconds for whole tree!!!!"  I haven't looked up how much of
    our nightly build time is spent getting files from VSS, but I seem to
    remember it's not inconsiderable, and that step has been failing more often 
    recently, so if we can make it both faster and more reliable, that'll be a 
    good selling point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ankhsvn.tigris.org/"&gt;Ankhsvn&lt;/a&gt; (Wow, what a horrible
    front page!  If I were &lt;a href="http://pyre.third-bit.com/blog/"&gt;Greg
    Wilson&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://pyre.third-bit.com/blog/archives/645.html"&gt;grading them on
    it&lt;/a&gt;, they'ld get a 51%.  I mean, it's there, so I'm not going to fail
    you, but for the love of Pete, hire a graphic designer, or look at the other 
    two links in this entry, or something.  Please.) or &lt;a href="http://www.pushok.com/soft_svn.php"&gt;PushOK&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.visualsvn.com/"&gt;VisualSVN&lt;/a&gt; for Visual Studio 
    integration, but everyone seems to use &lt;a href="http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/"&gt;TortoiseSvn&lt;/a&gt;.  I
    wonder if there's something similar for OSX?  Fortunately, Eclipse 
    integration is good enough that I don't really mind falling back to the 
    command line client when I have to, but still.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="http://codecorner.tigernews.co.uk/codecorner/presentations/ddd2-subversion.zip"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; on "Replacing SourceSafe with SubVersion".&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pumacode.org/projects/vss2svn"&gt;A Perl script&lt;/a&gt; 
    (&lt;i&gt;shudder&lt;/i&gt;) to migrate your VSS repository to svn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And there you go.  Management has been feeling the pain recently, and the Server 
Team Lead seems onboard with the idea, so we might actually make the change.  
Exciting times.
</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newtools.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The times, they are a' changin...</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/changes.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;So my role at the company is changing slightly.  Due to a manpower
shortage, I'll be back doing some server development.  Fortunately, I
sort of know my way around the modules this time, and so I don't
expect many surprises to crop up.  So, to make my life both simpler
and more difficult at the same time, I've decided to try out a new
IDE.  That's right, instead of using IDEA, I'll be giving Eclipse a
trial run.  It hasn't been too bad so far, but I'm still kind of
getting it set up to do the things I need it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My three main motivations for using Eclipse on this project are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I need to look at C++ code at the same time as Java code, since
      that's the only documentation we have for this project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The savings of an IDEA license are not inconsiderable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The co-worker who is working on it with me prefers Eclipse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Are they great reasons to switch?  Maybe, maybe not, but they're good
enough reasons to give it a try for a while.  It helps that I have
been using an older version of Eclipse for my Python development, so
I'm a little familiar with it.</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/changes.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2005 20:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Looking for work?</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/hiring.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;While I'm here posting up a storm, I should mention that &lt;a href="http://www.phantomfiber.com"&gt;my company&lt;/a&gt; could really use
some good Java and C++ people, hopefully senior enough to be team
leads on some upcoming projects, but I hear that we could use people
of any and all skill levels.  Well, perhaps not the most junior,
unless they're really smart, and self-starters.  If you are looking
for a job, or know anyone who is, please &lt;a href="http://www.phantomfiber.com/careers.htm"&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you wanted to know what it was like working here, feel free
to &lt;a href="mailto:blake@phantomfiber.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/hiring.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2005 13:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Busy busy busy.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/busy.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>So &lt;a href="http://www.phantomfiber.com/"&gt;my company&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.phantomfiber.com/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.latte.ca/camera/weblog/PhantomP.png" align="right"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on the virge of getting a bunch of new work,
which means that I might be back on client development.  But not
quite yet, since there is a bunch of framework-ish stuff that I
can do before that.  A couple of new games, with the necessary
changes to the base stuff to support them in as simple a way as
possible.  But before any of that, I get to make our demo project
compile.  That was a bigger pain than I thought it would be,
since we renamed it from "PhantomGaming" to "PgCasino",
necessating wide-sweeping changes in many source files, as well
as different settings in the project files.  But it compiles now,
so in theory, on Monday, I can start implementing the new games.
Should be fun.</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/busy.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2003 22:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tool of The Man.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/tooloftheman.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I notice that &lt;a href="http://crazedmonkey.com/blog/2003/01/22#w0096"&gt;Ian
Stevens&lt;/a&gt; mentioned an application that the company he works at
recently released.&lt;br&gt;Damn, what a sell-out!  I can't wait to
see what his next announcement will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Disclaimer: I work with Ian, and he knows that I don't
actually think he's a sell-out.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/tooloftheman.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2003 20:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Released!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/released.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="http://www.phantomfiber.com"&gt;the company I work
for&lt;/a&gt; has just released our &lt;a href="http://www.covers.com/covers/mobile/mobile.asp"&gt;first
product&lt;/a&gt;.  It took a lot of time and effort to get there, but
I think we did something good.  The main part I've been working
on these past few weeks was the "synchronized (offline) mode!"
part.  There are a lot of challenges to writing a Conduit for the
Palm Desktop, some of which come from our framework.  It was
really designed to be used in an application, with Models, and
Views, and asynchronous network calls.  I'm trying to use it in a
dll with no UI, no application, and synchronous messages.  It's a
bit of a mis-fit, but it mostly works.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>employment</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/released.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2003 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>