<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (everythingelse)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/everythingelse.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why?</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/why.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Why is it that we have three thousand different pens and pencils
of varying styles and manufacturers in this house, but only two
good ones?  One of which is at all times attached to
last week's cryptic crossword?
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/why.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Pictures Up</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/newpics2.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>We are in this weird state in packing and moving where everything
we can do a week in advance has been done, so today is kind of a 
quiet day.  That means I have had a chance to sit down and post the
two or three months worth of &lt;a href="http://www.latte.ca/pics/"&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt;
 that I was behind.</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/newpics2.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Calamity Jane</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/calamityjane.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
(Michelle, you should maybe skip this post in light of our conversation
re: passing out during an episode of ER.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday, as I was shuffling, shoeless about the house (as usual) I stabbed
my foot on a splinter.  Crap, I thought, that hurts; but I was in the middle
of preparing supper for the girls so I carried on, and in a lull in the
cooking I got my tweezers and tried to pull the splinter out so I
could get on with my evening.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The splinter didn't come out; I couldn't get a good grip on it with
my shiny red Tweezerman slanted tweezers while I was hopping around
on one foot, so I brought a dining room chair into the kitchen 
(where the light is best) and sat down.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once, twice, three times I pulled and somehow always lost my grip on
the splinter before I got it out.  Finally I really dug those pointy
Tweezerman corners into my foot, pinched the splinter as tight as I
could and pulled hard.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To my horror what I had thought was a little sliver
turned out to be an inch-long spear of hardwood floor.  I immediately 
started 
bleeding all over the floor, great big bright red drops, so I grabbed 
a tea towel off the stove
(there's a good reason to make sure you get a fresh tea towel out
every day; if you injure yourself at least you know there's at most
a day worth of crap on the first towel that comes to hand) and applied
pressure with one hand while calling for backup with the
other.  Fortunately Zaida was only a couple of minutes away so 
he came right over to help with the girls' supper while I bandaged
myself up and cleaned the kitchen floor.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That was yesterday.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last Tuesday, I woke up in the middle of the night with the most
excruciating pain I had ever had (although bear in mind I didn't
go through labour, so this could be nothing compared to that).
It felt like someone was punching me all over my chest and back.  It
went on for ten or fifteen minutes and was gone as soon as it had
come.  It came again on Thursday morning (there's just something
especially cool about lying on the floor in agony while your three-year-old
tries to figure out what to do with herself -- Mummies aren't supposed
to get sick!) so on Friday I went to the doctor.  She thinks I
might have gallstones, so I am getting an ultrasound this Friday to
check it out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
While I was at the doctor she informed me that those red bumps on my
belly which I thought were maybe bites or something are actually
shingles,
for which she gave me a prescription for a week's worth of blue
horse pills, anti-virals, and an exhortation to rest.  (I laughed,
and offered to let her come over and look after Cordelia and pack
while I rested.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So to recap: gallstones, shingles, and a bloody great hole in the
bottom of my foot.  It made yesterday's application for life insurance
a barrel of fun, for sure.  Well, Blake laughed a lot anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/calamityjane.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 15:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Talk About Your Holy Wars</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/holy.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
In the toddler room at Delphine's daycare there is a Gabriel, 
a Michael, a Heaven... and a Darwin.  There must be some
almighty fights in there.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/holy.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 16:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>And what else?</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/allergies.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have allergies, killer ragweed allergies.  I never used to be
allergic to anything until a couple of years ago.  I think I will
blame the children.  I can blame Cordelia, this year, for preventing
me from taking anything; we are still nursing and there isn't much
you're allowed to take.  So I walk around with a head full of 
cement all day and use a nasal decongestant spray at night so
I can sleep.  This sucks.  Apparently ragweed season goes until
November.  That sucks too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In other news, we are poking at the idea of moving.  More than
poking, actually; we are submitting our mortgage application today
to find out how much house we can afford.  I hope we will have a
new place by Christmas, although we're not on any sort of a 
deadline so we can take as much time as we need to find a good
house.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I'm packing up and getting rid of things and making lists
and all those sorts of things that people do, and that's mostly
why I am not posting here very much; if I have time to blog then
I have time to pack a box or two, so I do that instead.  Which I
should go do now...
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/allergies.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thirty-One</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/thirtyone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Tuesday was my birthday, and I am finally thirty-one.  
Thirty-one is a bit more convincing than thirty, which
sounds a bit like you're making it up, or at least
rounding.  And when you're thirty-one you're really,
properly in your thirties, not just, thirty.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Delphine's daycare is closed this week, so I invited
a bunch of her friends over and the day that worked
for everyone happened to be my birthday, so we had
Ursa and Tanya over, and Dexter and Ellen and Maxine.
I was talking to Delphine about our plans for the
day over breakfast, and I said, "Who's coming over
today?"  She said "Dexter."  "Who else?"  "Ellen,
and Maxine."  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I said, "Who else?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She said, "Who?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Ursa!"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Ursa?"  She looked slightly alarmed.  "Two friends?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Yeah, two friends!  Is two friends too many?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Yeah.  Why two friends?"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It turned out that two friends wasn't actually too
many, but she didn't like the idea of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, we got some KFC (which I always have for my
birthday), and Morgan and Kathryn came over too, and
Morgan brought cake, so
the house was noisy and full of fun for my birthday,
which I love.  I was absolutely exhausted by the end
of it all, but it was a good exhaustion.  I like my
friends.  And my friends' children.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then tonight was the family dinner; Morgan and Erik
and Baba and Zaida came over and we had steak and 
mashed potatoes and honey-spice cake which Blake
made for me.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It has been a nice birthday, unambitious and simple
and thoroughly enjoyable.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/thirtyone.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 01:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Back in the running</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/runupdate.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
My knee is better.  On my chiropractor's* advice I went to see
a podiatrist to see if I have any functional problems with my
feet, and he didn't find anything.  He thought it was a
"weekend warrior" injury, which I find curiously flattering
since no-one has ever accused me of being in any way 
warrior-like before.  I think he's right, I just overdid it;
not only was I wearing the wrong shoes, but I was also trying
to run like a real runner when at this stage I should be
doing the old-lady-shuffle to get my body used to this
unprecedented level of physical activity.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I resumed running a couple of weeks ago, but I only managed
to go out a couple of times before we decided to switch
our evening routine around, which left me without a good
time to go out.  Blake and I talked about it, and finally
decided that the only time I can go is after dinner.  I was
reluctant to go out after a meal, but there is no other 
good option, as I will discuss in another post (if I have
time).  And it will encourage me to eat a lighter dinner,
which I could certainly stand to do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last night I went for my first postprandial run and it was
great.  I didn't really want to go — it is against my nature
to leave the house after seven at night — but
go I did.  I ran on the Beltline, an old rail track nearby which
has been converted into a trail, again on my chiro's 
recommendation because it's softer and easier on the 
joints than pavement.  I thought it would be boring
running the Beltline all the time, but I really enjoy
all the people I see; couples with little kids going
out for a walk after dinner; fat people like me trying
to get fit; trim, middle-aged rich women walking briskly
in pairs or groups; serious runners with expensive
gear; groups of teenagers on bikes; people out walking 
their dogs.  Yesterday I saw an old lady out for a
fitness walk wearing white shorts and a t-shirt, 
thin putty-coloured ankle socks and 
&lt;a href="http://www.shoes.com/productimages/shoes_ib49552.jpg"&gt;plimsoll 
runners&lt;/a&gt;, and no bra.  And I thought I would be
bored!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am still doing two minutes of walking and one minute
of running, which is how they start you off in the
Running Room clinic.  When I got home last night I realized
it had been a pretty easy run, so next time I will step
it up to one-and-one.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="font-size:80%"&gt;
* While my chiropractor is technically a chiropractor, the
care she gives me is mainly something called 
&lt;a href="http://www.activerelease.com/about.asp"&gt;Active
Release Techniques&lt;/a&gt; which is basically very targeted
massage with movement, designed to loosen tight muscles
and break down scarring.  Since pretty much all my 
physical problems stem from tight muscles in my legs and
butt it works really well
for me.  I say this because I don't want you to think
I am dumb enough to go to a chiropractor for a sore
knee — I would no more do that than go to an opthamologist
for a sore elbow.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/runupdate.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2006 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Pictures</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/newpics.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I put up some new pictures in the gallery; everything after
May is new.  Enjoy!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/newpics.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 15:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shut up, nasty little man.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/thatman.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I realized today why my injured knee has been bothering me
so much, emotionally.
It's because that horrible little man, that man who lives
in the back of my head and who I thought I had banished
forever, is dancing with glee.  He is dancing with glee
and hissing "You see?  I told you!  I told you you are too
fat to be a runner!'
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Shut up, nasty little man, and crawl back in your hole,
because my knee feels better today and I will run again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Okay, you know the other thing that pisses me off
about this?  (Soon I will stop going on about this,
I promise.)  Blake decided that he was going to
ride his bike up to Balm Beach, like, 135 kilometers, 
and you know what,
I bet he is going to do it.  But &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; decide 
I am going to start running
and not two weeks into it I am couch-bound with a stupid
injury!  This after I had to give up hot yoga 
because of my back!  It's like every time I try and
get fitter something fouls it up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
How come everyone else can do this stuff and I can't?
Waah!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I know, welcome to my pity party.  I hope that eventually
this will just be a humourous anecdote about the 
inauspicious start to my long running career.  There I will
be, cocktail in hand: "I had only been running for
a week -- I had been out three times! -- and there
I was with an injured knee!  Ha ha!  Can you believe
it!  Well, then I got proper shoes and 
here I am, three marathons later!  Incredible!  
Ha ha ha!  Pass the olives!"
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/thatman.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Woe Is Me (But At Least I Am Not Dead)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/woe.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
A couple of weeks ago, after I read that Silken Laumann book,
I realized that I no longer had any excuse not to take a
running clinic at The Running Room.  
I had thought for a while about taking a clinic, thought about it, 
planned to do it at some unspecified point in the future...
and suddenly I realized that that point was now.
Cordelia is old enough
that she can be away from me for a while, and Blake is
more than willing to look after her and Delphine
while I go out running.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I signed up for the Learn To Run clinic, a ten-week
program that promises to take the slobbiest
slob and render them capable of running a 5K.
I dug out
my old running shoes and showed up 
the first Saturday, 8:30 in the morning.  
I was full of energy, keen
to go, had been up for hours already!  I ran, I walked,
it was great, it was easier than I thought, I loved
being out in the fresh air first thing in the morning
before all the crowds.  I went for a practice run 
that Monday,
and then for a bike ride with Blake on Thursday.  
I was feeling 
good, healthy, my back was feeling looser and
less painful than it had in years.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Okay, my knee was a little sore on the bike ride,
but hey!  My knees are always a little sore!
Arthritis, right?  Getting some exercise and losing
weight will only help, right?  So I went to the clinic
and ran again -- it was still good, but a little harder
this week.  Oh, and they mentioned that you should 
really get new shoes after you have babies because
your feet change.  Oh.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By then my knee really hurt, but I walked
the twenty-minute walk home, then back up to the
store again later that day to buy new shoes, and
home again.  (I am really stupid.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My knee still hurt by Wednesday -- all the time,
whether I was walking or running or just sitting -- 
so I went to see my physical therapist.  And as
it turns out, I have injured the cartilage in my
knee and I won't be able to run for at least a
couple of weeks, if ever.  (The "if ever" part
we will find out through a process of trial and
error, lucky me.)  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And in the meantime, I have to stay off my feet
as much as possible;
no trip to the store, no
trip to the library to pick up the books I have
on hold there.  It's a blessing that
Starbucks is just across the street, that's all
I say.  The irony is that I started this trying to
get fit, and here I am more sedentary than ever.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Oh woe, oh woe, but at least I am not dead.  
(A friend of a friend was killed in a horseback
riding accident last weekend, a timely reminder
that it could always be worse.)
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>everythingelse</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/woe.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2006 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>