<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (flat)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/flat.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>An Inconvienient Ride</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/inconvienientride.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew when I woke up this morning that it would be an annoying ride
in.  It was raining fairly hard, but there was a breakfast at &lt;a href="http://www.thebikejoint.com/"&gt;The
Bike Joint&lt;/a&gt;, and they usually have one
of the better breakfasts.  It’s the same coffee, muffins, bagels, and
fresh fruit as filling.  As it turns out, this year they got an
espresso machine, so instead of the normal coffee, I had a very nice
latte along with my chocolate chip muffin, but along the way I got
almost completely soaked and tore a hole in the crotch of my biking
jeans.  The hole wasn’t a complete surprise; the other side had gone a
couple of weeks ago, and I had patched it with some old t-shirt.  I
guess it’s time to re-do the patch, and extend it to cover both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I got there, had some coffee and a muffin, and as I got on my
bike after crossing the street when I noticed that my rear wheel
didn’t really feel right.  I looked behind me and found that it had
gone completely flat while I was standing around eating breakfast.  I
wheeled the bike back to &lt;a href="http://www.thebikejoint.com"&gt;the store&lt;/a&gt;,
Derrick replaced the tube, and I was on my way just as it started to
rain again.  And then my front light fell off and broke into three
pieces.  Fortunately, that was easy enough for me to snap back
together, and be on my way once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all that, I ended up being late for the 10:00am Status Meeting
at work, which was the cherry of annoyance on top of the annoying
ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day, so far, has gone much better.  I listening to a
not-particularly-interesting &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/5oag85"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; about
bicycle touring at &lt;a href="http://www.mec.ca/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt;, and while I was there
bought a bell.  My current bell works just fine, but it’s one of the
&lt;em&gt;ding&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ding&lt;/em&gt; ones, and no-one seems to recognize it as a bike bell,
so I got one that goes &lt;em&gt;ringggg&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;ringgg&lt;/em&gt;, which is the canonical bike
bell noise, and I hope that’ll help.  Work is good too, if a little
busier than I might like.  And I finally got emacs working with
Markdown pretty much the way I want, so all in all, woot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Update: The ride home went mostly well, although there were spatters
of rain throughout the trip.  Around Sherbourne and Bloor, my rear
tire started to slow wayyyy down, and then stop.  When I flipped the
bike over, I noticed that it was jammed right up against the frame, so
I loosened it, straightened it, re-tightened it, and kept on going.
Still, that’s never happened to me before, and was pretty strange.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>breakfast</category><category>flat</category><category>rain</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/inconvienientride.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:32:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>