<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (food)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/food.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Conversations with Kindergarteners</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/apples.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
The other day I went with Delphine's class on a field trip
to the Toronto Botanical Gardens.  I was put in charge of
Delphine; Annie, with long blonde hair in a messy ponytail and
huge blue Cindy Loo Who eyes; and Alyssa, tiny and cheerful
and not particularly inclined to stay with the group.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After all the festivities of looking at leaves and planting
garlic cloves and holding compost worms, we all stopped for
a snack.  The children got granola bars, but I had packed myself
an apple because I knew I would be hungry too.  (I eat like a 
little kid, lots of snacks.)  Alyssa asked what kind of apple
it was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"It’s a Honeycrisp.  I haven't tried them before but I really
like it; it's crispy and juicy and sweet.  We usually get Royal Gala."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"We get Honeycrisp," said Alyssa.  "I like them."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"We get Golden Russet," said Annie.  I asked if she liked
them and she said she did.  "They're brown and the skin is
kind of rough."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I said I would try them next time I bought apples, but
they didn't have any at the grocery store yesterday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Isn't that a weird conversation to have with four and five
year-olds?  I guess that's when you get when you live in
a neighbourhood of foodies.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversations</category><category>delphine</category><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/conversations/apples.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 19:43:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>God's Own Chocolate Cake</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/chocolatecake.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the world's best chocolate cake recipe -- it's
really easy, it always
comes out moist and rich and delicious, and best of all it
calls for cocoa powder, which I always have in the house,
not unsweetened chocolate, which I never have.  Use the
leftover buttermilk to make pancakes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cocoa Fudge Cake&lt;br&gt;
from the Betty Crocker Cookbook, 1969 Edition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1 2/3 cups all-purpose flour&lt;br&gt;
1½ cups sugar&lt;br&gt;
2/3 cup cocoa&lt;br&gt;
1½ teaspoons baking soda&lt;br&gt;
1 teaspoon salt&lt;br&gt;
1½ cups buttermilk&lt;br&gt;
½ cup shortening&lt;br&gt;
2 eggs (1/3 to ½ cup)&lt;br&gt;
1 teaspoon vanilla
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Heat oven to 350 degrees.  Grease and flour baking pan,
13x9x2 inches, or 2 round layer pans, 8 or 9x1½
inches. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Measure all ingredients into large mixer bowl.  Blend
½ minute on low speed, scraping bowl constantly.
Beat 3 minutes high speed, scraping bowl occasionally.
Pour into pan(s).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Bake oblong 35 to 40 minutes, layers 30 to 35 minutes
or until wooden pick inserted in centre comes out clean.
Cool.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If desired (!), frost cake.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Cocoa Butter Frosting&lt;br&gt;
from the Betty Crocker Cookbook, 1969 Edition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here's a frosting recipe I've used, with similarly
excellent results.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
1/3 cup soft butter&lt;br&gt;
1/3 cup cocoa&lt;br&gt;
2 cups confectioner's sugar&lt;br&gt;
1½ teaspoons vanilla&lt;br&gt;
About 2 tablespoons milk
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Mix thoroughly butter and cocoa.  Blend in sugar.
Stir in vanilla and milk; beat until frosting is
smooth and of spreading consistency.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Fills and frosts two 8- or 9-inch layers or frosts
a 13x9 inch cake.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/chocolatecake.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lazy Man's Homemade Ice Cream</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/lazyicecream.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Put some frozen blueberries in a bowl.  (I like
&lt;a href="http://www.europesbest.com/"&gt;Europe's Best&lt;/a&gt;
if you can get them.)  Pour in just enough whipping
cream to almost cover the berries.  Wait a few seconds
and the berries will freeze the cream -- voila, quick 
frosty goodness that's almost good for you!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/lazyicecream.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Food Chart</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/food/chart.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>Here's a chart I made up for myself, based mainly on
information from the book &lt;em&gt;Better Baby Food&lt;/em&gt;.
I stuck it up on my bulletin board in the kitchen and
I have been using it as a checklist to figure out what
Cordelia has tried so far, and what she's ready for
next.

&lt;table cellpadding="4"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;6 months&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
 rice&lt;br&gt;
 barley&lt;br&gt;
 oats&lt;br&gt;
 carrots&lt;br&gt;
 sweet potato&lt;br&gt;
 peaches&lt;br&gt;
 squash&lt;br&gt;
 potato&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 apples&lt;br&gt;
 bananas&lt;br&gt;
 pears&lt;br&gt;
 beets&lt;br&gt;
 plums&lt;br&gt;
 avocadoes&lt;br&gt;
 peas&lt;br&gt;
 broccoli&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;7 months&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 wheat&lt;br&gt;
 chicken&lt;br&gt;
 pork&lt;br&gt;
 tuna&lt;br&gt;
 salmon&lt;br&gt;
 beef&lt;br&gt;
 beans&lt;br&gt;
 egg yolk
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 tofu&lt;br&gt;
 yogurt&lt;br&gt;
 cottage cheese&lt;br&gt;
 pasta&lt;br&gt;
 lentils&lt;br&gt;
 chickpeas&lt;br&gt;
 toast&lt;br&gt;
 crackers&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;9 months&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
 milk
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;1 year&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
 berries&lt;br&gt;
 tomatoes&lt;br&gt;
 egg white&lt;br&gt;
 honey
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/food/chart.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2006 02:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Feed Your Baby (When You Can Barely Feed Yourself): Six Month Edition</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/food/howtofeedyourbaby.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Once upon a time, a long time ago, when Delphine was still
a baby, some friends wondered how a person who can barely
manage to feed themselves without a takeout menu
can manage to feed a child.  I used to think I would
be able to answer that question, but the fact is I
have become very domestic in the last few years; I
have a kitchen that is almost always clean enough
to cook in, I have multiple pans and knives, I have
a working dishwasher, I have enough staples on hand
to cook a dinner or bake a cake.  I even have a 
chest freezer. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One day this could be you (well, maybe not the chest
freezer).  
The journey from urban restaurant forager to urban
chef has been one of many steps, and one of
them was having a child who needed good food, not 
just leftover pizza (although they still get that
sometimes).  So it may be that having to
feed your child properly is exactly the kick in the
pants you need to learn how to feed yourself properly too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But that is neither here nor there -- what you need
to know right now, with your hungry six month old
on your knee, mouth agape, is how and what do I feed
her now?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Your first and best friend in this task is the boxed
baby cereal.  The one I always get is Heinz -- look
for one with as few extraneous ingredients as possible,
especially without milk or added formula.  
Lots of baby cereals have
milk in them; those cereals are for formula-fed babies
who have already been exposed to the 
hard-to-digest foreign proteins in cow's milk -- if
your baby is exclusively breastfed there is no need
to expose her to those proteins until she is ready for
them, in a couple of months.  So look for cereal that
just has grain, and probably a couple of vitamins,
in the ingredient list.  Get used to reading ingredient
lists -- you will be doing it a lot.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Start with rice cereal -- rice is the easiest grain
to digest.  If you're a champion pumper you can mix
it with breastmilk, otherwise use water.  You're
supposed to use boiled, cooled water -- I just used
whatever's in the bottom of the kettle from my last
cup of tea, which was never very long ago.   If you
trust your municipal water supply, after a while you
will just use tap water if you're lazy like me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A little bit of cereal a couple of times a day is 
fine to start off with.  Remember, real food is just
recreational for now -- your baby gets all 
her nutrition from breastmilk (or formula) at this
stage, and will until she is a year old.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do rice for a week, then try barley and oatmeal -- 
these are also very easy to digest.  If you are
brave enough to try them, you will find that the 
tastiest of the cereals is barley, despite being 
the unappetizing grey colour of &lt;em&gt;papier mache&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You're supposed to wait four days or so between 
introducing new foods -- Cordelia is almost eight
months old as I write this, and I am introducing 
new foods at a manic pace of one a day or so.
You might be more conservative if you have any
concerns about allergies or if your baby is 
sensitive to new tastes and takes a while to get
used to them, or if you're just nervous.  
Whatever works for you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After you have your baby nicely warmed up on
cereal, you can introduce fruits and veg.  My
doctor suggested doing orange, then yellow,
then green, but I think this whole process is
complicated enough without bringing the rainbow
into it.  Just introduce whatever you think would
be fun.  (See the chart I posted for ideas.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jarred Food or Homemade?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Both.  Jarred food is convenient, and you can get
good stuff.  You can even get organic if it's 
important to you.  Just, again, read the labels 
and don't buy anything with added sugar or starch.
If the jar says "Sweet Potato" the ingredient
list should say "sweet potato" and nothing else.
Use your good sense.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Two things to avoid: jarred banana tastes weird
because it's cooked, so it actually has that
fake banana taste, and also, how hard is it to
mash up a banana with a fork?  Buying jarred banana
is just embarrassing.  And jarred green beans 
are sour and horrible -- homemade green beans
aren't nice either; they just don't puree well.
Green beans can wait until your baby has learned
how to chew.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But homemade baby food is nice, too -- there
are lots of fruits and vegetables that you 
can't get jarred -- okra?  asparagus?  mango?
And there's a warm, fuzzy feeling to feeding
your baby something you have made with your
own hands.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
How to make homemade baby food?  This is the
easiest way: 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;open a bag of frozen peas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dump some in the beaker that came with your
hand blender (You do have a hand blender, don't
you?  How do you make milkshakes?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour in just enough water to cover the peas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put a saucer over the top of the beaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stick it in the microwave for a few minutes,
    until the water boils and the peas get
    a little bit soft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drain off the water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blend the peas into mush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Put some in a bowl, wait until it cools, serve.
Put the rest into those little one-cup or half-cup
Gladware containers and freeze.  (Everyone says to
use ice cube trays, but they are a pain in the
ass, and my kid easily eats a quarter-cup at a
sitting, which is way more than one ice cube.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can do the same with other frozen vegetables,
or frozen or canned fruit (you don't have to microwave
the fruit, obviously).  If the resulting puree 
is too runny, add some of the dry baby cereal to
thicken it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you have a clean knife and cutting board kicking
around, you can do much the same thing with any
fresh vegetable or fruit (with the exception of
berries and tomatoes, which can be allergenic).  
If you prefer, cook it in a 
pan on the stove, if you have a clean pan and your
stove works.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Get someone else to clean up, you have done enough.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/unsolicited%20advice/food/howtofeedyourbaby.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2006 02:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Food Things</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/threethings.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1. Square Meatballs.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I got this from &lt;em&gt;Better Baby Food&lt;/em&gt;, which is my favourite cookbook
these days.  In the book it's a recipe but here I will just describe
the idea: square meatballs.  Instead of making little round meatballs,
which involves lots of time spent with your hands coated in raw meat
(not so good when the baby gets into the Choking Hazards), you pat
your meatball mixture in a thin layer (three-quarters of an inch?)
in a baking dish, and then bake them for twenty minutes at 350F.  Yes,
it's basically a thin meatloaf.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After they are done, use a sharp knife to cut them into little squares
for the kids and bigger squares for the grown-ups.  Genius!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Thing&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My in-laws make a dish called Zucchini Thing, which is really so
unlike anything else that the only possible name 
for it is Thing.  I have the recipe, but I am loathe to make anything
that calls for Bisquick.  To my delight, though, I found a recipe in
a magazine for the very same thing, except without Bisquick:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
3 C grated zucchini&lt;br&gt;
1 small onion, chopped&lt;br&gt;
1 C all-purpose flour&lt;br&gt;
1 C grated provolone cheese&lt;br&gt;
3 eggs, beaten&lt;br&gt;
1/4 C vegetable oil&lt;br&gt;
4 T grated Parmesan&lt;br&gt;
2 t chopped fresh basil&lt;br&gt;
1 t baking powder&lt;br&gt;
1 t salt&lt;br&gt;
1/2 t black pepper
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Mix it all together, slap it in a greased pie plate, cook it at 350F 
for 45 to 50 minutes or until golden brown, let it cool for 10 minutes,
and &lt;em&gt;voila&lt;/em&gt;!  Thing!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The nice thing about Thing, though, is that it is forgiving.  Substitute
some other pureed vegetable for the zucchini (provided it is about as
moist as grated zucchini, which is pretty moist).  Stick some other
kind of cheese in!  And best of all, kids love it and it has three (3)
food groups.  Cut it into little squares and let 'em pick it up in
their fingers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. Chocolate charoset&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I just made this up today.  I was making charoset for Passover dinner
tonight (I know, we're late) and I did it Sephardic style, in little
balls rolled in cinnamon.  After I had done a few I thought they looked
like truffles, and my mind wandered to truffles coated in cocoa.  "Hm."
I thought.  "I wonder..."  So I tried it, and they're really tasty.
Dessert charoset!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/threethings.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2006 19:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Holiday Eating</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040411.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Today we had Morgan and Erik over for a Passover/Easter feast.  Morgan
made saucy chicken and chopped liver, and I made fruit kugel and 
Passover brownies and roasted asparagus.  (The asparagus was an afterthought
when I realized we didn't have any vegetables.)  We also had Easter
eggs with the brownies for dessert.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The recipes for Morgan's saucy chicken and my kugel both came out of
&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0969797206/102-4098737-5815362?v=glance"&gt;the yellow book&lt;/a&gt; and they both turned out really well.
The Passover brownies were made from my mother-in-law's recipe.  They
didn't turn out so well because they didn't cook through;  I didn't
realize until this morning when I tried to turn them out of the pan.  I 
glued the whole mess together with Glossy Chocolate Frosting made from
a recipe in my old Betty Crocker book, and it worked really well.  I
thought the whole meal turned out great, considering all the recipes we
used were new to us.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We all ate and ate until we couldn't move, and then squeezed in a little
more, and now I'm &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; tired.  It was good; I love holiday food.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040411.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 01:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-thousand Calories</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040323.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
A while ago I said I was going to cut down to 2000 calories a
day, but I've been having a hard time doing so.  It seems so lame, 
when you consider that there are so many people on 1200 and 1600 cpd
diets, that I can't even cut down to a still-excessive 2000 cpd.  The
difference for me is that when you're on a diet, you know it's a 
temporary thing, that even if you can't have the cookie or the chocolate
today, one day when you're not on the diet anymore you'll be able to.
Since my diet isn't a temporary change, I am reluctant to give things up
because I know it's forever.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My ultimate goal is to eat an average of 1800 calories per day.  You
need to take in about 1600 calories per day to get all the nutrients
you need; that's 1600 calories of real food, leafy vegetables and
whole grains and lean meat and fruit.  At 1800 calories a day that
only leaves 200 calories free for "fun" food.  That's less than a 
chocolate bar.  That's just two cookies.  I'm sure there are plenty
of people in this world who live without having fun food every day, but
I'm not sure I want to be one of them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This resistance to giving up treats is what has made it so hard to
break the 2000 calorie barrier.  I've been hovering around 2050 for
the last few days, but yesterday I decided if I can be under 2000 every
day this week, I will reward myself with some tacky makeup or something
on the weekend.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have a couple of strategies I'm working on.  One is to have a big
breakfast with lots of protein and fruit, to keep me going without hunger
until lunchtime.  Then theoretically I'll be able to have a smallish lunch.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Another strategy is to keep digestive 
cookies in the house.  It sounds counter-intuitive to diet by keeping 
cookies in the house, but digestives are pretty low calorie*, and a couple of 
them plus a cup of tea are enough to satisfy my desire for
a treat in the afternoon.  If I don't have them around, I'm likely to
go to Starbucks and get a 200 calorie mocha and a 500 calorie scone.
I think of them as a pressure valve.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[*Actually digestives are still pretty high calorie -- around 75 calories
each.  I think next time I will buy social tea biscuits or something,
which are only around 22 calories each.  That way I can have six of them!]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, having said that, I weighed myself at the doctor's office 
this morning and
I have lost another 5 lbs to bring me down to 190, with a BMI of 30.7.  That's
only 0.7... um....  BMI units? away from being merely "overweight", not "obese".
How exciting!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm curious to see if I plateau at 185, since I have never been able to
diet down past 185.  I think that might be my adult low, actually.  (I 
don't know what I weighed in high school, although I do know I was wearing
size 36 Levi 501s.  I should go try on a pair and see if I fit into them.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've lost a total of 42 lbs from my pre-pregnancy weight, but I don't 
feel 42 lbs smaller, and I don't think I look it.  I get the odd comment,
but not the barrage of compliments that you'd hope for when you've lost almost
20% of yourself. 
Part of the problem is
that I haven't bought many new clothes, so I'm still wearing my 230 lb
wardrobe; my look now is "baggy".  And of course there's the fact that
for so long I've been so militantly happy to be fat that most of my
friends know better than to say "You've lost weight!" as a compliment.  
Still, it would be nice to know that my shrinkage is perceptible to
others.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I read an article by a woman,
my height, who described herself as plump and unattractive.  Then she said
she needed to lose 20 lbs to feel desirable -- she was 155 lbs and wanted
to be 135.  Twenty pounds is the difference between unattractive and desirable,
and I've lost twice that!  Before, I felt like me, and now, I feel like
me.  I guess it's good that I don't invest my weight with so much meaning,
but the flip side of that coin is that when I lose weight I don't get
the big irrational ego boost.  Humph.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040323.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2004 03:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>28 Year Checkup</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040309.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I went to the doctor today for my annual physical.  I always enjoy
physicals because I'm generally healthy, and when else do I get to spend
forty five minutes talking with someone all about me! me! me!?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everything's good; she gave me the go-ahead to work on another baby,
which is great if academic since I'm still amenorrheic due to nursing.
Apparently most women start ovulating while they are still nursing.
Also the average age difference between children when birth control
is not used is 22 to 28 months, and pregnancies started before that
are more likely to miscarry, although they're not sure why.  Interesting
facts which all basically mean we will let nature take its course, and
also that I will start taking folic acid now so I'm all ready to go
whenever my body is.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I also talked a bit about the arthritis that's developing in my hips.
There's not a whole lot they can do about that, which is a bit of
a pisser.  She said if there's a lot of pain, or I'm anticipating
some activity which will cause pain (like tennis, she said.  That'll
be the day.) I could take a prophylactic ibuprofen to inhibit the
inflammation which causes more joint damage.  Also, losing weight
is a great idea, she said.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And hooray, I'm down to 195 lbs!  I haven't seen this side of 
200 lbs lo these many years.  (I'm also down to a size 18, another
numeric milestone.)  I'm quite pleased that I'm still
losing even though I've been sitting at 2100 calories per day for
quite a while now.  The doctor suggested I should go down to around
1800 calories a day, so I've changed my goal in Fitday to 2000
cpd, and I'll work my way down.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The challenge is going to
be eating properly; I have a tendency to skip real food in order
to save calories for treats like pastries and ice cream.  Such
a bad idea.  I'm going to try watching my food groups, making
sure I get 5 to 10 fruit and veg, 6 to 12 grain, etc etc.  I have 
to be in good nutritional shape to make another beautiful 
healthy baby.  I think it will be easier now that spring is
coming; fruit and salads always seem more palatable in warm
weather.  In winter I just want large piles of meat and potatoes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040309.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 16:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Massive Attack</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040131.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I visited my friend Ellen the other day.  Ellen lives in the 'burbs,
so you have to go all the way to the end of the subway line, and then
take a bus to get to her place.  So when I go, I put Del in the 
BabyTrekker and she dangles there, making googly eyes at all the
other riders.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ellen was surprised when I arrived with Del in the 'Trekker; 
she's having trouble hauling Dexter around in the Bjorn because
he's so heavy.  I bragged that Delphine is 22 lbs, and that I can
carry her because I am so tough!  I am He-Woman!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But the next morning I did the math, and I realized that while Delphine
has gained 12 lbs since she was born, I have lost 22, so between us
we mass 10 lbs less than we used to.  I'm actually 10 lbs-worth weaker
than I used to be.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I made a mistake: I weighed myself last Friday at Morgan's place
- 207 lbs; and then again at Ellen's on Thursday: 210 lbs.  I knew
as I was weighing myself the second time that I shouldn't, that it
would be meaningless whether the number went up or down, but I did
it anyway.  And sure enough, I was disappointed when the number
was higher, even though the difference in scales, in time of day, the
small amount of time between the two weighings, all conspire to
make the difference all but meaningless.  And yet still I was
disappointed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And it goes against the whole point of this Calorie-Control Initiative,
which was to control calories, not lose weight.  Somehow I let myself
start to enjoy the weight loss, to wist for numbers (195!  185!  Lower!)
or dress sizes (16?  14?  12?!) that I can't control instead of focusing
on the one I can control, the number of calories I eat.  And that's 
a recipe for grief.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've decided I'm not going to cut down any more (I'm at 2100 cpd)
until I've talked to my doctor.  For one thing, the USDA is pretty vague
about where in the 1600 to 2200 range a not sedentary but not athletic type
like me fits, and for another I'm still nursing so I need more calories
than I otherwise would.  My final concern is that when I get pregnant
again I'll need to modify my intake up, and I worry that I'll gain huge
amounts of weight if my metabolism is all fucked up from going down
too low and then back up again.  So I'll
talk to my doctor and get her opinion before I go any
lower.  I have an appointment for a physical in early March.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>food</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/food/040131.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 02:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>