<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (fread pudding)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/fread-pudding.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 21:12:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Awesome First Day of March Break</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodday2.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today started early for me - I was awake at around 6:30.  Awake
of my own voilition!  No-one jumped on me.  I
lay in bed, too hot because we haven't adjusted our bedding
to account for spring (why is it that even though the thermostat
always says 18, it's way colder in January than in March?) and
listened to an unexpected chattering noise from somewhere
in the house.  It wasn't music or the radio... I couldn't
place it, and then I realized it was Delphine reading to
Cordelia. I stayed in bed for as long as I could stand the
heat, and finally got up at 6:45. The girls and I headed
downstairs for breakfast, with a brief detour to jump on
Daddy (well, for the kids).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For first breakfast we had cereal, and then Delphine logged
on to play her daily complement of video games (she likes
Diego games lately) and I hied myself upstairs to clean the 
bathroom and take a shower.  Once clean and dressed I went
downstairs again to put brunch in the oven, for we were 
expecting company!  Then I vacuumed and tidied and cleaned
and dusted like a mad woman, in time for everything to be
ready at 10, when our friends were to arrive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we waited!  And cleaned.  And waited!  And puttered.  Waited!
Put some coffee on.  Waited!  Arranged coffee mugs and cream
and sugar artfully on the counter. Waited! Sent children 
outside to greet company. And then finally they arrived!  They 
were probably only ten minutes late but when you've 
busted your ass to be ready in time and you're all set, it's
so anti-climactic to have an empty house for even a couple
of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunch was a delightful French toast/bread pudding.  I got the
recipe from Kat, who got it from her friend's mother (I think).
I reproduce it here in full because it's that good:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;French Toast Bread Pudding (Fread Pudding, of course)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 loaf challah (although we used raisin bread this time and it was sublime)&lt;br&gt;
7 eggs&lt;br&gt;
2.5 C milk  &lt;br&gt;
1 tsp vanilla extract  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/2 C butter  &lt;br&gt;
1 C brown sugar&lt;br&gt;
splash of maple syrup if you have any  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut up the bread into cubes.  Beat the eggs and milk and vanilla
together, then mix the bread in.  Put it in the fridge overnight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning butter a lasagna pan, and put the bread mixture in it.
Melt the butter and mix in the brown sugar, and then pour the butter
mixture over the bread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bake the whole thing in the oven at 350 degrees Fahrenheit (see,
I can spell it!) for 40 to 45 minutes.  I usually broil it for
a minute or two for crunchiness.  Let it cool for a few minutes
and serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had great company - two other couples with two kids each, so
we had one baby, an almost-two, Cordelia who is three, Evan who
is four, and Delphine and Ursa who are five.  They all had a 
great time with only bits of crying. Otis in particular was a
trooper despite having lost a fingernail in a horrific toilet
lid accident earlier in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we stuffed ourselves silly with fread pudding, bacon, croissants,
strawberries, and coffee the children dragged us slowly to the
park where they ran around for an hour, or maybe two, while we
grownups talked to each other.  Lovely! And Blake got a sunburn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh that's right!  I didn't mention how perfectly perfect the weather
was!  It seems we have passed that season of purgatory wherein 
if it is sunny it must be cold, and if it is warm it must be 
gloomy. Now we can have both at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Blake has a charming sunburn on one side of his forehead. I
said we have to go back to the park tomorrow and stand on the 
other side of the playground, so he matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the girls had run their fill (almost - I don't think they
have ever actually exhausted the charms of the park on their
own terms, I always have to drag them away, but the dragging was
easier than usual today) and I had investigated a rather charming little
creek born from the runoff from giant snow mountains dumped at the
top of the park throughout winter, we headed east, to Bayview.  I 
bought the girls their ceremonial First Ice Cream of the Season
(lemon for Delphine and chocolate mint for Cordelia), and I had
my first Frappuccino of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally we circled back to home, which was still tidy and
clean from my hard work of the morning.  The girls did some 
drawing, and before we knew it, Baba and Zaida were here for
family dinner.  Zaida picked up sushi, so we didn't have to
cook or dirty up the kitchen, and it was delicious.  The girls
played outside for a little longer, and then headed to bed
without all that much fuss. (Especially since I didn't have
to put them there - Blake and Zaida did bedtime while I worked
on the cryptic with Baba.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was one of those lovely, chilled out, sunny, fun days with
lots of good friends (good, smart friends!) and family, cute kids and
yummy food.  Food and company - I think those are my favourite
things. At least for today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>food</category><category>fread pudding</category><category>recipe</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/diversions/goodday2.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 02:01:19 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>