<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (holidays)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/holidays.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Hallowe'en and Other Things</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're in the midst of the fall festive season, and
as anyone who is less than four feet tall knows, 
that means it's Hallowe'en.  Both Delphine and Cordelia
are very excited, and it's clear that Cordelia
remembers a thing or two about last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine is planning to be a penguin this year.  We haven't bought a penguin costume; rather we
are hoping to kludge something together with 
a white shirt and a black hoodie and orange 
construction paper beak and feet.  I hope it
works because we haven't had a chance to
try it out and we're running out of pre-Hallowe'en
weekend.  Delphine has a pretty convincing penguin
waddle which would sell the lamest costume,
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordelia has independently decided to be a black
cat.  For a while there she was going with
ghost and I thought we would have to find and
then butcher a white sheet — you always see
that white-sheet-with-holes ghost costume in
cartoons and stuff but I've never seen it
in real life.  I thought it would be cool to try
it out.  But about a week ago she switched
to black cat, so I dropped a whopping $19 on
ears and a tail, which together with black clothes
and some eyeliner whiskers will make a convincing
and adorable cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Hallowe'en is that it gives
you lots of chances to talk about such topics of 
childhood interest as death and scary things.  Last
year we spent a lot of time talking about being dead
and what death is (and who Death is — a house around
the corner has an inflatable Grim Reaper).  This year
we are leaning more towards Hallowe'en imagery and
what is scary.  Delphine wanted to know why someone
had fake gravestones on their lawn.  "Gravestones
aren't scary", she said.  I said they mark where dead people
are buried, but she was unmoved by that because to
her mind dead people aren't scary.  And of course 
by extension, skeletons aren't scary either.  What
&lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; scary?  Witches, spiders and ghosts are apparently
scary.  I don't think bats are and rats definitely 
aren't, although we did decorate with black rubber 
rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delphine likes Monopoly.  I know, weird.  I wouldn't
have occurred to me to put her in front of a game of
Monopoly, but my friend Tanya, who is nothing if not
ambitious with what she exposes her kid to, brought it
over and Delphine loves it.  She loves the money: she
likes to sort it out, stack it up, pay for things and
get money from other people.  She likes choosing which
piece she will be, and she loves to move around the
board.  She got tired of it, though, after maybe forty minutes,
and started acting up.  "I'm so bored of giving people
money!"  Yeah, tell me about it.  So for Christmas I
got her &lt;em&gt;Monopoly Junior&lt;/em&gt;.  I'm normally not in favour
of kiddified versions of things, but this looks like
it retains the main elements of the adult version
(including the lovely money) but goes faster.  Plus
the setting is a carnival, not some boring old city.
Delphine loves carnivals and fairs and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cordelia went for her birthday sleepover at Auntie
Morgan's house this weekend.  Unfortunately I have
no idea what they did because Cordelia said she had
fun but she didn't want to talk about it.  I know
what Delphine did, though, because she stayed home
for what we have termed a "sleepunder", which is
what you get when you're the sister who stays
home and has Mum and Dad to herself.  Mostly we
played Monopoly.  Delphine chose KD for supper, and
we read lots of chapters at bedtime because we
didn't have to put Cordelia to bed.  In the morning
Delphine decreed that Blake should get up early (that
is, when Delphine and I got up) and join us for a 
breakfast of French toast and pancakes.  Then more
Monopoly, and then we went out to get Cordelia back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Incidentally, the thing with Blake getting up with us turned
out abysmally.  Usually he stays in bed for an hour
or more on weekend mornings while I get up with the
kids and make breakfast and read the paper.  Having
missed that extra sleep, however, he was logy and 
grumpy all day.  He napped twice but it didn't help.
God knows what he's like during the week, but from
now on I will gladly let him get his morning beauty
sleep.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sleepunder was lovely.  Unfortunately at the moment the girls
are much more pleasant to be around one at a time than
together.  Delphine alone is insightful and contemplative
and interesting, Cordelia alone is funny and clever and
demonstrative.  Together they are whiny and scrappy 
and tiresome.  Not all the time, but often enough that
it wears me out.  Hopefully between them they will eventually
grow out
of it and figure out how to enjoy each other's company
more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>holidays</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/halloween.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 19:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First Hallowe'en in the New House!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/halloween07.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Our neighbourhood loves Hallowe'en.  At least half of the 
houses, it seems, are decorated, and the sidewalks were so
thick with trick or treaters last night that most people
weren't even bothering to close their doors between
visitors.  On our block most of our neighbours were sitting
on the front porch steps chatting; some with wine, some
without.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We decorated our house with three pumpkins (remember when
one jack o' lantern was enough?) and three bats made from
our leftover NDP campaign sign, painstakingly cut out and
coloured with black magic marker.  We also used the 
uprights upon which said sign was mounted to string a 
spiderweb to which I glued a spider, also made from
the sign.  (I decided I wasn't going to buy anything
last month so we had to make our own decorations from
whatever we had at hand.  Thank goodness there had been
an election!)  It all looked pretty awesome,
and all the more satisfying since we didn't just buy it
at the dollar store.  I guess today I should
take it all down.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Last night Cordelia was dressed as a bumblebee, with 
yellow and black
tights and a pair of sparkly wings.  (The headband with 
antennae came off pretty early and Morgan and I ended
up wearing it.)  She loved trick or treating, and she
wouldn't let anyone else hold her bag of candy even when
it was almost too heavy for her to carry.  She learned
to say "t'ick a t'eat!" and "t'anks!" right away.  Well,
with prompting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Delphine was a bunny, with fluffy ears, a beige hoodie (bunnyhug!) 
and a cottontail sewed to her white skirt.  She was into
trick or treating until she hit the Brick Wall of Sleepiness
at around 7:15 and refused to get off the 
&lt;a href="http://www.lascal.se/html/kb_models01.aspx"&gt;kiddy 
board&lt;/a&gt; until we got home.  Cordelia trick or treated
at a couple of different houses after that and when Delphine
was asked if she wanted some candy she said "No thanks."
When that kid is tired, she is tired.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After we got home and sorted through Delphine's candy,
and ate some, we put the girls to bed (an hour late!)
Then Blake and I picked through their respective booty
and set aside the thirty most succulent (and safe, and
appropriate) pieces (one for
each day in November) for each girl, and kept the rest for ourselves!
Well, Blake will take them to work and fatten up his
colleagues.  Then we sat and watched &lt;em&gt;Band Candy&lt;/em&gt; and
ate chocolate until we were done eating chocolate.  Which,
for reference, means we ate a lot of chocolate.  Mmmm...
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>delphine</category><category>holidays</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/halloween07.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 18:45:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>