<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (house)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/house.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Cordelia is Fifteen Months Old</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/fifteenmonths.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Cordelia is my little monkey.  She is fearless and ambitious —
this morning she was hauling the cat carrier around the house,
dragging it behind her and bashing into every damn thing.  She
dragged it into the kitchen and before I could turn around she had
climbed on it and was messing around on the counter.  She
does appalling things like that every day; I certainly didn't
get any experience with this kind of behaviour from Delphine.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last time I posted about Cordelia, she had just started
walking.  Well, she's been walking for four months now and
she's pretty darn good at it.  Mostly.  The other day I put
her down in  the front yard and she took off like a flash down
the path; there's a little step right before the path meets
the sidewalk, and she stepped down it.  Unfortunately the
step is about four inches, and Cordelia's leg is also about
four inches, and so after her foot made contact with the
ground, her right hand did, then her left, and then... her
head. She hardly cried at all, but I had to pick some grit
out of her, and now she's walking around with a gnarly big
scab on her forehead.  She doesn't care; it makes her
look fierce.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She says a few words now: cat, up, milk, ball, book, 
Mimi (which applies to all cats), Daddy, Mummy, duck, 
and of course, "no", with a
little head shake.
She always says "no" when you ask her a question;
I think she just likes shaking her head.  She had her
eye on my tea — the child is always thirsty — and asked 
for it, but then answered her own question by shaking
her head sadly: "no".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Fifteen months is the age Delphine was when we started
putting her down to sleep alone; Cordelia has been sleeping
alone for almost a year.  She sleeps from six or six-thirty
until six in the morning, and she goes down without a
fight.  Last night I was nursing her to sleep and she 
stopped nursing and looked around.  I issued my usual
ultimatum: "Boobie or bed!"  Her typical response is
to latch right back on in a hurry, but last night she
said "Bed!", and sat up to be put in the crib.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She's down to one nap a day, mostly — she just suddenly
stopped needing a morning nap one day.  The catch is
that when she's sick she still needs two naps some days,
and I'm never sure whether any given day will be a one-napper or
a two-napper.  Makes planning ahead hard.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Being in the house with Cordelia is also really hard; if I
want to go upstairs or to the basement, I have to pick her
up; I can't work in the basement with her because there
are too many hazards: cat litter, stairs, unexpected pointy
things.  Upstairs we don't have a baby gate for stairs, so 
I have to pick a room to work in, shut the door, and stay
there.  So mostly we stay on the main floor, which makes
unpacking and doing laundry and any other multifloor
pursuit very difficult.  I do miss having everything on the
same floor, but I have to remind myself that one day
Cordelia will be able to handle stairs and being by herself,
so I will be able to get stuff done much easier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And in the meantime, she makes me laugh every single
day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>development</category><category>house</category><category>sleep</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/fifteenmonths.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Settling</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/houseandhome/settling.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
People keep asking me if we're getting settled in,
and until today I was getting pretty tired of it,
because I really didn't feel all that settled.
Today, though, we moved a bunch of boxes out of
the living room and laid down the rug, cleared
the upstairs landing, and unpacked a couple of
big bins, and now it finally does feel like we're
getting settled, like this is really where we 
live and not just where all our stuff is.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course we still have a million things to
unpack, but we have been cleverly hiding boxes
in the basement rather than face them, and we
are managing quite nicely with the forty 
percent of our possessions that we have unpacked.
I have a grand plan for unpacking the rest 
which involves a large box labelled "Garage
Sale"; Blake and I will dig into that project
in the New Year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's a crappy little house (in some ways, and
in others it's wonderful), and sometimes I 
wonder why we bought it.  The kitchen needs 
redoing, the bathroom needs redoing (not to
mention there's only the one), the basement
isn't done at all... this house is a money sponge
capable of absorbing every spare
penny for the next two decades.  Why didn't we
buy one of the shiny, renovated perfect houses
with the dug-out, finished basements and the
second bathrooms and the nice kitchens?  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Money, for one thing; we didn't pay much for
this place.  But we're going to have to put more
than the difference back into it to get it up
to snuff.  The burning desire to be knee-deep
in plaster dust for the next five years?  A
passion to express myself through interior
design?  That can't be right.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't think that's the reason we bought
the house.
I think we fell in love with the
oldness of it, with the perfect trim and the
retro cabinets, and with the challenge of
taking this beloved old house and bringing it
up to date without erasing its character; 
deciding what to keep and what to take away.
Taking what is in a sense a blank slate and
making it our own.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We've got some pretty good ideas about keeping
the character while still beating the house
into twenty-first century submission.  We're
going to rip down a bunch of walls, but save
the trim and cleverly use it elsewhere:  we're
going to use the trim from between the living
room and the dining room to frame a huge
pass-through between the kitchen and the dining
room; we're going to use trim from one of the
doors to create an archway at the end of the
new front hall; we're going to use two doors
to make a headboard, and another to make a mirror
for the top of the stairs.  We're going to 
salvage the doorknobs and line them up on a
board to hang coats and hats on.  We're going
to patch the floors rather than refinish
(or replace) the hardwood.  And of course
I want to do the kitchen in a style reminiscent
of the fifties; I almost want the kitchen to 
look like it was installed in the fifties
and impeccably maintained, rather than to
look like a new kitchen with all the latest
fashions and gadgets.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think when we're done this first phase of
renovations, the house will be modern and
comfortable, with an open living space, lots
of light and air, a large, usable kitchen,
and new wiring and light switches in sensible
places, but it will still retain the patina of
age that we love.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>home</category><category>house</category><category>houseandhome</category><category>moving</category><category>status</category><category>unpacking</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/houseandhome/settling.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 03:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>