<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (java)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/java.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why is this stuff so hard?</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/juliandate.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago, I fixed a bug by deleting the class.  I don’t
often get to do that, but this class was buggy, hard to use, and
ill-considered in the first place.  I won’t post the code, but some
sample output is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fri Aug 27 00:00:00 EDT 1976
Julian Day: 2443017
Milliseconds since midnight: 43200000
Thu Aug 26 20:00:00 EDT 1976&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Clearly that’s not right, since the top and bottom date should be the
same.  So, what was wrong with it?  Well...
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Julian dates use milliseconds since noon, not milliseconds since
midnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The milliseconds since noon should be 57600000, because we’re in
EDT, which is 4 hours behind UTC.  (The cause of this particular
bug.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The class was implemented as a subclass of
&lt;tt&gt;java.util.GregorianCalendar&lt;/tt&gt;.  A Calendar exists soley to link
a &lt;tt&gt;java.util.Date&lt;/tt&gt; and a &lt;tt&gt;java.util.TimeZone&lt;/tt&gt;, but
Julian dates are all relative to UTC, so should not be represented as
a Calendar, much less a Gregorian Calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I managed to replace almost all the occurrances with
&lt;tt&gt;java.util.Date&lt;/tt&gt;s, except for a couple of places where I needed
to group things by day in EST.  Those places I just created a new
&lt;tt&gt;java.util.GregorianCalendar&lt;/tt&gt;, and used it to figure out where
to split my groups.  The algorithm to go from the Julian days and
milliseconds since noon to a &lt;tt&gt;java.util.Date&lt;/tt&gt;, and back again
is fairly easily derivable from the formula:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;date = (julianDate - JULIAN_START) * MILLIS_PER_DAY + julianMillis - MILLIS_PER_DAY/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Solve for any one of the three lowercase variables, using a little
truncating-division, or a little modulo arithmatic to get rid of
unknown terms, and you’re good to go.  So please, if you’re dealing
with dates or times, don’t make this mistake, at least not where I
might run across it.</description><category>bad_code</category><category>dates</category><category>delete</category><category>gregorian</category><category>java</category><category>julian</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/juliandate.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 18:54:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>