<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (javascript)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/javascript.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>More stuff on the iTouch.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/iTouch/languages.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, like I was done messing with my iTouch.  Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been playing around a lot with the iTouch, and developing
quite a few programs for it.  The first one was by request, although
I’m also finding it very useful.  (And apparently a &lt;a href="http://forums.macrumors.com/showthread.php?p=4754458"&gt;few other
people&lt;/a&gt; are as well!  Cool!)  It’s called &lt;a href="http://www.csse.uwa.edu.au/~chris/iphone/WifiToggle/"&gt;WifiToggle&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s a small app that simply toggles on and off
your Wifi connection, so as to save batteries.  The next thing I did
was &lt;a href="http://iphone.latte.ca/info/Javascript.html"&gt;a port&lt;/a&gt;
of the &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.org/js/spidermonkey/"&gt;SpiderMonkey
Javascript&lt;/a&gt; interpreter.  It works, and it wasn’t that hard to get
compiled and installed, which is really pretty cool when you stop to
think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final thing I got working just tonight (which I was playing
around with mostly to take my mind off of stuff.  See tomorrow’s post
for details), was &lt;a href="http://iphone.latte.ca/info/GambitScheme.html"&gt;a port&lt;/a&gt; of the
&lt;a href="http://www.iro.umontreal.ca/~gambit/wiki/index.php/Main_Page"&gt;Gambit Scheme&lt;/a&gt; interpreter.  I know, Scheme is just like
Javascript, only with an uglier syntax, but I still like it, and
hopefully the lack of punctuation will make it easier to use on the
iTouch.  Heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, if you own an iPhone or iTouch, and have jailbroken it, be
sure to add &lt;a href="http://iphone.latte.ca/"&gt;http://iphone.latte.ca/&lt;/a&gt; to your list of Installer sources, and
geek out!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>itouch</category><category>javascript</category><category>languages</category><category>scheme</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/iTouch/languages.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 02:06:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Does the Future Belong to Javascript?</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/javascript.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div style="width:6.25em; height:6.25em; float:right"&gt;
  &lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 100 100"&gt;&lt;text fill="red" x="50" y="97" text-anchor="middle" font-size="120"&gt;J&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This started off as a response to &lt;a href="http://pyre.third-bit.com/blog/archives/971.html"&gt;Greg's post&lt;/a&gt;,
but grew too long, so I figured I'ld put it here instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reaction I've seen from the developer community to Apple's "iPhone
Development" announcement has been poor at best.  Everyone seems to think
that it's a cop-out, and that they should have just said "We don't support
third-party development, but you can use the web."  My favourite quote has
to be from &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2007/06/wwdc_2007_keynote"&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;If all you have to offer is a shit sandwich,
just say it. Don't tell us how lucky we are and that it's going to taste
delicious.&lt;/blockquote&gt; Maybe it's because I'm an old fuddy-duddy, but I
don't think the Web 2.0 development is really the wave of the future.  I
think the future, like the past, will have desktop apps, client-server apps
with both thick and thin clients, where the server may be a web server or
may not, etc, etc...

&lt;p&gt;And Javascript is still missing the extreme number of useful libraries
that the other three languages have.  Like &lt;a href="http://ironfroggy-code.blogspot.com/2007/06/python-ironpython-apples-and-oranges.html"&gt;Calvin Spealman&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Does syntax alone make a language?
Maybe one day it could, but those days died out. Python is far more than
its clean, beautiful syntax. The libraries that come in the standard
library provide even more value. As a foundation for all the software built
on top, these packages are fundamental to the success of
Python.&lt;/blockquote&gt;and I find that to be true over and over again.  Java
the language kind of sucks.  But the huge number of libraries to do just
about anything I want really rocks.  (And the IDEs are sweet too, which is
a good thing, since trying to write Java without an IDE would give even a
super-robot a serious case of carpal tunnel syndrome.)

&lt;p&gt;Which is not to say that there won't be more and more libraries shipped
with Javascript, but then again, since it's mainly a web-language, the
browser makers will want to keep it light, and so the libraries won't be
part of the language proper, as they are with Python or Java, and any
"standard" library you see will be vendor-specific, just like it is today.
(I already write some Javascript scripts for my day job, but I know that
they're going to run on a Windows box.  I have no idea how to write the
cross-platform equivalent of stuff like:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;if ( FS.FileExists( flavour + "\\gamelist.txt" ) )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
or:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;WScript.Echo( "Unhandled folder: " + fname );&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
much less:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var WSHShell = WScript.CreateObject("WScript.Shell");
var cmdline = "jar.exe xvf " + item + " META-INF/MANIFEST.MF";
WSHShell.Run( cmdline, ActivateAndHide, true );&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Any suggestions?

&lt;p&gt;And while I'm here, that red "J" was the best thing I could come up with
for a Javascript logo, after extensive web searching.  (There's a reason
I'm a programmer, and not a graphics person.)  Anyone seen anything
better?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>greg_wilson</category><category>iphone</category><category>javascript</category><category>reply</category><category>svg</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/javascript.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 17:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>