<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about job)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/job.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to get laid off.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newjob/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few Fridays ago, I was laid off from my job.  After seven years I’m
sort of out of practice at looking for a new job.  The economy is also
kind of slow, and I know a few people who are going to graduate soon
into this economy, and who might want to know what I did when I was
laid off, and how I’ve found a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Friday.  As a side note, if you’re ever in the position of letting
go of employees, please don’t lay them off or fire them on a Friday.
They can’t do anything but sit and brood over the weekend, which can
really get them depressed.  On the other hand, I’ve been pretty upbeat
about it because after seven years, I’m kind of ready for a change.
It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a big shock when I first learned about it, but I had made my
peace with it after around 30 minutes or so.  An hour later, there was
a meeting where the rest of the employees found out, and that was kind
of tough to sit through, but afterwards it was like there was a big
weight lifted from my shoulders, and my co-workers and I started to
joke around about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon, and the next couple of days, I emailed my friends and
asked whether they knew of any companies that were hiring.  From that
I got six or seven leads, and three or four interviews, and finally
decided to do some work and sign a three month contract, which will
probably turn into a longer term contract.  I don’t expect it’ll turn
into a full time job, but that works out fine for me, since I expect
the market will have changed by the new year, and I’m hoping that a
friend of mine will get the hiring freeze he’s currently in lifted by
then, and hire me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, now that I’m working from home, I bought a new
computer because I can deduct the price from my income as a business
expense.  Similarly I can deduct part of the interest on my mortgage
from my income.  And I’ll be making a fair bit more than I was getting
as a full-time employee, because of the lack of benefits, my inside
knowledge of the app, and finally because I have had only one raise in
the last seven years.  (It was hard for me to ask for a raise, because
I knew the company didn’t have a lot of money to give me a raise with,
and because I owned some of the company, so I would rather have seen
my shares increase in value than get extra cash in the short term.  Of
course neither ended up happening, but who could have foreseen that?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, there’s my tale of woe and hope.  It’s really not that bad,
apart from the sadness of seeing something that you worked really hard
for crash and burn.  But even in that sadness is the spark of
excitement for something new and different.  If you haven’t gotten
your first job yet, then I don’t know if this will help you all that
much.  I guess the main thing to take away from it would be that you
should cultivate contacts among your peers, profs, co-workers, and
clients because they’re the ones who will find you the good jobs, in
the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>job</category><category>phantom</category><category>search</category><category>work</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newjob/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 18:21:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>