<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about milestones)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/milestones.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Three!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/three/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cordelia is three!  She has been three for almost two weeks now!
We didn't have a big party or anything, because she doesn't
really have any friends yet, and also I couldn't be bothered.
I asked her what kind of cake she wanted and she said "a
tomato cake!"  Apparently there is such a thing, but I didn't
feel up to that kind of experimental weirdness, so I asked
her (on a different occasion) whether she would like a
chocolate cake or a white one.  (This is how you get little
kids to do what you want, you trick them and then you
paint them into a corner.)  She said she wanted a white cake
with chocolate icing (this is how they get what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; want).
And since she had been talking about having a tomato birthday
for months, I drew three juicy tomatoes on top of the
cake in red icing.  That seemed to satisfy her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn't have a party, as I mentioned, but a few people
did end up coming over for cake: Baba and Zaida were there,
and Tanya and Douglas and Ursa and Otis came too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordelia's choice for her special birthday dinner was sushi,
so Zaida kindly brought over a platter of sushi from our 
favourite place.  Extra kindly, because his car wouldn't
start!  He walked it halfway over to our place and
Blake met him and brought it the rest of the way.  What 
these men wouldn't do for their little girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordelia really seems to have bought into this three thing.
Her new favourite word is "why", in that reflexive way 
little kids ask when they're trying to get as much information
into their little brains as possible.  She has stopped 
fighting so much with Delphine, and is generally more
easy-going lately.  We don't lock horns so much over
silly things like which way her toast is sliced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her latest favourite book is a counting book called
"Ten Black Dots" by Donald Crews.  We've read it at every
nap and bedtime for the last week.  She likes to point 
at the dots and count them, which she now does perfectly,
even down to pointing to each dot exactly once.  She 
can also do rudimentary math in her head, adding or
subtracting one or two.  I said rudimentary!  Generally 
she seems more numerically-oriented than Delphine was
at her age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She's also really big!  Actually she's right on the 50th
percentile, but dammit, she seems big to me.  I'm still
coming to terms with the fact that my baby days are behind
me.  I know that means that also behind me are spit-up and
leaky boobs and diapers and baby gates and food allergy
scares and chokable object embargoes, and ahead of me are
piano lessons and baking together and interesting conversations
and going for walks and joking and reading and doing crossword
puzzles.  But I've been a baby-mummy for five years; it was
such a huge part of my life — it was my whole life! — for
such a long time and yet it's already over.  How can that be?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>birthdays</category><category>milestones</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/three/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 18:56:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordelia Grows Up</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/growsup/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
On Friday, Cordelia (who is two and eight months) decided she 
was done wearing diapers and wanted to wear underwear.  She has
decided to wear underwear before with mixed results, but 
this time she was really adamant about not wearing diapers,
not even pull-ups.  So she wore underwear, I accompanied her
to the bathroom after meals and her nap, and she went the 
whole day without an accident.  Saturday she had three
accidents but mostly because we weren't on the ball with
taking her to the bathroom at regular intervals.  
Notably, after her first accident, Blake (who didn't
yet understand the depth of her determination to 
wear underwear) tried to put her in a diaper and she
was mortified!  She was furious and miserable until I
explained to her that she could wear underwear and
everyone has accidents.  Since Saturday she hasn't had
any accidents.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On top of that, in Saturday we sold her crib, the one
the people at work bought for Delphine, and now Cordelia
is sleeping in the toddler bed.  She is big!  She 
will get really mad if you call her "little".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So that's it, I don't have any babies any more.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>milestones</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/cordelia/growsup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>