<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (moving)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/moving.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:12:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A few weeks in…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/monthone.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, itʼs been a couple of weeks, and thought I might write a few notes on how itʼs been going…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Laptop, now all stickered up…" src="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/Stickers.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/monthone.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>moving</category><category>update</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/monthone.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s here!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/weekone.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It arrived!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dude.  I got a Dell.  Not as much dragon, though…" src="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/MyDell.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/weekone.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrival</category><category>moving</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/weekone.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Welp, I did it.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/welp.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in a &lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html" title="My problems with the new MacBooks"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I wasn’t really excited by the new MacBooks that were announced this year.  And the more I read the less compelling they seemed…  As I talked with my co-workers, I heard some really good reviews of a couple of models of Windows computers, and since 90% of Firefox’s users are using Windows it’s probably not such a bad idea if I use it, too, both to help me understand the problems they’re running into, and to make sure that the code I’m writing will work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/welp.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>expectation</category><category>moving</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/welp.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moving to Windows…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/summary.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iʼm writing a series about switching to Windows, and thought it would be nice
to have a summary post, with links to all the other ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/summary.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>moving</category><category>summary</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/summary.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Settling</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/houseandhome/settling.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
People keep asking me if we're getting settled in,
and until today I was getting pretty tired of it,
because I really didn't feel all that settled.
Today, though, we moved a bunch of boxes out of
the living room and laid down the rug, cleared
the upstairs landing, and unpacked a couple of
big bins, and now it finally does feel like we're
getting settled, like this is really where we 
live and not just where all our stuff is.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course we still have a million things to
unpack, but we have been cleverly hiding boxes
in the basement rather than face them, and we
are managing quite nicely with the forty 
percent of our possessions that we have unpacked.
I have a grand plan for unpacking the rest 
which involves a large box labelled "Garage
Sale"; Blake and I will dig into that project
in the New Year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's a crappy little house (in some ways, and
in others it's wonderful), and sometimes I 
wonder why we bought it.  The kitchen needs 
redoing, the bathroom needs redoing (not to
mention there's only the one), the basement
isn't done at all... this house is a money sponge
capable of absorbing every spare
penny for the next two decades.  Why didn't we
buy one of the shiny, renovated perfect houses
with the dug-out, finished basements and the
second bathrooms and the nice kitchens?  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Money, for one thing; we didn't pay much for
this place.  But we're going to have to put more
than the difference back into it to get it up
to snuff.  The burning desire to be knee-deep
in plaster dust for the next five years?  A
passion to express myself through interior
design?  That can't be right.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't think that's the reason we bought
the house.
I think we fell in love with the
oldness of it, with the perfect trim and the
retro cabinets, and with the challenge of
taking this beloved old house and bringing it
up to date without erasing its character; 
deciding what to keep and what to take away.
Taking what is in a sense a blank slate and
making it our own.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We've got some pretty good ideas about keeping
the character while still beating the house
into twenty-first century submission.  We're
going to rip down a bunch of walls, but save
the trim and cleverly use it elsewhere:  we're
going to use the trim from between the living
room and the dining room to frame a huge
pass-through between the kitchen and the dining
room; we're going to use trim from one of the
doors to create an archway at the end of the
new front hall; we're going to use two doors
to make a headboard, and another to make a mirror
for the top of the stairs.  We're going to 
salvage the doorknobs and line them up on a
board to hang coats and hats on.  We're going
to patch the floors rather than refinish
(or replace) the hardwood.  And of course
I want to do the kitchen in a style reminiscent
of the fifties; I almost want the kitchen to 
look like it was installed in the fifties
and impeccably maintained, rather than to
look like a new kitchen with all the latest
fashions and gadgets.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think when we're done this first phase of
renovations, the house will be modern and
comfortable, with an open living space, lots
of light and air, a large, usable kitchen,
and new wiring and light switches in sensible
places, but it will still retain the patina of
age that we love.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>home</category><category>house</category><category>houseandhome</category><category>moving</category><category>status</category><category>unpacking</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/houseandhome/settling.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 03:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>