<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (ouch)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/ouch.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>When will I learn?</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ouch3.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I fell again, in a rather spectacular fashion.  I was
crossing St. Clair on Mt. Pleasant, and had just passed a
right-turning bus (on the left!  I’m not dumb enough to try to pass a
right-turning bus on the right!), and was signaling that I was going
to go back to the right-hand side of the lane (and therefore only had
one hand on the handles) when &lt;b&gt;*BUMP*&lt;/b&gt;, I hit a large ridge in
the road, which turned the tire sideways, and I went straight over the
handlebars, skidding to a stop near the curb.  My bike flew overtop of
me, crashing into a hedge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I got up, I noticed that the crash had apparently turned both my
front light and my bike computer around, which was quite a shock until
I realized that it was actually the whole handlebars which had gotten
turned around.  I spun it back and then just sort of stood there for a
while, catching my breath and calming down a little.  A lady driving
by asked me if I was okay, and if I needed a ride somewhere, but I
told her I was fine, which wasn’t entirely the truth.  My knees are
pretty much fine, a little scrape, perhaps.  My elbow is completely
ripped up, and even though I cleaned it thoroughly with soap and water
and a lot of scrubbing, it still looks pretty ugly, and is probably
going to scab up something awful.  Worse than that, my shoulder is
really sore again, in the same way that it was after &lt;a href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/Ouch2.html"&gt;my last fall&lt;/a&gt;, which can’t
be good.  I really need to get that looked at sometime.  The
&lt;i&gt;worst&lt;/i&gt; thing, however, is that I ripped the elbow of my &lt;a href="http://www.mec.ca/Products/product_detail.jsp?PRODUCT%3C%3Eprd_id=845524442618331&amp;amp;FOLDER%3C%3Efolder_id=2534374302692363&amp;amp;bmUID=1185298111978"&gt;cycling shirt&lt;/a&gt;.  Yeah, I can darn it, but darn it, I liked that
shirt!  But with every negative, there comes a positive.  The power
button on my Palm TX started working again.  Weird.  Maybe the next
time I fall, the sound will come back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in summary, signaling on a bicycle is bad!  No, not really.
Maybe the lesson is more that bumps in the road aren’t the greatest,
especially when you don’t have your hands on the handlebars.  Other
than that, I don’t really think I have any takeaways from this one.
That intersection of St. Clair and Mt. Pleasant is treacherous,
perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>biking</category><category>ouch</category><category>pain</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/biking/ouch3.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 17:41:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>So &lt;i&gt;that’s&lt;/i&gt; why 34-year olds don’t skateboard.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/pride.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;a href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/Arm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/small/Arm.jpg" align="right"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.creatingdance.com/jason.htm"&gt;friend of
mine&lt;/a&gt; (or more accurately, his parents) recently offered us an
air-conditioner.  A most welcome addition, given the silly heat levels
we’ve been experiencing, and the complete lack of any cooling
facilities in our house.  But that left me with the problem of how to
get it from their house to ours.  I could probably have carried it,
although it would have been really tough.  I might have been able to
borrow a bike trailer from someone (or fit it into the kid’s bike
trailer (more on that in an upcoming post), but I didn't really know
who, or where, and I kind of wanted to get it over here and hooked up
fairly quickly.  Fortunately, I remembered that I had seen a
skateboard amongst some old garbage a block away from my house, so I
walked over, and grabbed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in my younger days, I used to be quite the ‘boarder.  Okay, I
was never really that good at getting air, but I had no problems
getting around on it.  So I thought I’ld give it another try.  The
first push went well, and I glided along for a couple of meters,
before hopping off, feeling a little silly.  I walked to the end of my
street, and then thought about how cool it would look to cruise up to
the front door on the skateboard, so I put it down, and hopped on.
But this time, my front foot was facing forwards instead of sideways,
and when I tried to turn it (in Birkenstocks!), it sort of didn’t, and
back I went, landing flat on my ass, elbows, and shoulderblades.  I’m
fairly sure I didn’t hit the back of my head, at least not too hard,
and it was more my pride that was damaged than anything else, although
the muscles on the front of my neck are really rather sore.  It did,
however, answer one important question.  I’ve still got “it”, it’s
just been packed away and put in the basement, perhaps to be brought
out and given to my children in a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. It's even scabbier now!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dumb_stuff</category><category>ouch</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/pride.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 00:28:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>