<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (palm)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/palm.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Choices, choices...</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/choices.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;So I hit the Apple Store in the Eaton Center again today, to play
with the iPod Touch a little more, and now I’m kind of sad that I did.
There seem to be a few things about it that I don’t know if I can deal
with.  First, the screen apparently uses a &lt;a href="http://electronics.howstuffworks.com/ipod-touch2.htm"&gt;capacitive
screen&lt;/a&gt;, which basically means that you need to use your fingers to
touch it.  No slightly-longer-than-normal thumbnails, no left-over spare
stylii, nothing that could make the large surface area of my stubby
fingers slightly smaller.  This turned out to be a little annoying when
I was trying to type.  I would probably get used to it if it weren’t for
the second problem.  Very few of the apps seem to support landscape-mode
text input.  Where by "very few", I mean "only Safari".  The keyboard in
portrait-mode is just a little too small for my fingers.  Bah, who am I
kidding?  The keyboard in landscape-mode is just a little too small for
my fingers.  The keyboard in portrait-mode is way too small for my
fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I can’t really type on it.  That’s a fairly big problem.  But at
least I can download videos and music from my website, so that when I’m
at the office, and I see that my long DVD-to-iPod conversion has
finished, I can grab a copy of it over HTTP to watch on the commute
home…  But when I tried it, it was a total no-go.  None of the avis
worked, which isn’t totally surprising, but the mp3s in the same
directory also gave me the “Safari is unable to download this file”.
WTF?!?  An MP3 player that can’t play MP3s?  The biggest downside of
this whole trip is that I can’t really think of a good way around either
of those problems.  I mean, I guess text editors will come out which
allow landscape-mode keyboards, but it’s going to be annoying every time
I go to enter a new appointment, or contact.  And I don’t have any idea
what I could do to get around the no-downloading stuff. So I guess I’m
back to looking at other options (and maybe ending up asking Jeremy for
my SD Card back).  And no, I don’t think the Nintendo DS is a reasonable
replacement.  It’s too… game-y.  Not enough like an actual PDA.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>ipod</category><category>itouch</category><category>palm</category><category>touch</category><category>tx</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/choices.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 01:49:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Tale Of Woe</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/woe.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="left" src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/OrangePalmLogo.gif"&gt;&lt;img align="right" src="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/GreyPalmLogo.gif"&gt;A few weeks ago, I
was reading a pdf file on my Palm TX, when all of a sudden, it reset
itself.  Now, if that was the end of this story, then it would have been
slightly annoying, but nothing to post about.  However, that’s nowhere
near the end.  After resetting itself, it came back to the initial
orange Palm logo, as seen on the left, then it switched to the grey
PalmPowered logo, as seen on the right.  And there it sat.  And sat. And
sat…  The only thing I could consistently do is reset it, and every time
I did, it ended up on the grey screen, sitting there.  Soft resets,
debug resets, hard resets, zero-out resets…  Nothing could get it to
move past the grey screen.  On the off chance it was just taking a long
time to do its thing, I left it sitting overnight.  In the morning, I
opened it up expectantly finding… the grey screen again.  I read on the
internet that it might fix this problem if I left it sitting without any
power for a week, so I did, and the next time I plugged it it?  Yeah,
grey screen.  My heart was broken.  What could I do?&lt;br clear="all"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could call &lt;a href="http://www.palm.com/us/support/contact/canada_repair.html"&gt;Palm’s
tech support&lt;/a&gt;, and get a replacement!  It’ld only be $35 to get them
to ship one.  But when I called I found that I was way out of warranty.
Like, a year out of warranty.  So I decided not to go that route, since
it would be $150 to get it fixed, (or $185 to get the advance exchange,)
and I just don’t have that kind of money kicking around.  Then I
remembered that I had bought an extended warranty from the store, good
for a year after Palm’s warranty had run out, until Boxing Day of this
year.  Excellent, now I can just trade it in for a new one at the store.
But, I couldn’t find the receipt from two years ago, nor could I find
the credit card bill.  So I’ld have to figure out a way of getting them
to honour the warranty without knowing the warranty number.  That was
going to be hard, but in theory they had my information in their big
database, so it should be possible.  On the Monday morning, I was
checking through our filing cabinet one last time before heading off to
the store, and in the midst of a bunch of other receipts, (Why are we
keeping receipts for two year old meat purchases, anyway?  I’m pretty
sure that at this point, even if the meat was bad, we couldn’t return
it.) I found it!  So now, with all my ducks in a row, I left for the
store, &lt;a href="http://www.compusmart.com/"&gt;Compusmart&lt;/a&gt; at Yonge and
King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at the store, I was slightly surprised to find the doors
locked, and a notice up from the landlord, saying that this location was
closed.  Apparently, some time in the past two years, Compusmart had
decided to close all of its Ontario locations.  Well, great.  What the
heck do I do now?  Getting to the office, I hit the internet, found a
phone number, got redirected to a different phone number, and then spoke
with someone who checked my warranty number (convieniently printed on my
two-year-old receipt), and said that they’ld send me some email which I
should sign and fax back.  Since there were no more Compusmart stores
left in Ontario, they couldn’t exchange the merchandise, and so they
were going to buy it back from me for the purchase price of $400!  I was
elated, until I realized that, because I had already done an early
exchange on this unit with Palm to fix an unrelated problem, the serial
number on the back of the TX was different than the one they had on
file.  And I bet that’s the sort of thing you would check if you were
going to send out a $400 cheque.  I called them back, and asked what I
should do.  They replied that I would need to get some sort of proof
from Palm that I had traded in the one unit for the other.  After
another set of phone calls and emails, I eventually got a PDF from Palm,
listing the date, and the early advance exchange, and the two serial
numbers, which I proceeded to forward off to the warranty company.  And
now I’m waiting for them to update my policy and send me their buyout
agreement so that I can fax it back to them, send them my Palm TX, and
get my $400.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I’ve got one of those problems people don’t mind
having.  I’m trying to figure out what to spend the money on.  Should I
get another Palm TX, with infrared keyboard, for &lt;a href="http://www.softmagic.ca/_e/Palm/product/1047ML%2DBP3/%0APalm_TX_PDA_Handheld_w_WiFi_Free_Wireless_Keyboard.htm"&gt;$300&lt;/a&gt;?
Basically replace my current setup, and pocket the extra $100?  Or
should I get something &lt;a href="http://store.apple.com/1-800-MY-APPLE/WebObjects/canadastore.woa/"&gt;a little newer&lt;/a&gt;?  That back there is supposed to be a link to the
iPod Touch. Specifically, the 16 Gig version.  (It’s really not, but
let’s pretend it was.)  It’s going for $449, which is a fair bit more
than I’m getting a cheque for, but…  If I go to the &lt;a href="http://store.apple.com/1-800-MY-APPLE/WebObjects/AppleStore.woa/"&gt;
American Apple Store&lt;/a&gt;, I see that the price for the 16 Gig version
there is only $399 USD, or around $373 Canadian.  (Remind me, again, why
I’m paying $70 ($80 USD!) more for stuff just because I live in Canada?
Honestly, people, fix your freaking prices already!) And I know people
in the States who would be more than happy to ship it to me.  Heck, some
of them might even be coming up here for Christmas, and could just pack
it in their luggage.  Uh, where was I?  Oh, yeah, do I stick with the
devil I know, or do I go for the devil I don’t know?  I was leaning
towards the Palm TX recently, because there’s &lt;a href="http://www.macosxhints.com/article.php?story=2007092413051689"&gt;no
text editor/note taker&lt;/a&gt; for the iPod Touch, and you &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2007/09/10/apple-confirms-ipod-touch-cannot-add-appointments/"&gt;can’t create appointments&lt;/a&gt; in the Calendar
app, two things I kind of do a lot of.  But today I read about &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/mobiletextedit/"&gt;a text editor&lt;/a&gt;, and a
&lt;a href="http://www.modmyifone.com/forums/showthread.php?t=9507"&gt;way to
enable&lt;/a&gt; the missing add-appointments feature.  Then I was worried
that the best way to view a PDF would be &lt;a href="http://www.aimersoft.com/tutorial/download-dvd-pdf-youtube-videoto-ipod.html"&gt;to convert it to text&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="http://www.modmyifone.com/forums/showthread.php?t=2665&amp;amp;page=2"&gt;maybe not&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the thing that finally convinced me was &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/weboo/1547734040/"&gt;this picture&lt;/a&gt;.
Yeah, I’m a huge geek.  What can I do?  (&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/weboo/1557567120/"&gt;This picture&lt;/a&gt;
didn’t hurt either.)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>ipod</category><category>palm</category><category>touch</category><category>tx</category><category>warranty</category><category>woe</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/woe.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 00:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>