<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (random)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/random.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Meet the new blog, same as the old blog.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/microblog/newblog.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things I did over the holidays (so far) is upgrade the software that
powers &lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca"&gt;the blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/microblog/newblog.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blog</category><category>microblog</category><category>nikola</category><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/microblog/newblog.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Woo!</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/daemon.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It's 06/06/06, so I felt that I should really post something, but I
don't have much to say, and I'm going to &lt;a href="http://www.mec.ca/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt; for a Lunch-And-Learn, so this is going to be a really short
entry.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/daemon.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 21:28:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Remind you of anyone?</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/familiar.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bwinton.latte.ca/camera/weblog/MorgDel-Large.jpg"&gt;&lt;img align="right" src="http://bwinton.latte.ca/camera/weblog/MorgDel-Small.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I
was chatting with both &lt;a href="http://www.tantastik.org/"&gt;Tan&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://book.amberdragon.ca/"&gt;Kate&lt;/a&gt; recently, and they each
mentioned how much Delphine looked like me.  I completely agree, and
have the photo to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, that's not actually my sister and my daughter.  That's my
mother and I, circa 1976(-ish.  I'm guessing that I was three in the
photo).&lt;br clear="both"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/familiar.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 15:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Strange Conversations in IM</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/strangeconversations.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;pre&gt;[14:50] Skiff: о
[14:50] Skiff: привет
[14:51] Skiff: сообщения дошли?
[14:51] Coder: I'm afraid I don't speak Russian.  Perhaps you were looking for someone else? 
[14:51] Skiff: omg :)
[14:52] Skiff: do you have a GLATCO Credit Union enroll accounts?
[14:52] Coder: Nope. 
[14:53] Skiff: sorry
[14:53] Skiff: b
[14:53] Coder: No problem.  I get it all the time. 
[14:53] Coder: Have a nice day. 
[14:54] Skiff: thx :)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was odd.  Can anyone translate the stuff at the top, and
leave a comment letting me know what it says?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/strangeconversations.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2005 20:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Eye</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/annai.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.burstofbeaden.com/annai_hi.mov"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt;
is cute.  Really cute.  I'll have to play it for Delphine when I
get home.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/annai.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 20:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Parental Observations.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/earlyandlate.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, Amy, Delphine, and I went to meet some friends from New
York at the Distillery District.  Sadly, we just missed the bus at
King and Yonge which would have taken us there, which got me to
thinking.  Normally I'm an extremely punctual person.  In fact, I
usually show up five or ten minutes early to wherever it is I'm
supposed to be, with the expectation that I'll have to entertain
myself.  Since my Clie is with me all the time, and I usually have two
or three books on the go on it, I'm never worried about having
something to do while I wait.  (The one exception to this is hanging
around Delphine's day care.  I feel sort of like the strange man who's
a little too interested in your children.  Since I'll probably be
picking up Del for the next few months so that Amy can work a few more
hours, I should probably get over that, eh?)  Anyways, when I'm
travelling with Delphine, I'm much less likely to get somewhere early,
because she's much harder to keep amused for five or ten minutes than
I am, and so I cut my travelling time closer, and then sometimes miss
connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just something to keep in mind if you're ever meeting me
somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/earlyandlate.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 17:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Daycare Rock Star</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/daycarerockstar.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I go with Blake to drop off Delphine at daycare every morning, and one
morning one of the other toddlers, Claire-Marie, came running to him
and gave him a hug around the knees.  She's just huggy like that.
Then Antonio and Beniam decided
they wanted a piece of the hugging action, so they came over too, and
now every morning when the kids see Blake they all swarm him.  He's like
a rock star.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/daycarerockstar.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2005 17:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I'm sure it'll get better.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/worstdayever.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Wow!  This has started off as the worst day I've had in a very long time.
On my ride to work, someone walking past me snagged my headphone cord with
their purse, and yanked the cord out of both my ears, and my Clie.  Damn
did it ever hurt, and apparently broke my right headphone, since now no
sound comes out of it.  Then, I just missed the elevator, and no-one in it
was nice enough to hold the door for me.  Once I got to the office, I tried
to make oatmeal, but it boiled over in the microwave after a minute, so I
cleaned it up, and decided to cut my losses and just eat the slightly
crunchy gruel it's ended up as, and on my way back to my desk, I spilled
the cup of coffee I was carrying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm sure it'll get better as the day goes on, but at this point, I'm
just afraid of what'll happen next.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/worstdayever.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2005 13:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dammit!</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/miso.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been keeping a small tupperware full of miso paste in the
fridge at the office for the past few months.  It seemed like
something that I could use to supplement my lunches, or as a nice
alternative to coffee when I was in need of a hot liquid.  In
related news, I'm feeling a little under the weather today due to
being in the middle of a cold I got from my wife, or perhaps
daughter, and since all I have for lunch is a baloney sandwich,
and some salad, I thought that it would be the perfect thing to
clear my sinuses, and give me a little boost of wellness.
Hah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll be the first person to grant that miso paste looks a
little like something that's gone off, and it's nice that people
are clearing out the fridge, but man is that ever bad timing.
Worse, since payday isn't until today, and there wasn't enough in
the bank account for me to take out any spending money, so I
can't even buy an overpriced chicken noodle soup from the food
court.  So I ended up having a cup of coffee, but it just wasn't
the same somehow.  At least I got in early, so I'll be able to go
home in a couple of hours, and have some soup there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hah!  And just as I finished writing my tale of woe, it
started raining.  Man, what a day!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/miso.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2004 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Isn't this what weblogs are for?</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/isntthis.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://bbspot.com/News/2003/01/os_quiz.php"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.bbspot.com/Images/News_Features/2003/01/os_quiz/palm.jpg" width="300" height="90" alt="You are Palm OS. Punctual,
straightforward and very useful.  Your mother wants you to do more
with your life like your cousin Wince, but you're happy with who you
are."&gt;&lt;br&gt;Which OS are You?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found by &lt;a href="http://www.livejournal.com/users/dagbrown/"&gt;dagbrown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="media"&gt;[Listening to:  Break &amp;amp; Enter  -  Prodigy  -  (8:24)]&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>random</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/isntthis.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2004 22:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>