<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about resolutions)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/resolutions.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Year’s Resolutions…</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/newyears2015/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I managed to spend New Year’s Eve lying sick on the couch, and then went
to bed semi-delirious from lack of sleep at 12:08, which kind of sucked, but I’m
still hopeful that 2015 will be better than 2014 was.  I mean, it almost &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt;
to be, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, my first, and so far only, resolution is to consume less and create
more.  When I look back on the year, I find I have spent more of my free time
than I’ld like passively consuming other people’s content instead of making new
things of my own, and that kind of bothers me.  I’m very glad that a large part
of my job involves making things, and that has definitely been rewarding, but
there are also a lot of personal projects I want to start or finish or just push
forward.  And it doesn’t have to be code.  I’ld like to write more blog posts,
to explain the things I’m doing, and why they interest me enough to spend time
on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>new years</category><category>resolutions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/newyears2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 18:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hello 2009!</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/resolutions2009/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the last day of 2008. To celebrate, Blake and
I are watching the last episode of the latest season of
&lt;em&gt;Canada's Worst Driver&lt;/em&gt;, and hopefully going to bed
early.  Last night we stayed up too late and ended up
sleeping in, which made us late to go to the Art Gallery,
but more importantly made Blake hurry through his morning
routine and miss his cup of coffee, so I had to deal with
his bad mood all the way through the gallery.  It was
like dragging a recalcitrant donkey around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I digress.  This here is my New Year's Resolutions
post.  I meant to make one of these a year ago, but I
never got to it, which leads me to my first resolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog more&lt;/strong&gt;.  As you might have guessed from my
frantic book blogging of the last few days, I have a lot
more to say than I actually get around to saying.  Whether
that's a good thing or not is a matter of opinion, but
there's no point in having a blog if you don't post to
it.  Now that the girls are a little older, and now that
we have two computers (maybe three if we get the new 
router and the old Toshiba set up) I hope I can post at least
once at week.  That should allow me to, at least, keep on
top of the books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I alluded to the necessity of my next resolution above:
&lt;strong&gt;try to sleep from 11 until 7&lt;/strong&gt;.  I know, eight hours a 
night for a mother of two seems a little princessy, but
really the whole family is better off when I've had
my beauty sleep.  It also seems to me that I feel most
well-rested when I wake up at 7, and I have a pretty
good alert period in the late evening which I could
take advantage of if I stayed up until 11.  I read an article in
&lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt; a few years ago which said that everyone
has their own natural "time zone" (and so some people's
time zone doesn't fit into the 9-5 world, which gives
them a kind of societally-inflicted jet lag).  I think
11 to 7 works best for me — I'm just a little too cranky
when I wake up before 7.  Fortunately the girls sleep
that late most days.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This might be my last year of sleeping until 7 for a long
time, since next year Delphine starts Grade One and I'm
not sure if we can get out the door in time waking up at 7.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I'm going to try and schedule &lt;strong&gt;more playdates&lt;/strong&gt; for
Delphine.  She's a really social little kid and I know 
she would love to play with her friends more — I know
I would have when I was her age.  The only reason 
she doesn't is that I don't get around to scheduling
playdates for her.  So I'm going to try harder and
get her out there (or someone over here) maybe once
a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is a bit embarrassing, but here it is.  I have
a problem keeping my cat's water clean.  I tend to 
fill it up and then leave it for days while it gets
gnarlier and gnarlier until Thomas is obliged to
drink the leftover water in the bathtub.  To be
sure, Thomas contributes by doing everything in 
his limited power to drown pieces of kibble in the
water bowl, and by inexplicably flicking the water
out of the bowl and mucking up the tray his water
lives in.  Anyway, I need to just suck it up and
&lt;strong&gt;pick up Thomas's gross water bowl every day and replace it
with a clean one&lt;/strong&gt;.  How hard is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to &lt;strong&gt;talk to my mother more often&lt;/strong&gt;.  Before my 
dad died I talked on the phone with my mother maybe
every couple of weeks, which isn't often enough.  I 
should talk to her every couple of days at least, just
to touch base and chit chat.  Part of the problem is that
I just don't make the time to call, and part of the
problem is that my mother is incapable of ten minute
phone calls; every call turns into a hour-long 
extravaganza.  However, maybe if I called every day
my Mum wouldn't feel the need to keep me on the phone
forever?  Anyway, I make stupid excuses, like
I have two little kids and I'm tired and I have other
stuff to do, but of course those excuses won't hold
much water when my Mum is gone too and I've missed
a thousand opportunities to talk to her.  That would
be stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a gimme: I'm going to &lt;strong&gt;give up on
houseplants&lt;/strong&gt;.  I just can't do it.  My house is too
dark and I never remember to water them at the right
time, and I just don't care that much.  I have enough
trouble keeping three people and a cat alive.  The
houseplants are toast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a million books on hold at the library, but
 I have to &lt;strong&gt;catch up on my 
Neal Stephenson&lt;/strong&gt;.  I read &lt;em&gt;Cryptonomicon&lt;/em&gt; but I
haven't read any since then, and my geek cred is
severely suffering as a result.  I don't know if
I'm going to plough through &lt;em&gt;The Baroque Trilogy&lt;/em&gt; or
just skip straight to the latest one.  We'll see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>resolutions</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/everythingelse/resolutions2009/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 03:37:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>