<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (running)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/running.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>December Slump</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/decemberslump.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Today I ran for the first time in a month and a half.
I  signed up for the Resolution Run 5K on December
31 in an attempt to motivate myself to keep running
through the winter, but I didn't count on the move
joining forces with the cold weather to put me off
lacing up my sneakers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So between cleaning and packing and moving and
unpacking and being busy and exhausted, I haven't
been running.  It seems there are things I give 
up on when I am very busy, and things I don't;
the things I give up on are exercise, reading,
baking and cooking complicated meals.  The things
I don't give up on are watching TV, sleeping,
flossing, going to choir practice and seeing 
friends.  And eating — I hear there are
people who get so busy they forget to eat, but
that's never been an issue for me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I did, finally, go for a run today.  After the
collosal binge that is Christmas Day I was 
desperate to do something healthy, and I thought
I should test the waters to see how well I can 
expect to do at the Resolution Run on the 31st.
I did 2K today, and I didn't die; I made it through
the first ten minutes okay, although I started too
fast and almost wore myself out.  I had to take a
walk break in the second ten minutes, but only for 
half a block.  I think I should be fine in the
Run if I do five and ones or seven and ones.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now that we are getting settled in and it's no
longer imperative to spend every spare moment
unpacking, I am going to try and go out for two 
2Ks and one 5K every week.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/decemberslump.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 01:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>5K Again!</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/tenandone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
On Saturday I did a surprisingly easy 5K of ten and ones —
surprising because I ran exactly  no times the week before.  I 
guess some rest is what the doctor ordered.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Last night I went out in the drizzle and did another 2.5K of
ten and ones, and I thought about why I like running outside 
rather than in a treadmill: every time you go out, it's a 
new run, even if you are running the same old route.  Running
in rain is different from running in sun, is different from
running in snow is different from running three days after
it snows.  Running uphill is different from running downhill,
running on gravel is different from running on pavement is
different from running on asphalt.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you run on a treadmill the best you can hope for is that
the Seinfeld repeat is one you haven't seen lately.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/tenandone.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 18:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight And Ones, and Other Things</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/eightandone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I just got back from a 2.3K run of eight and ones.  It was hard;
I am still a little wheezy and having trouble catching my breath.
But I am quite pleased with myself for doing it; it was already
8:30 by the time I went out, and I really wanted to stay home
and sit on the couch.  We have our
condo on the market (anyone want a condo?) and I have spent the
last week cleaning and tidying like a fool instead of running
and sleeping and doing other sensible things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I haven't been keeping up with the homework for the Learn To
Run clinic; you are supposed to run three times a week but
I have only gone once this week and it's already Thursday
(clinic meets on Saturday).  This week we are doing 4.75K of
nine and ones and I am going to be suffering.  Hopefully, though,
now that the condo is clean and tidy I will be able to get back
to three runs a week.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And hey, back in June when I started all this foolishness I
wouldn't even have been able to &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; of running for
eight minutes without stopping.  So that's something.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/eightandone.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What's Next?</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/plan.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I feel strangely deflated now that my first run is behind me,
although I have another month to go in my running clinic to give me
something to work on.  (We are doing eight and ones next
weekend; how I am going to go from five and twos to eight and ones
I do not know).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think I will sign up for a 5K sometime this winter or early 
spring to keep me honest over the winter and give me something to 
aim for: I 
would like to improve my time by running for a larger proportion
of the time.  I will need some kind of external incentive because
I can really see myself forgetting about running altogether in
the chilly winter evenings.  Although I bet Michelle wouldn't let
me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the summer of '07 I will do two or three 5Ks, then
maybe another over the winter (if I feel like I need it to keep
my momentum up).  Then in '08 I'd like to do the Sporting Life
10K (because it's mainly downhill!) and the 10K in the zoo
(because the zoo is cool).
Maybe by '09 I'll be ready for a half-marathon, or maybe I will
do a couple more 10Ks, and do a half-marathon in '10... we'll see.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course this could be derailed by unforseen circumstances, but
so could any plan; no reason not to make it!
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/plan.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 01:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Done!</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/waterfront5k.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I did it, I finished my first run!  I did the Scotiabank Toronto
Waterfront 5K in 42 minutes, doing
intervals of two minutes of walking and five minutes of running.
It was a good pace, fairly challenging but not so hard that I felt
like I wasn't going to make it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It was cool to run in a real race, although there was a marked
difference between the 5K and the "real" races; we had little
kids, people with special needs, people who clearly intended to
amble the route (not that there's anything wrong with a nice
amble, but I'm not sure I'd choose Lakeshore for it).  There
was even a woman enjoying a nice, bracing cigarette before the
race began!  But hey, it was a good start and I'm really glad I
did it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/waterfront5k.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 01:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More Five and One</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/fiveandoneredux.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Five and ones have been kicking my ass lately and I don't know
why; the first couple of times were fine but ever since then
I have had that cruddy bronchitis feeling in my chest every time
I run.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For some reason I have been a complete slacker this week.  I ran
on Sunday, and I was going to run on Tuesday, Thursday, and
Saturday.  Then I didn't run on Tuesday because I was deathly
tired and felt kind of sick; so I planned to run on Wednesday
and Friday, and skip Saturday to rest up for my 5K on Sunday.
But on Wednesday we went to see a house in the evening; the
house was crap so I was grumpy and just felt like sitting on
the couch eating, so that's what I did.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So now it's Thursday and I just got back from a rather half-hearted
2.2K run, complete with that bronchitis feeling, but hey, at least
I ran.  I will run 2K on Saturday and go to bed early so I am nice
and fresh for the 5K on Sunday.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have to say, if this were a 5K run instead of a 5K run/walk I
would totally not be ready.  I have never run 5K; I have never
even run 4K -- we supposedly did a 4K run in the clinic last week,
but really everyone stopped running after 3.5K and walked the 
rest of the way.  Fortunately it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a run/walk, so I will do
five and twos and do my damnedest to keep up that pace for the
full 5K.  And &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; time I do a 5K I will do it at
ten and ones, so there.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/fiveandoneredux.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 01:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Increasing Intervals</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/intervals.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
This post started as a response to Jillian's comment in my last post;
my response started getting really long so I figured I would post it
instead.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here's what Jill said:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fives and ones. I am in awe. I'm still doing twos and ones. 
Although perhaps that's because I live in the boonies and drive everywhere.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Someday I'll get an interval timer so I don't have to look at 
my watch every three steps. That might speed me up a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hey, two and ones are better than, say, the none and nones I was 
doing before this!  I have been increasing my running time every 
week or so fairly religiously.  I talked with Blake about it and he 
agreed that there's no point in waiting until one time becomes 
"easy" before moving up.  I mean, I guess it gets easi&lt;em&gt;er&lt;/em&gt;
but never what I would call easy.  But then somehow the next step
up isn't all that much harder, and lo and behold here I am at
five and ones without ever feeling that I have over-exerted myself.
It's kind of weird, really.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Having a good timer must help a lot.  I am going to buy myself 
one of those cute little pink and purple Timex running watches as a 
reward for completing the 5K, I think (with my Running Room clinic 
coupon).  Right now I am using a hundred-year-old watch borrowed 
from Blake which only does one interval per set, so if I want to 
do five and ones I set it for six minutes, watch it obsessively 
for the first minute while I walk, and then run until it beeps.  
It does the trick for now, but it is neither pink and purple nor
cute.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="40%"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some opportunistic bacteria have taken advantage of my allergically 
stuffed-up sinuses and set up residence there so now I have added sore teeth
and joint pain and general all-over misery to my existing repertoire
of sneezing and stuffiness, ironically just in time for the ragweed
pollen count to go down.  What this has to do with running is that
I skipped my run last night, which wouldn't be so bad except I 
skipped my run on Sunday too, due to being lazy and full after a
big family dinner.  So now I have skipped two runs in a row and I
am beginning to get annoyed with myself.  I should really have gone
out on Sunday; perhaps even eaten less so I wouldn't have been
so lethargic!  Now there's an idea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was having a look at the 
&lt;a href="http://www.torontowaterfrontmarathon.com/en/images/stwmmarmap_big.jpg"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;
for the marathon I am not running on the 24th.  Notice how the 5K isn't
even shown on the map?  That's because the resolution of the map isn't
high enough to show the itty-bitty 5K route.  Damn, marathons are 
&lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt;!
I know, news at eleven, but look at that thing!  These people are running
all the way out to the Beaches, oh, but that's not far enough so on the way,
let's run &lt;em&gt;all the way down Leslie Spit&lt;/em&gt; and back, and oh hey, that's
&lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; not far enough, we have to double back all the way through 
downtown, past Roncesvalles, past High Park, to.. I don't even
know where that is!  Etobicoke?  Someplace I never go!  AND THEN
BACK DOWNTOWN!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Marathons are long, dude.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/intervals.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2006 13:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Five And One; Two Weeks To Race Day</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/fiveandone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Still running...  I am up to five minutes of running and one minute
of walking, and it's easier than I thought it would be.  My friend
Michelle said that, physically, it never got harder for her than
one and ones, which is heartening. And I have to say I agree,
so far.  Running five minutes isn't particularly harder than running
four minutes, which wasn't much worse than running three minutes...
In fact, I rather enjoy five and ones because five minutes is long
enough to really get into the running part.  With shorter intervals
I found I spent a lot of time wondering if it was almost time to
stop running yet, but you can't really do that for five minutes,
so instead you think about other things, houses and school and
work and life, and then when the beeper beeps telling you to walk
it comes as a pleasant surprise rather than something you have
been obsessing about for the last minute and a half.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The 5K run (I hate to call it a "race" since I am not running
for speed, just completion) that I signed up for is on the
24th.  So far the farthest I have run is 3.75 K, but I am not
too worried about going 5K.  I will try and run it (with walking
breaks) and if I can't manage it I will walk it in.  No harm done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Learn To Run clinic I am taking is getting a little lamer; 
there was one really cool girl who dropped out two weeks ago, 
and now the only people I want to talk to are really fast, so
I am stuck at the back running with boring, annoying people who 
act like they are
doing me a favour running slow with me.  I think it's actually harder
to run with someone boring than to just go by myself.  To add
insult to injury,
the instructor seems to think that I need lots of encouragement
and chivvying along; "How are you doing?  Are you okay?  You can
walk if it's too hard."  Just because I am fat doesn't mean I am
out of shape, lady, I walk more in a day than most of you do in
a week;  I think everyone in the clinic drives there except me.
Ah well, I didn't get into this to make friends.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/fiveandone.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 13:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Running With A Friend, and Some Other Things</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/threeandone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I went running last night with my friend Michelle, my real-life
inspiration for all this perspiration.  It was the first time I
have been running with someone else, apart from the clinic.  It
was easier than running alone; the time goes a little faster.
We chatted about this and that and she gave me some hard won
running tips.  (Breathing is good!)    She is training for a
half-marathon which means she runs for, like, multiple hours
at a time, and is doing hill training and real athletic things
like that.  That's so cool!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since I was running with company (company, moreover, with a
fancy interval-timing watch) I decided to try three-and-ones 
for the first time.  The first set was fairly hard but we
slowed down a little and the rest were quite doable, if a
smidgen on the long side.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Running with someone was fun, but running alone is nice, 
too — it's good to have some
time alone with myself.  I think it will be less pleasant as I
increase my running time; I imagine it will be harder work and I
will find it more difficult to keep my mind off the pain, or
maybe the boredom.  Perhaps that is when I will treat myself to
an iPod.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm back in a Learn To Run clinic again; last Saturday was
the first meeting.  Obviously, since I attended the first two
weeks of the last clinic before my injured knee forced me to
drop out, it was all familiar material.  The run portion was
a cakewalk for me since it was two minutes walking, one minute
running, although we were running a little faster than I have
been.  I hit it off with another girl and we ran quite far behind
everyone else.  She was embarrassed but I didn't care; better to
run slow and keep running than to run fast, save face, and hurt
yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/threeandone.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2006 17:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two and Ones</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/twoandone.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm into two and ones, two minutes of running and one
minute of walking.  I've been for two runs at that pace
and they have been hard but not impossible.  I had to
consciously slow myself down so that I would be able
to get through the two minutes a couple of times, and
some of those one minute breaks seemed pretty short,
but I've managed.  I think I will do another couple of
runs at this pace before I move to three-and-ones; so
far I have only done two-and-one in the blistering 
heat and humidity, so I am curious to see how they are
in reasonable weather.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also next weekend my Learn To Run clinic (second
attempt) begins; they will start back at one-and-twos
so I will be in great shape for that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I continue to shock myself with how motivated I am
to run, but I know why.  I usually exercise because
I knew I should exercise, because it's Good For Me.
I don't know what the human aversion is to
doing things just because they're Good For You, but
it definitely exists:  I hated to exercise and would
create all kinds of excuses not to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But running has managed to elude being categorized
as exercise in my brain; somehow it seems to have
slipped into some kind of Hobbies and Activities
category.  I run for the sake of running, not for
the exercise or because it's good for me or to lower
my cholesterol or lose weight.  I run so that I 
can run more, so
that I get better at it, so that I can do a 5K in
September.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So much so, in fact, that when I noticed my shorts
were getting a little looser it took me a while to
think that, yeah, it's probably because of the
running.  I actually thought, surely twenty minutes
of running three times a week wouldn't make that 
much difference.  But I haven't changed anything
else, so that must be it.  (Unless I do have some
wasting disease, which was my first thought.)
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>running</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/amy/motion/twoandone.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 02:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>