<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about school)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/school.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Cordelia is...</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;...independent!  We had Cordelia's parent-teacher "chat" today,
with her nursery school teachers.  I love talking about my 
children, so I was very excited to be there, and of course Blake
doesn't have a job so he came along 'coz he doesn't have anything
else to do.  Just kidding; he had taken the morning off to
come anyway, before the company folded (or whatever it's in
the process of doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simone and Sameera were very happy to talk about Cordelia too.
Apparently she's a delight at school.  (I bet they say that
to all the parents.)  She's very independent; she puts on
her own outside clothes and clears up after snack by
herself.  This is a revelation to me because like idiots 
we're still helping her on with her snowsuit and boots,
and begging her to take just one thing into the kitchen
after meals.  Suckers, we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her favourite things are sensory activities:
playdough, cornstarch, sand.  Anything messy.
She's still focused to the point of being oblivious to
what's going on around her (she gets that from Blake),
and she's happy playing by herself, to the point that
her teachers are actually engineering situations to
force her into talking and playing with other kids.  They
are going to hook me up with some good playdate matches
for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's their only concern for kindergarten, that she
won't be able to make connections with other kids and
with the teacher.  Academically, in terms of colours,
shapes, letters and numbers, she's just fine!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cordelia</category><category>development</category><category>school</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/amy/girls/cordeliais/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 13:35:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First Day of Senior Kindergarten</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/firstdaysk/</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday was Delphine's last day of summer vacation.
We stuck labels on her &lt;a href="http://www.landsend.com/pp/SolidClassMateJuniorBackpack~146384_-1.html?bcc=y&amp;amp;action=order_more&amp;amp;sku_0=::PRO&amp;amp;CM_MERCH=IDX_00004__0000000491"&gt;new backpack&lt;/a&gt;, 
lunch bag and 
&lt;a href="http://zeta.zappos.com/product/7319163/color/16179"&gt;shoes&lt;/a&gt;, and speculated about her new teacher, which
of last year's kids would be in this year's class, and 
whether the JKs would be cute or not.  While we were
eating lunch I wondered how we had felt on the same day last
year, Delphine's last day before Junior Kindergarten. 
Were we excited, were we nervous?  I don't know, and I
never will because I never wrote it down.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year Delphine was a little nervous.  She was 
scared that the teacher wouldn't like her, although
that fear was largely soothed by the arrival of a 
lovely letter from Mrs Thompson to Delphine (in the
mail, no less!)  saying how excited she was to 
meet Delphine and what fun they would have in 
kindergarten, learning letters and numbers.  Delphine
was a bit offended by that last bit — "I already
know letters and numbers!" — but I said Mrs T
probably sent the same letter to the SKs and JKs, 
who might not know their letters and numbers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, too, was a little nervous, probably more so than
last year because this year I know what is coming —
a lot of getting people places on time and not much
time in between to take stock.  But only a little
nervous, because this year I do know what's coming,
and I have a plan, and perhaps most importantly I
have accepted that taking people places is my main
job during the school year (well, along with feeding
and clothing them), and anything else I can
get done apart from that is pretty much bonus.  So
rather than regarding the commuting as an inconvenient
interruption to my life, I now just go along with it.
Think of all the exercise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine's first day of school was last Wednesday.
She's still in afternoons, and she's in the same classroom
as last year, and as it turns out, all the Seniors were
in her class last year.  The first day of school
was only Seniors, so she got to renew some old friendships
and get to know her new teacher.  Delphine loves Mrs Thompson!
Mrs Thompson smiles a lot, and on the first day she wore a pink
dress — I don't know if that was calculated to win the
favour of a roomful of five-year-old girls (the Seniors
are six girls and two boys) but if it was, it worked.
Delphine says Mrs Thompson does everything in the
wrong order (which is to say, not the way Mrs
Hollister did it) but she seems willing to indulge her
errors.    Mrs Thompson taught her a new song!
In fact, yesterday Mrs Thompson taught her the 
Macarena!  And they say public schooling is inferior!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delphine has now had four days of SK.  She wasn't
impressed by the JKs on day two — they were noisy
and talked too much — but yesterday she kind of made
friends with one of them.  She had gym on Thursday 
(her teacher's name is Mr Laundry!  Actually it's
Mr Landry, but 'Mr Laundry' cracks her up) and Library
on Friday, and everything seems to be going fabulously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Delphine learned to read over the summer, and
SK/Grade 1 is supposed to be when you learn to read,
I'm going to talk to Mrs Thompson about what, if any,
other goals Delphine should work towards over the 
school year, and what kinds of enrichment she can
offer her.  She's beyond the basic "k-k-k-kite"
Jolly Phonics stuff this year, so I hope we can manage
not to bore her out of her tree.  Especially 
considering there are only eight SKs.  But I'm
borrowing trouble, I'm sure we'll work something out.
Now it's time to make lunch and haul everyone off to
school, at least once I manage to get some clothes
on Cordelia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>delphine</category><category>school</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/firstdaysk/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 18:59:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>