<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (seven)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/seven.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 18:09:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Seven Things You Probably Didn’t Know About Me</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/seventhings.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My life, such as it is, is pretty much an open book.  I’m not a very
complicated person, so I don’t know if I can find seven things that the
average reader of this blog probably doesn’t know about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, that’s no reason not to try.  So, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had two jobs that didn’t pay me.  After the first, I swore that if
   an employer didn’t pay me again, I would quit, but this last time they
   laid me off before I found out that I wasn’t getting paid.  The most
   recent company swears that they’re trying to get me my money, but I’m
   not going to hold my breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hated country music from the first time I heard Billy Ray (father of
   Miley) Cyrus until Elizabeth Campbell sent me a CD full of the good
   stuff.  So now the only kind of music I don’t like is “New Country”.
   And Schönberg.  &lt;em&gt;Der Mondfleck&lt;/em&gt; sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know enough Visual Basic to write a compiler for it, but you will
   never &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; see it on any of my resumes.  &lt;em&gt;Ever&lt;/em&gt;!  My policy is to only
   put on my resume things that I would enjoy working with on a day-to-day
   basis, and VB definitely isn’t one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am almost every link but for one in the first 5 pages of Google
   results for “Blake Winton”.  I guess that’s one of the benefits of being
   on the Internet for 17 years.  (Well, kinda.  Amy has been online as
   long as I have, but doesn’t show up until page 8 of the results for her
   name, mainly because of the Unicorns-riding-fairies artist who shares
   her name.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a quarter of a cow in our downstairs freezer.  Well, quite a bit
   less now that Amy and I have eaten a bunch of it.  We split half a cow
   with some friends, and it arrived pre-chopped up, so we’ve been having
   at least one beef dinner per week, and often two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I download, watch, and enjoy, American Idol.  Less so, now that we’re
   out of the “Simon says snarky things to really bad singers”, and into
   the “Simon says snarky things to Ryan”, but it’s still enjoyable.  (Go
   Alexis Grace!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first hard drive wasn’t actually 5 Meg, as I like to claim.  My
   father bought two hard drives, and took the 5 Meg one to the office,
   leaving the 10 Meg one at home.  The story about having 11 Meg of RAM is
   true, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay, that’s my seven.  There were a few more I could think of, but I’m
glad &lt;a href="http://blog.codekills.net/archives/50-Seven-Things.html"&gt;David&lt;/a&gt;
didn’t run across the 25-things-about-you version, since then I would have
had no choice but to resort to things you probably don’t want to know about
me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of disbelieving in bad luck, I will now tag no-one, thus
breaking the chain.  (Although, if any of you are feeling verbose, feel
free to pick up the meme and post a list of your own.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>seven</category><category>things</category><category>wolever</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/seventhings.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 02:30:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>