<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (sleeping)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/sleeping.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Saddest Thing In The World.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/sleeping/thesaddestthing.html</link><dc:creator>Amy Brown</dc:creator><description>#datetime 6/8/04 14:55
&lt;p&gt;
We've decided to teach Delphine to sleep by herself in a crib.  I guess I
knew that this day would come eventually, but I had hoped that she would
decide to sleep on her own, uh, on her own.  Or at the very least to be
able to understand why we were leaving her alone, and to try to work with
us at least a little.  But she didn't, and isn't, and so she cries and
cries, and it breaks my heart to not be able to go and pick her up and hold
her and cuddle her until she's all better.  But I know that that wouldn't
teach her that she's okay sleeping on her own, so I restrain myself.  On
the other hand, I can't help but wonder whether not going to her is just
teaching her that she can't depend on us for help and comforting when she
needs it.  Being a father is really hard sometimes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Update: For the past two nights, she hasn't woken up when we put her to
bed, and so has ended up sleeping through the night.  Here's hoping that
this is a trend that continues.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Update #2: It didn't.  She woke up and cried at 4:00 am this morning.  But
I think she might be getting a new tooth, and in pain.  I would normally
give her Tylenol, but it wouldn't last through the night, so that plan is a
non-starter.  Maybe I'll suggest it if she wakes up again.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>sleeping</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/delphine/sleeping/thesaddestthing.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2004 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>