<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (together)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/together.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:16:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 5.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine5.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;And today it all fell apart.  Instead of pre-preparing dinner when
Delphine was at kindergarten, I read my book, and watched The Daily
Show.  As a result, the salmon casserole was nowhere near ready at
5:00, and indeed, wasn’t ready until about 6:30.  So Delphine had
chicken noodle soup, billion-grain toast (I’m serious, there’s no
flour in this freakin’ bread.  It’s all just seeds and nuts packed
together somehow!), and some cherry tomatoes which my parents brought
over last night (in exchange for the apple cake and apple pie and ice
cream).  And after we went out for fish &amp;amp; chips for lunch, too.
Thank god for the tomatoes, or I’ld feel like a completely bad
parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I’m off to read some more (by which I of course mean watch
some more TV), before turning in for the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>delphine</category><category>together</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine5.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 01:11:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 4.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine4.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, today is coming together much better than yesterday did.  I
just skipped the Starbucks, and came home from kindergarten, stopping
off at Valumart to pick up a couple of pie shells.  Oh, yeah, this
morning, Delphine and I made an apple cake, but our &lt;a href="http://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/sku3993557/index.cfm"&gt;bundt pan&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t nearly large enough, so we were left with a ton
of apple filling.  I threw it into a (store-bought, shhh!) pie shell,
cut the other shell into strips, and made a nice lattice on top, and
I’m now baking it at 350º for 25 minutes.  (I totally guessed at the
time and temperature.  I suppose I should go look it up in Betty
Crocker, huh?  Damn, did I ever mess that one up!  Betty says 425º for
40-50 minutes, with foil around the edges and stuff.  Good thing I
checked.)  Easy-peasy (even with the foil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I think I’m going to end this entry now, and go sit on the
couch and read my book.  &lt;span style="font-size:x-large"&gt;Mu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:large"&gt;hu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium"&gt;heheha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small"&gt;hahaha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:x-small"&gt;haha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:xx-small"&gt;hahaaaaa&lt;/span&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>delphine</category><category>together</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine4.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 18:10:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 3.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine3.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, kindergarten.  After dropping Delphine off, I went to
Starbucks, grabbed myself a latte, and sat and started to read my
book.  Sadly, the presence of two wasps flying past my head sort of
ruined my quite interlude, and I headed on home.  When I was here, I
managed to check my email, increment the laundry (you all use that
term too, right?  When you put the stuff from the dryer into the
basket, the stuff from the washer into the dryer, and stuff from the
dirty hamper into the washer), and hang the wet load out in the
backyard.  Yeah, apparently when Amy isn’t home I get all domestic.
Who’lda thunk it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even given that, I really seem to have less free time than I
thought I would.  Somehow, between checking email and the various
household chores, I haven’t been able to read as much of my book as I
would have wanted, much less write the specs/code that I was hoping
to.  Ah well, perhaps I’ll get used to the routine by Friday, or maybe
I’ll just put those tasks on pause until I get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>delphine</category><category>together</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine3.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 01:29:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 2.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine2.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Today seemed a little more in control than yesterday.  I was really
slacking yesterday, doing as little housework as I could possibly
manage.  Today I got a load of laundry done, and hung up in the
basement, and I would be on my second load, but apparently the door
didn’t close, or something, and so the load was completely dry when I
went to check it after dinner.  Dinner was another thing I handled a
little better.  Since my father and sister were coming for dinner, I
made chili from around 3:00 until 4:00, and let it sit on the stove on
low, mellowing.  It turned out really well, I think, and there are some
leftovers.  Delphine and I also made some Rice Krispie Squares that
afternoon (I made them, she licked the various implements), so we had a
fun dessert as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really looking forward to tomorrow, though, since I’ll have two
fairly large blocks of free time, in which to attempt to beat the house
into something approaching shape.  The kitchen really needs a cleaning,
there are three more loads of laundry to do.  (Four if you count the
failed attempt in the washing machine.)  In the morning, I’ve got to
make sure that Delphine has all the stuff she needs for kindergarten.
Okay, that’s not actually something I can do in the blocks of free time,
but I figured since I was listing all the stuff I need to get done, I
might as well just slip it in there.  And on that note, I think I’ll be
off to try and get another couple of things done before I head to
bed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>delphine</category><category>together</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine2.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:50:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blake and Delphine’s Excellent Week Together – Part 1.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine1.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Amy and Cordelia left for Saskatchewan at 6:30 this morning, and so
Delphine and I got to spend the whole day together.  The first of
seven.  It’s going pretty well so far, I think.  We played together in
the park this morning: digging in the sand, flying kites, and kicking
a soccer ball.  We got home, and had some leftovers for lunch (grilled
cheese and pizza, both heated in the toaster over), then watched the
obligatory Charlie and Lola show, and read some books.  Ooh, we also
had banana/frozen-strawberry/milk smoothies for afternoon snack.  They
were really good, and a convenient way to get some fruit into our
bodies.  After hanging out a little, we went to the grocery store,
grabbed the week’s worth of groceries, and headed home.  So I thought
I’ld take a few minutes to write a quick blog entry while I’m cooking
dinner (frozen President’s Choice vegetable lasagna).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinner was tasty, and Delpine liked it, even though she started off
saying “I’ve had this before at daycare, and I don’t like it.”.  Then
we looked for recipes for apple cake, found one, and headed off to
bed.  And now I’m not entirely sure what I’m going to do for the rest
of the evening.  I suppose there’s a FIFA Women’s World Cup game I’ve
got taped, or I could watch a video about Haskell by Simon
Peyton-Jones, but I dunno, neither of those seem to really be grabbing
me.  Ah well, I’m sure I’ll figure something out.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blake</category><category>delphine</category><category>together</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/family/theweekofdelphine1.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 23:50:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>