<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (Posts about tv)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/tv.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:03:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Whatever will I do without trashy TV?!?</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/hdtv/</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s official.  I just cancelled my cable service, effective
January 23rd.  I found that for the past few weeks, I really haven’t
been watching anything worth while, and $96.22/month is a lot to spend
to have the only thing on be the HD version of &lt;a href="http://www.nbc.com/American_Gladiators/"&gt;American
Gladiators&lt;/a&gt;.  (No, seriously, that’s what I’m watching right now.
Pity me.)  I’ld like to say that it’s the writer’s strike, and the
resulting lack of decent shows, or that I’m getting smarter and the
shows are appealing to me less and less, but really it’s just gotten
too expensive for the value I’m getting out of it.  Heck, maybe I’ll
take half of that money, and buy a couple of DVDs every month.  But
we’ll probably use it to pay down the Line of Credit that financed the
deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember the last time I didn’t have cable of some sort,
and so I’m not really sure how I’ll be occupying my time.  Reading
books?  Reading the Interweeb?  Programming?  It’s a blank slate.
It’s all up in the air.  And if I end up spending all my time at my
sister’s house, watching her TV, then we’ll know I’ve got a bad
addiction, and should seek professional help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I should also mention that the person on the other end of the
line was &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; nice.  She tried to figure out a way for me to
pay less, and still get the channels I wanted, (the best deal was
$19.95/month for channels 2-28 and 59-70, but that was only for 6
months, and it’s still $20/month I would rather spend elsewhere,) but
totally wasn’t pushy about it and was fine with me cancelling the
service outright.  I picked up the dial phone when they called me back
for the customer satisfaction survey, and so couldn’t complete it, but
I did want to make a mention of how helpful she was, and how well it
all went.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cancelling</category><category>hd</category><category>hdtv</category><category>tv</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/random/hdtv/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 02:05:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>