<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog-O! (wiki)</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="https://weblog.latte.ca/tags/wiki.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 17:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Sprinting on DrProject.</title><link>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/drproject/codesprint.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday and Saturday afternoon this week, I took some time out of my
day to go down to the University of Toronto and participate in the &lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/"&gt;DrProject&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/DrProject/mail/5059"&gt;Code Sprint&lt;/a&gt;.  It
was a lot of fun, and I managed to fix a couple of bugs, and get a better
understanding of one of &lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/DrProject/browser/trunk/drproject?file=wiki"&gt;the hairier parts&lt;/a&gt; of DrProject.  At least I hope it’s one of the
hairier parts of DrProject, since if the whole codebase is as ugly as the
wiki parts, we’re in some serious trouble.  To be fair, it’s a
not-entirely-deterministic parser for a not-entirely-deterministic
language, so when something goes wrong, it’s kind of, uh, tricky to figure
out what’s just happened.  For example, after parsing a link surrounded in
square brackets, the following character seems to be &lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/DrProject/ticket/1075"&gt;treated as
text&lt;/a&gt;.  Why?  Who knows.  As someone new to the wiki parser, I’ld love
to have the code be simpler to understand, but I’m starting to suspect that
the complexity is inherent in what it’s trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two bugfixes/feature additions I did, although they seem sort of unrelated, both work
together to let people create a bibliography/set of footnotes to pages,
which is something &lt;a href="http://pyre.third-bit.com/blog/"&gt;Greg&lt;/a&gt; said
that he’s been wanting for a while, so that was kind of cool.  It’s nice to
be able to go somewhere, be surrounded by smart people, and concentrate on
making something better without interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the bugfixes, they were:
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/DrProject/ticket/870"&gt;adding
support for dl/dt/dd&lt;/a&gt; in the wiki syntax, which turned out to be
surprisingly hard, since it seemed to be the first bit of syntax that
wanted to either return more than one tag or insert a tag into the
already-generated stream, so I had to figure out which option to go with,
and how to get it working, and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;coming up with and implementing a wiki syntax for &lt;a href="https://www.drproject.org/DrProject/ticket/1038"&gt;creating and referring to anchors&lt;/a&gt; in a page, which I think I did a
pretty decent job on.  The syntax uses [wiki:#foo] as an anchor, and
[wiki:MyPage#foo] as a link to that anchor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bugs</category><category>drproject</category><category>parser</category><category>sprint</category><category>wiki</category><guid>https://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/drproject/codesprint.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 02:14:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>