<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Blog-O! (windows)</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/windows.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 15:40:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Welp, I did it.</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/welp.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in a &lt;a href="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/mac/disappointment.html" title="My problems with the new MacBooks"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I wasn’t really excited by the new MacBooks that were announced this year.  And the more I read the less compelling they seemed…  As I talked with my co-workers, I heard some really good reviews of a couple of models of Windows computers, and since 90% of Firefox’s users are using Windows it’s probably not such a bad idea if I use it, too, both to help me understand the problems they’re running into, and to make sure that the code I’m writing will work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on Friday I bit the bullet and ordered a Dell &lt;a href="http://www.dell.com/ca/p/xps-15-9550-laptop/pd?oc=nxps15550_bt_h1609e&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;s=dhs" title="Link to the Dell Store"&gt;XPS 15&lt;/a&gt; (with Touch screen, 32Gb RAM, and a 1Tb SSD) for my latest laptop refresh.  I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; that the recent updates to the &lt;a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/wsl/2016/04/22/windows-subsystem-for-linux-overview/" title="Windows Subsystem for Linux"&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux&lt;/a&gt; will let me do all the same Unix-y stuff I’ve been doing on the Mac, and if I use the same keyboard and trackpad, I’m not sure I’ll notice much of a difference, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dude.  I’m getting a Dell." src="https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/images/blake/Dell.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be a few weeks before it arrives, which is nice because it lets me think about all the stuff I’ll need to transfer over, and because it lets &lt;a href="http://exple.tive.org/blarg/2016/11/14/switching-sides/" title="Switching Sides"&gt;Mike Hoye&lt;/a&gt; go through all the pain of switching before I do, so I can hopefully avoid the worst pitfalls.  😉  There is, of course, a &lt;a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Transitioning_to_Windows#Applications_.26_tools" title="Transitioning to Windows"&gt;guide to switching&lt;/a&gt; for Mozilla people, but it’s pretty out of date.  I’ll probably be updating it as I run into stuff, and hopefully the other people who are also switching will do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here’s the big list of stuff I currently use, and replacements (where I know what they are):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, the obvious ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://slack.com/" title="Slack"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/" title="Firefox"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.twitter.com/products/twitter-for-windows/" title="Twitter for Windows"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crashplan.com/en-us/" title="Crashplan"&gt;Crashplan&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Crashplan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/browser/desktop/index.html" title="Chrome"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, the slightly more complicated ones: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://iterm2.com/" title="iTerm 2"&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ &lt;a href="http://cmder.net/" title="λcmder"&gt;Cmder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    Cmder isn’t the same, but it’s the best Windows terminal app I’ve found.&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: I might go with &lt;a href="https://conemu.github.io/" title="ConEMU"&gt;ConEMU&lt;/a&gt;, the program underlying Cmder, instead. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/safari/" title="Safari"&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Also Chrome.  Or maybe &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/microsoft-edge" title="Microsoft Edge"&gt;Edge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
    I use Safari mostly for YouTube.  I used to use Chrome for this; maybe I’ll go back, or maybe it’s time to try a new browser.  I hear Edge has really good battery life while watching video…  🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://atom.io/" title="Atom"&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Atom (or &lt;a href="http://code.visualstudio.com/" title="Visual Studio Code"&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;br&gt;
    I’ve heard not-great things about Atom on Windows, so I’m starting to look into switching to Visual Studio Code.  So far it seems okay…  I do miss the minimap and &lt;a href="https://atom.io/packages/atom-whimsy" title="Atom Whimsy"&gt;Whimsy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/home" title="Dropbox"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ Dropbox (or &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/" title="Google Drive"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.getcloudapp.com/" title="CloudApp"&gt;CloudApp&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;br&gt;
    Mozilla moved to Google Apps for our email, and now we have a big shared space there.  Should we really still be paying for Dropbox Pro accounts for our team?  Maybe not…  Of course, I don’t think Google Drive uploads screenshots automatically, so maybe I’ll also need to install CloudApp for that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://secure.flyingmeat.com/acorn/" title="Acorn"&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; ⇒ &lt;a href="http://www.getpaint.net/index.html" title="Paint.net"&gt;Paint.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    Totally not the same, but I think paint.net will do &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of the stuff I want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that is the software I’m unsure about alternatives for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://limechat.net/mac/" title="LimeChat for Mac"&gt;LimeChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    I’ve been looking for a while, but still haven’t found a beautiful IRC client for Windows.  (Please don’t suggest mIRC, or irssi over ssh…  Anyone who considers those “beautiful” clearly doesn’t share my aesthetic. 😝)  The closest I’ve found has been &lt;a href="http://fooirc.com/#!index.md" title="Foo IRC"&gt;Foo IRC&lt;/a&gt;, but I’m not sure how well it works.  For some reason I had a pinned tab open on &lt;a href="http://www.icechat.net/site/" title="IceChat"&gt;IceChat&lt;/a&gt;’s page, but I’m not a big fan of how it looks…&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-ca/store/p/irc-explorer/9wzdncrdkmgz" title="IRC Explorer"&gt;IRC Explorer&lt;/a&gt; looks pretty nice, too… &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail.app&lt;br&gt;
    I’m not really enthused with Apple’s Mail app, but it’s not terrible.  I hear Microsoft’s Mail app is pretty similar, so I’ll give it a try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://xscopeapp.com/" title="XScope"&gt;XScope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    I don’t think there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; anything like XScope on Windows 10.  I might just have to go back to my Mac for the kinda stuff I use it for…
    &lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="http://ngwin.com/picpick" title="PicPick"&gt;PicPick&lt;/a&gt; looks like it might do some of the stuff XScope does…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And things I just don’t know about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Calendar.app&lt;br&gt;
    I’m sure there’s &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; on Windows that does calendaring, but will it connect to my home iCal account?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://culturedcode.com/things/" title="Things"&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    I don’t use this a ton these days, but it’s good for keeping track of what’s on my plate.  I may just continue to use it on my iPhone…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/itunes/" title="iTunes"&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    I don’t think &lt;a href="http://www.winamp.com/" title="WinAmp"&gt;WinAmp&lt;/a&gt; or iTunes for Windows are really what I’m looking for here.  I might switch to a combination of &lt;a href="https://play.spotify.com/search/hamilton%20mixtape" title="Spotify"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and my iPhone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://anvilformac.com/" title="Anvil for Mac"&gt;Anvil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    Do I still need to run folders as websites?  Maybe not so much these days, since I’m using &lt;a href="http://webpack.github.io/" title="Webpack"&gt;webpack&lt;/a&gt;a lot more, and it comes with a dev server. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://qsapp.com/" title="Quicksilver"&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    I think I could probably use the Cortana search menu for most of what I use Quicksilver for…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trankynam.com/atext/" title="aText"&gt;aText&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    This is another one of those “There &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be something like this” apps, but I have no idea what it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suggestions for any of the apps mentioned above would be very appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>expectation</category><category>moving</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/windows/welp.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Like a Thesis Defence &lt;small&gt;(or so I imagine)&lt;/small&gt;</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/bzr/thesis.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently started using &lt;a href="http://bazaar-vcs.org/"&gt;bzr&lt;/a&gt; as my go-to version control
system, and as a newbie I’ve &lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/bzr/BazaarNotes1.html"&gt;run
into a couple of small things&lt;/a&gt; I’ld like changed.  Fortunately, bzr
is written in &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, and comes
with an extensive set of unit tests, so it was easy for me to jump
right in and add the feature I wanted.  To be honest, I started off by
writing it up as &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/bzr/+bug/129299"&gt;a bug report&lt;/a&gt;,
with a trivial patch (by which I mean one without any tests).  The
comments on the bug led me to write up an actual mergable set of
changes (which seems to be called a bundle by the bzr folks), and
submit it for review.  What followed was a few &lt;a href="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.comp.version-control.bazaar-ng.general/29306/focus=29306"&gt;back-and-forths&lt;/a&gt; where various people pointed out things I hadn’t
done correctly, or hadn’t really understood, and I fixed them.  As a
result, I think the code in &lt;a href="http://bundlebuggy.aaronbentley.com/request/%3C46C303B4.60109%40latte.ca%3E"&gt;the most recent bundle&lt;/a&gt; is pretty good, and is certainly far
better than anything I would have produced on my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bazaar-ng</category><category>bzr</category><category>patch</category><category>path</category><category>submit</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/bzr/thesis.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 14:14:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some notes on Bazaar</title><link>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/bzr/bazaarnotes1.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This started off as a reply to some email on the Bazaar-NG list,
but it sort of grew and grew, until there were a whole bunch of things
in it, and I thought it would probably be better as a weblog entry, so
that I could find it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the email...&lt;br&gt;
Martin Pool wrote:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt; If you have sftp access to your server, then just do&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr init-repo sftp://user@host/~/myproject&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr push sftp://user@host/~/myproject/mybranch&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt; then on the second machine (eg at work)&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr init-repo ~/myproject&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   cd myproject&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr branch sftp://user@host/~/myproject/mybranch&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a related question, if I wanted other people to be able to download
my branch over http, would it suffice to do something on the server
like&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
bzr init-repo ~/www/myproject&lt;br&gt;
cd ~/www/myproject&lt;br&gt;
bzr branch sftp://user@host/~/myproject/mybranch&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
or would I need to push straight to ~/www/myproject/mybranch?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm of two minds here, and I'ld like to explain why, in case it's a
common problem.  On the one hand, the repo I created by following the
steps in the first part of Martin's message&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr init-repo sftp://user@host/~/myproject&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;   bzr push sftp://user@host/~/myproject/mybranch&lt;br&gt;
should be just the same as any other repository, right?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But, on the other hand, when I ssh to "user@host", and look in
~/myproject, all I see is a .bzr directory.  None of the files I
allegedly pushed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search for 'bzr push "no content"' and 'bzr push missing files'
turns up nothing that makes much sense to me.  running 'bzr help push'
finally shows me the following lines:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt; The target branch will not have its working tree populated
because&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt; this is both expensive, and is not supported on remote file
systems.&lt;br&gt;
which explains it at least a little.  So I started looking for a way
to push and update, which quickly led me to the push-and-update
plugin, but I'm now lost as to how to install it into my copy of bzr
(the binary distribution, running under Windows XP.)  The plugins
document that ships with bzr says "typically found in
/usr/lib/python2.4/site-packages/bzrlib/plugins/", but I'm really
fairly sure that's not where it's located on &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; box...  &lt;a href="http://dpi.radiology.uiowa.edu/mifar/doc/bazaar-setup.php"&gt;another
page&lt;/a&gt; says that it is "usually [...]
C:\python2.4\site-packages\bzrlib\plugins under Windows", but again,
that directory doesn't exist where I am.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I expect it'll make a difference to any answer I get, let me
just say upfront that I've installed Bazaar (bzr) 0.18.0 into
C:\Program Files\Bazaar\ using the Windows standalone installer.  The
output of "bzr version" is:&lt;br&gt;
"""&lt;br&gt;
Bazaar (bzr) 0.18.0&lt;br&gt;
Using Python interpreter: C:\Program Files\Bazaar\bzr.exe&lt;br&gt;
Using Python standard library: C:\Program
Files\Bazaar\lib\library.zip&lt;br&gt;
Using bzrlib: C:\Program Files\Bazaar\lib\library.zip\bzrlib&lt;br&gt;
Using Bazaar configuration: C:/Documents and
Settings/blake/Application Data/bazaar/2.0&lt;br&gt;
Using Bazaar log file: C:\Documents and Settings\blake\My
Documents\.bzr.log&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Copyright 2005, 2006, 2007 Canonical Ltd.&lt;br&gt;
http://bazaar-vcs.org/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
bzr comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY.  bzr is free software, and you
may use, modify and redistribute it under the terms of the GNU General
Public License version 2 or later.&lt;br&gt;
"""&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, where should I put the plugins in this case?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, as given on irc, seems to be "put it somewhere else and
set the BZR_PLUGIN_PATH env variable".  Works for me, although it
would have been nice if the Windows standalone installer did that for
me, by creating a Plugins directory under the install directory.  And
as one final note, the BZR_PLUGIN_PATH, which it may contain spaces
(i.e. "C:\Program Files\Bazaar\Plugins"), must not end in a trailing
"\".&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bazaar-ng</category><category>bzr</category><category>http</category><category>notes</category><category>plugins</category><category>push</category><category>sftp</category><category>windows</category><guid>https://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/bzr/bazaarnotes1.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 19:06:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>