<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog-O! (work)</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/tags/work.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:14:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Some new toys</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/somejetpacks.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There have been a couple of things I’ve noticed myself doing over and over
again recently, and because I’m a developer whenever I do something over
and over again, I try to find a way to automate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did some playing around with Mozilla’s &lt;a href="https://builder.mozillalabs.com/"&gt;Add-on Builder&lt;/a&gt; and came up with &lt;a href="http://bwinton.latte.ca/Work/jetpacks/"&gt;a couple of Jetpacks&lt;/a&gt; that solved my problems.  Maybe
you’ll find them useful, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>firefox</category><category>jetpacks</category><category>mozilla</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/somejetpacks.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 21:56:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More notes on Mercurial.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/pbranch.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I made some changes to &lt;a href="http://weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/mercurial"&gt;my work flow&lt;/a&gt; to get around
some slight annoyances.  Specifically, I switched from using &lt;a href="http://mercurial.selenic.com/wiki/MqExtension"&gt;mq&lt;/a&gt; to using &lt;a href="http://arrenbrecht.ch/mercurial/pbranch/"&gt;pbranch&lt;/a&gt;.  The features that pbranch
gives me that mq didn’t basically boil down to two main things;
sharing, and tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With pbranch, it’s way easier for me to share my changes, both with
other people, and with myself in a virtual machine.  It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; possible
to share the patch with mq, by cloning the patch repo if I remembered
to run qinit -C, but with pbranch all I have to do is clone the main
repo, and my changes are right there, waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For tracking, when I’m nearing the end of a patch, and it mostly
works, I get really nervous if I can’t check in my changes.  With mq,
I set up an alias to let me commit the patch queue, so that I could go
back, but it was really hard to tell what I had changed between any
two commits, since it was showing me the diff of my diffs.  And so I
didn’t use it as much as I would like to.  With pbranch, I just commit
the code, like I want to, and it keeps track of what the patch should
look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my day-to-day workflow now looks more like this:&lt;br&gt;
If I’m working on a bug that I’ve already got a patch started for, I
cd to the appropriate branch, type &lt;tt&gt;hg pgraph&lt;/tt&gt; to see where I
am, and &lt;tt&gt;hq update branchname&lt;/tt&gt; to get to the pbranch I want to
work on.  Then I make my changes, and when I’m happy with the results
of &lt;tt&gt;hg diff&lt;/tt&gt;, I type &lt;tt&gt;hg commit&lt;/tt&gt; to put the changes into
the pbranch.  After that, I use &lt;tt&gt;hg pdiff &amp;gt;
../branch-name-bugnum-description.diff&lt;/tt&gt; to get a patch that I can
upload to bugzilla.  At this point, I usually load the patch into Vim,
and search for some of the mistakes I’ve made in the past.
(&lt;tt&gt;/^+.*[[:space:]]+$&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt&gt;/dump&lt;/tt&gt; caught a lot of my
initial mistakes.  Now I’ve moved on to things that are tougher to
check for, like putting open-parens on a new line instead of on the
previous line.)  I usually go through a couple of cycles of &lt;tt&gt;hg
commit&lt;/tt&gt;/&lt;tt&gt;hg pdiff …&lt;/tt&gt; before I’m happy with the patch.  Once
I am, I don’t have to type anything before I upload it, since it’s
already committed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hg</category><category>mercurial</category><category>mozilla</category><category>mq</category><category>pbranch</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/pbranch.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 15:48:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My first couple of days at Mozilla Messaging.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/jobatmomo.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I started a new full-time contract at &lt;a href="http://mozillamessaging.com/"&gt;Mozilla
Messaging&lt;/a&gt; (a.k.a. the people who brought you
Thunderbird).  I meant to post this on the Wednesday after I started, but
didn’t get around to it until now.  So, here you go, my notes from just
after I started a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a pretty crazy couple of days, both because I’m not that used
to working for a full 8 hours on one thing, and because I’m at the point
where there’s still so much to learn that I could spend all my time
researching stuff, and never get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even with all the stuff for me to learn, I feel like I’ve made a fair
bit of progress.  There were a few bugs assigned to me, based on &lt;a href="http://hg.mozilla.org/comm-central/rev/98a7de404c08"&gt;a
previous patch&lt;/a&gt;, as
well as a couple of things left to do to get &lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=45715"&gt;the feature&lt;/a&gt; working, so I jumped
right in to those.  After I had new patches up for review on all of those
bugs, I talked with &lt;a href="http://clarkbw.net/blog/"&gt;Bryan Clark&lt;/a&gt; about what bugs
I should tackle next.  He and &lt;a href="http://ascher.ca/blog/"&gt;David Ascher&lt;/a&gt; both
suggested that the new &lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=autoconfig"&gt;automatic mail server config&lt;/a&gt; dialog could use a
bit of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, I did some investigation on group email addresses for &lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=496440"&gt;one of
the bugs&lt;/a&gt; I’m working
on, and took a look at how the autoconfig dialog was put together so that I
wouldn’t sound like I was completely lost in the meeting.  (XUL, CSS, and
Javascript.  No surprises there.  :)  Then, after the &lt;a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Thunderbird/StatusMeetings/2009-06-09"&gt;Status
Meeting&lt;/a&gt;,
Bryan and I chatted a bit about what the various bugs were that he had
assigned to me, and what sort of things I might look into to try and fix
them.  A few hours later, I had a fix for &lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=490105"&gt;one of them&lt;/a&gt;, and applied a similar
fix to &lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=490106"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt;.  (As
an aside, you’ve got to love the 3 hour investigation which ends up being a
9-character change.  At least while investigating the bug, I learned a lot
about &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/XUL/hbox"&gt;hboxes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/XUL/vbox"&gt;vboxes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/XUL/Attribute/flex"&gt;flexes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/XUL/grid"&gt;grids&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/XUL/description"&gt;descriptions&lt;/a&gt;, which will hopefully
come in handy in future bugs.  :)  Finally, I ended the day by reading a
review of a patch I submitted on Monday morning, making some tweaks to my
code, and resubmitting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final thing that amazes me is that each day is taking up pretty much a
full page of my log book, which is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than usual.  Most of the days
last month got a line or two.  Really full days would maybe get half a
page.  But yesterday and today were a solid page, chock full of
information, each.  I wonder how long this trend will continue.  I hope it
keeps on going like this for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mozilla</category><category>new_job</category><category>thunderbird</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/mozilla/jobatmomo.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 04:04:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How I use Mercurial (and the MQ extension).</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/mercurial.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started working for &lt;a href="http://www.mozillamessaging.com"&gt;Mozilla Messaging&lt;/a&gt; a
while ago, and since &lt;a href="http://blog.codekills.net/"&gt;David Wolever&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/wolever/status/2394705659"&gt;asked
me&lt;/a&gt; how I used Mercurial and the
MQ extension, I thought I would put up some notes on how I’m currently using
them in my day-to-day work.  Of course, the stuff I’m doing now is a little
different than what I’ve done in any of my previous jobs, so I’m not sure how
useful any of the following will be to anyone who isn’t contributing to an open
source project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk a little bit about how I have my Work directory set up.  The
first thing I did when I started working on the Thunderbird source code was to
pull down a clean copy of the source into a directory named “src-base”.  The
purpose of that directory is to always contain a clean copy of the upstream
source code so that when I want to update the various branches I have (five, at
last count), I only need to download the changes from the Mozilla repo once,
and I can then propagate them from src-base to the other branches.  I got the
idea to do that from the Bazaar-NG developers, and I think it has helped to
keep my bandwidth usage down.  It might cause a problem if I was sharing my
branches, but since Thunderbird seems to revolve around submitting patches to
bugzilla, it works out pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I did was to clone src-base into a directory named
“add-reply-list-button” (because I was writing a patch to add a Reply-To-List
button :), go into that directory, and type &lt;tt&gt;hg qinit -c&lt;/tt&gt; to create an
mq repository, and put the mq repository itself under version control.  (I
didn’t actually do that the first time, and was quite annoyed that I couldn’t
revert changes I had made in my patch queue.)  The other part of that is that
I’ve aliased &lt;tt&gt;mq&lt;/tt&gt; to &lt;tt&gt;hg -R $(hg root)/.hg/patches&lt;/tt&gt;.  This lets
me type &lt;tt&gt;mq commit&lt;/tt&gt; to commit the changes to the patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now we’re at my day-to-day work.  If I’m working on a bug that I’ve already
got a patch started for, I cd to the appropriate branch, type &lt;tt&gt;hg
qseries&lt;/tt&gt; to see where I am, and &lt;tt&gt;hq qpush&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;hg qpop&lt;/tt&gt; to
get to the patch I want to work on.  Then I make my changes, and when I’m happy
with the results of &lt;tt&gt;hg diff&lt;/tt&gt;, I type &lt;tt&gt;hg qrefresh&lt;/tt&gt; to put the
changes into the patch.  After that, I use &lt;tt&gt;hg qdiff &amp;gt;
../branch-name-bugnum-description.diff&lt;/tt&gt; to get a patch that I can upload to
bugzilla.  At this point, I usually load the patch into Vim, and search for
some of the mistakes I’ve made in the past.  (&lt;tt&gt;/^+.*[[:space:]]+$&lt;/tt&gt;, and
&lt;tt&gt;/dump&lt;/tt&gt; caught a lot of my initial mistakes.  Now I’ve moved on to
things that are tougher to check for, like putting open-parens on a new line
instead of on the previous line.)  I usually go through a couple of cycles of
&lt;tt&gt;hg qrefresh&lt;/tt&gt;/&lt;tt&gt;hg qdiff …&lt;/tt&gt; before I’m happy with the patch.  Once
I am, I type &lt;tt&gt;mq commit -m "Updated patch to fix foo and bar."&lt;/tt&gt; to save
the state of the patch, and then I upload it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hg</category><category>mercurial</category><category>mozilla</category><category>mq</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/thunderbird/mercurial.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 02:31:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Okay, this is cool.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/freewifi.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found myself downtown today, with nothing really to do between 3:30
and 6:30.  I suppose I could have headed over to U of T, but it seemed
like sort of a long way to go just to connect to the internet and come
all the way back again.  So instead of making the trek, or wasting two
tokens, I took advantage of the 2 hours of free WiFi that comes with
my Starbucks card, and stayed near Yonge, drinking green tea with a
little honey, and investigating a few bugs for work.  After it runs
out (in another 31 minutes), I think I'm going to pack up, and walk
north to my next appointment, grabbing some dinner on the way.  If I'm
right, that should put me right where I need to be, right when I need
to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, if only everything in my life could fall into place this easily.
(The upgrade to Aquamacs 1.6 that I just did also worked out really
well.  Maybe today is just my day for doing stuff!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>remote</category><category>starbucks</category><category>wifi</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/freewifi.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 21:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Things on my mind.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/thoughts.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was chatting with a friend and former co-worker of mine today, and
asked him why I was never a part of the group guiding where the
company was going.  (Okay, I actually asked why I was never a part of
the management, but in retrospect that was the wrong question, for
reasons detailed below.  I should have asked the question I said
above.)  His answer basically boiled down to “You never wanted to be.”
One of the things he mentioned was that when I traded salary for extra
vacation days (something I was fairly proud of thinking of, since it
makes me an easier sell to the CFO, and the two are pretty much equal,
if you’re allowed to cash out unused vacation days), it indicated that
my priorities lay more with my family than with the company, with the
unspoken implication that that attitude isn’t one that will lead to a
position of power within the company.  That initial assumption led to
a series of misunderstandings, and miscommunications, until I was
effectively shut out of helping to guide the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that’s fair enough, kinda, but it’s a shame that people think
that having interests outside of the office means that I’m somehow
less interested in the success of the company.  Particularly since I
didn’t take the vacation days, and was always intending on cashing
them out.  So, for my next job, I think I’m going to take that option
off the table, since I didn’t use the vacation days anyways.  (I had
27 days built up when I was laid off!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also asked him what I could do to get into management next time, but
I’m not really sure that’s really where I want to be.  I know a few
people who have moved into management, and then found it hard to get a
job when they were laid off.  Along the same lines, I still believe
I’m a far better architect and coder than manager, and so it’s sort of
foolish for a company to hire me for my managerial skills when my
coding skills are far superior.  And I really &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like
programming.  &lt;strong&gt;Really&lt;/strong&gt;.  With the spare time I had after I was laid
off, I wrote code for an iPhone game.  For fun I read up on
programming languages I haven’t seen before, and solve &lt;a href="http://projecteuler.net/"&gt;Project
Euler&lt;/a&gt; problems with them.  But I don’t
know if there’s a way to parlay my architecture and coding prowess
into the ability to help guide a company, since that seems to be the
exclusive province of people who manage other people.  (Of course, my
work on &lt;a href="http://www.basieproject.org"&gt;Basie&lt;/a&gt; last term also has me
wondering if I’m actually a mediocre manager, or if I may be better at
it than I always thought I was.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose there’s always one way to find out how good a manager/team
lead I am, and I expect I’ll start moving that direction in my next
job.  I can always write code on evenings and weekends, right?  Well,
either way, it’s not something I’ll worry about until I get another
job.  And certainly not something I should be worrying about this
late at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>career</category><category>coding</category><category>management</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/thoughts.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 03:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to get laid off.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newjob.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few Fridays ago, I was laid off from my job.  After seven years I’m
sort of out of practice at looking for a new job.  The economy is also
kind of slow, and I know a few people who are going to graduate soon
into this economy, and who might want to know what I did when I was
laid off, and how I’ve found a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Friday.  As a side note, if you’re ever in the position of letting
go of employees, please don’t lay them off or fire them on a Friday.
They can’t do anything but sit and brood over the weekend, which can
really get them depressed.  On the other hand, I’ve been pretty upbeat
about it because after seven years, I’m kind of ready for a change.
It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a big shock when I first learned about it, but I had made my
peace with it after around 30 minutes or so.  An hour later, there was
a meeting where the rest of the employees found out, and that was kind
of tough to sit through, but afterwards it was like there was a big
weight lifted from my shoulders, and my co-workers and I started to
joke around about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon, and the next couple of days, I emailed my friends and
asked whether they knew of any companies that were hiring.  From that
I got six or seven leads, and three or four interviews, and finally
decided to do some work and sign a three month contract, which will
probably turn into a longer term contract.  I don’t expect it’ll turn
into a full time job, but that works out fine for me, since I expect
the market will have changed by the new year, and I’m hoping that a
friend of mine will get the hiring freeze he’s currently in lifted by
then, and hire me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, now that I’m working from home, I bought a new
computer because I can deduct the price from my income as a business
expense.  Similarly I can deduct part of the interest on my mortgage
from my income.  And I’ll be making a fair bit more than I was getting
as a full-time employee, because of the lack of benefits, my inside
knowledge of the app, and finally because I have had only one raise in
the last seven years.  (It was hard for me to ask for a raise, because
I knew the company didn’t have a lot of money to give me a raise with,
and because I owned some of the company, so I would rather have seen
my shares increase in value than get extra cash in the short term.  Of
course neither ended up happening, but who could have foreseen that?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, there’s my tale of woe and hope.  It’s really not that bad,
apart from the sadness of seeing something that you worked really hard
for crash and burn.  But even in that sadness is the spark of
excitement for something new and different.  If you haven’t gotten
your first job yet, then I don’t know if this will help you all that
much.  I guess the main thing to take away from it would be that you
should cultivate contacts among your peers, profs, co-workers, and
clients because they’re the ones who will find you the good jobs, in
the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>job</category><category>phantom</category><category>search</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/employment/newjob.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 18:21:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Now I feel like I’m behind the times.</title><link>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/seachange.html</link><dc:creator>Blake Winton</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was reading &lt;a href="http://blogs.mathworks.com/images/steve/92/handout_final_icip2006.pdf"&gt;a presentation&lt;/a&gt; about how to write better software for non-developers, and it said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would refuse to work on any sort of collaborative software
development project that doesn’t use version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I totally agree.  Heck, I even use version control for my personal
one-off projects.  But it got me wondering what people use at their
jobs, so I asked my friends who were on instant messenger, as a straw
poll.  The results were shockingly unanimous.  &lt;a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/"&gt;Subversion&lt;/a&gt;.  8 for 8.  I regret to say that I’m
not using Subversion at my job, but that may change someday.  In the
meantime, leave a comment, and tell me what you’re using at work or at
home, either to make me feel better, or to rub my nose in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: One person uses Clear Case.  I’ve heard good things about
Clear Case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bzr</category><category>survey</category><category>svn</category><category>vss</category><category>work</category><guid>http://bwinton.github.io/weblog.latte.ca/blake/tech/seachange.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2008 20:03:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>